<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd">
<collection><source>PMC</source><date>20201223</date><key>pmc.key</key><document><id>5740447</id><infon key="license">CC BY</infon><passage><infon key="article-id_doi">10.3897/BDJ.5.e21271</infon><infon key="article-id_other">8321</infon><infon key="article-id_pmc">5740447</infon><infon key="article-id_pmid">29308045</infon><infon key="article-id_publisher-id">Biodiversity Data Journal</infon><infon key="elocation-id">e21271</infon><infon key="issue">5</infon><infon key="kwd">Citizen science Mobile phone Social networking system Open data</infon><infon key="license">This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License 4.0 (CC-BY), which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Osawa;given-names:Takeshi</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Yamanaka;given-names:Takehiko</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Nakatani;given-names:Yukinobu</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Nishihiro;given-names:Jun</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Takahashi;given-names:Shiori</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Mahoro;given-names:Suzuki</infon><infon key="name_6">surname:Sasaki;given-names:Hironobu</infon><infon key="section_type">TITLE</infon><infon key="type">front</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>0</offset><text>A crowdsourcing approach to collecting photo-based insect and plant observation records</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract_title_1</infon><offset>88</offset><text>Background</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>99</offset><text>Scientific field observation by members of the public is known as citizen science and has become popular all across the world. Citizen science is advantageous for collecting large amounts of scientific data and can be seen as a crowdsourcing approach to data collection. Information and communications technology is enhancing the availability of citizen science. Mobile devices, such as mobile phones, that have a digital camera with a global positioning system (GPS) are necessities for contemporary life and can be utilised as powerful observation tools in citizen science.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract_title_1</infon><offset>675</offset><text>New information</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>691</offset><text>A web-based system has been developed as a data collection tool for citizen science. Participants submit an e-mail with a photo taken by their mobile phones. The photos contain location information, which can be easily and automatically embedded if the mobile phone is equipped with GPS. Collaboration has been undertaken with regional event managers, such as museum curators and held citizen science events in each region and for various target taxonomic groups. All photos were stored in the data server and the organisms were taxonomically identified by citizen scientists, regional managers and the authors. In total, 154 species and 843 data records were collected in this project conducted from 2011 to 2016.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>1406</offset><text>Introduction</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>1419</offset><text>A citizen scientist is a volunteer who collects or processes data as part of a scientific enquiry. Today, these volunteers are active in several scientific areas, especially the environmental sciences and many recent studies have benefitted from this approach. One of the important research benefits provided by citizen science is the crowdsourcing of large data sets. In addition to its scientific merits, this approach has educational advantages because it gives members of the public opportunities to observe and interact with organisms in nature. Thus, the approach can provide substantial benefits for both researchers and citizens.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>2057</offset><text>Recent advances in information and communications technology have made citizen science more user-friendly and accessible. Mobile devices, in particular, have become key tools for citizen science activities in recent years. Most mobile phones have a digital camera with a global positioning system (GPS) that allows people to record species occurrence data with high precision, because the data contain not only the location details, date and time but also the evidence (i.e. photo) of the targets. As mobile phones have become a necessity for contemporary life, citizen science projects using mobile phones are expected to attract more volunteers than ever before.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>2722</offset><text>A web-based system has been developed as a data collection tool for citizen science. When a participant submits an e-mail with a photo that has embedded GPS information, the system automatically detects when and where the observation was made from the exchangeable image file format (EXIF) information and these data are stored in the system’s data server. Collaboration is undertaken with regional event managers such as teachers and museum curators and field observation events conducted with citizen scientists using our web-based system. The purpose of the events depends largely on the collaborators and varies according to whether the event is scientifically or educationally orientated. Consequently, this project has covered several themes and has yielded data on various taxonomic groups in many regions scattered across Japan. Although these records contain information on a wide range of organisms in many regions, when combined with other biodiversity records, they can help to clarify regional flora or fauna and nationwide distribution ranges.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>3782</offset><text>In this data paper, the collection of both plant and insect observation records are reported based on photos taken by many citizen scientists. All records have the location and date/time, which were extracted from the EXIF information in the header of the photo files. Although observation records, collected by citizen scientists, may have quality problems, such as misidentification, photographic data can be useful for avoiding such problems. The compiliation of digital data records according to Darwin Core, which is a standard format for biodiversity data, have also been reported.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>4370</offset><text>Project description</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>4390</offset><text>Title</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>4396</offset><text>NIAES mobile photo project</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>4423</offset><text>Study area description</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>4446</offset><text>This project does not have specific themes, such as target species. Instead, the themes are chosen by regional project managers, who have their own targets, motivations and purposes. Thus, the project was designed to include a variety of approaches, have different goals and involve many scientific disciplines. Increasing participation in citizen science projects is essential and devising strategies on how to attract participants and deciding which themes will enhance participation are critical challenges.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>4957</offset><text>Design description</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>4976</offset><text>The platform has been provided (described in the Sampling methods section) for an internet-based photo-collection system for regional managers. Regional managers have been assisted in arranging data collection events, but the data collection itself is handled by the regional managers. For example, the manager could be a natural history museum curator who is interested in organising nature walks that incorporate photography, or an environmental non-profit organisation that is conducting a survey of alien invasive species around a locality. Each regional manager arranges the data collection method, recruits participants and posts photos to this system via e-mail. Those e-mails are then automatically handled by the system and are stored in the system’s data server.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>5751</offset><text>Sampling methods</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>5768</offset><text>Sampling description</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>5789</offset><text>A web-based system has been developed to collect photos taken by citizen scientists. The system is a customised version of the commercial mobile photo system developed by Fujitsu FIP, Co. (http://www.fujitsu.com/jp/group/fip/solutions/business-and-technology-solutions/sustainability-solution/management/biodiversity/; accessed 10 August 2017). Customised system could set a several subsystem which independent in each. Each regional manager can prepare that system according to the purpose of the collection event and manage it. In the subsystem, the regional manager can manage the photos which are collected for their event only. In the main system which is managed by the authors, all photos are collected by all subsystems. The data collection procedure is simple: a participant takes a photo of the observation target and sends an e-mail with the photo that has geographic information embedded by GPS (Fig. 1). The timing and location of all the photos sent to the system are automatically extracted and stored in the data server (Fig. 1). The records and the photos are available to be viewed by participants in these project websites from 2011 to 2016 (Note, however, that they are currently closed.) with the map of the web GIS.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>7027</offset><text>The rationale for each event are discussed with the regional manager beforehand and an event-specific subsystem for projects is established. An event-specific address to which the participants send their e-mails is designated. Event-specific websites which relate to each subsystem are opened. For some observation events, citizen scientists are asked to identify the organisms that they have observed and put the names of the organisms in their e-mails. Regional managers are helped to check all records posted and re-examine the species names classified by the citizen scientists on the basis of the photos attached. Records that could not be identified to the species level from a photo are removed.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>7730</offset><text>Geographic coverage</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>7750</offset><text>Description</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>7762</offset><text>The collection sites of the data provided here are distributed across Japan, from Hokkaido to the southern islands. One foreign record is also included.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>7915</offset><text>Coordinates</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>7927</offset><text> and Latitude; and Longitude.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>7957</offset><text>Taxonomic coverage</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>7976</offset><text>Description</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>7988</offset><text>With regard to taxonomy and systematics, all species were identified by the regional managers and authors according to the morphotypes of objects. If sufficient information could not be obtained for proper species identification, i.e. the species which is difficult to identify, that record was not included in this data paper. As a result, 843 records of 154 species have been provided. Thus, these species were ordinary which can identify easily based on photo.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>8452</offset><text>Temporal coverage</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>8470</offset><text>Notes</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>8476</offset><text>The system was launched in 2011. Data will be released from 2011 to 2016.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>8550</offset><text>Usage rights</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>8563</offset><text>Use license</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>8575</offset><text>Open Data Commons Attribution License</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>8613</offset><text>Data resources</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>8628</offset><text>Data package title</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>8647</offset><text>A crowdsourcing approach to collecting photo-based insect and plant observation records</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>8735</offset><text>Resource link</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>8749</offset><text> https://www.gbif.org/dataset/c671d43f-7fb9-4b5a-a964-630bfbf47dd2#geographicCoverages </text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>8837</offset><text>Number of data sets</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>8857</offset><text>1</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>8859</offset><text>Data set 1.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>8871</offset><text>Data set name</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>8885</offset><text>dwca-niaes_mobile_photopj1-v1.3.zip</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>8921</offset><text>Data format</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>8933</offset><text>Darwin Core Archive</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>8953</offset><text>Number of columns</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>8971</offset><text>16</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>8974</offset><text>Download URL</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>8987</offset><text> http://www.gbif.jp/ipt/archive.do?r=niaes_mobile_photopj1 </text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>9047</offset><text>Description</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>9059</offset><text>The data set is available from GBIF network through Japan node of GBIF(JBIF).</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">DS1.xml</infon><infon key="id">DS1</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table</infon><infon key="xml">&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;table frame=&quot;hsides&quot; rules=&quot;all&quot;&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Column label&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Column description&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;occurrenceID&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;An identifier for the Occurrence (photo).&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;institutionID&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;An identifier for the institution having custody of the information.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;collectionCode&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Identifying the collection from which the record was derived. In this data set, project name is provided.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;basisOfRecord&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;The specific nature of the data record. In this data set, all records were &quot;Observation&quot;.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;scientificName&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;The scientific name without authors and year.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;taxonRank&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Lowest taxonomic rank of the record. In this data set, all records were species.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;kingdom&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Kingdom name.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;phylum&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Phylum name. Some of species were not ranked.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;class&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Class name. Some of species were not ranked.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;order&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Order name.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;family&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Family name.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;eventDate&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;The date on which a photo was taken.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;decimalLatitude&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Approximate point latitude of the field site in decimal degrees.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;decimalLongitude&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Approximate point longitude of the field site in decimal degrees.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;verbatimCoordinateSystem&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;The spatial coordinate system on that data set.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;geodeticDatum&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Geodetic datum&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
</infon><offset>9137</offset><text>Column label	Column description	 	occurrenceID	An identifier for the Occurrence (photo).	 	institutionID	An identifier for the institution having custody of the information.	 	collectionCode	Identifying the collection from which the record was derived. In this data set, project name is provided.	 	basisOfRecord	The specific nature of the data record. In this data set, all records were &quot;Observation&quot;.	 	scientificName	The scientific name without authors and year.	 	taxonRank	Lowest taxonomic rank of the record. In this data set, all records were species.	 	kingdom	Kingdom name.	 	phylum	Phylum name. Some of species were not ranked.	 	class	Class name. Some of species were not ranked.	 	order	Order name.	 	family	Family name.	 	eventDate	The date on which a photo was taken.	 	decimalLatitude	Approximate point latitude of the field site in decimal degrees.	 	decimalLongitude	Approximate point longitude of the field site in decimal degrees.	 	verbatimCoordinateSystem	The spatial coordinate system on that data set.	 	geodeticDatum	Geodetic datum	 	</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">title</infon><offset>10196</offset><text>References</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">149</infon><infon key="issue">1</infon><infon key="lpage">172</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Dickinson;given-names:Janis L.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Zuckerberg;given-names:Benjamin</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Bonter;given-names:David N.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1146/annurev-ecolsys-102209-144636</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Annual Review of Ecology, Evolution, and Systematics</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">41</infon><infon key="year">2010</infon><offset>10207</offset><text>Citizen science as an ecological research tool: challenges and benefits</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">291</infon><infon key="issue">6</infon><infon key="lpage">297</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Dickinson;given-names:Janis L</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Shirk;given-names:Jennifer</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Bonter;given-names:David</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Bonney;given-names:Rick</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Crain;given-names:Rhiannon L</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Martin;given-names:Jason</infon><infon key="name_6">surname:Phillips;given-names:Tina</infon><infon key="name_7">surname:Purcell;given-names:Karen</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1890/110236</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Frontiers in Ecology and the Environment</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">10</infon><infon key="year">2012</infon><offset>10279</offset><text>The current state of citizen science as a tool for ecological research and public engagement</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1</infon><infon key="issue">1</infon><infon key="lpage">19</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Kobori;given-names:Hiromi</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Dickinson;given-names:Janis L.</infon><infon key="name_10">surname:Miller-Rushing;given-names:A. J.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Washitani;given-names:Izumi</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Sakurai;given-names:Ryo</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Amano;given-names:Tatsuya</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Komatsu;given-names:Naoya</infon><infon key="name_6">surname:Kitamura;given-names:Wataru</infon><infon key="name_7">surname:Takagawa;given-names:Shinichi</infon><infon key="name_8">surname:Koyama;given-names:Kazuo</infon><infon key="name_9">surname:Ogawara;given-names:Takao</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1007/s11284-015-1314-y</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Ecological Research</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">31</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>10372</offset><text>Citizen science: a new approach to advance ecology, education, and conservation</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">89</infon><infon key="issue">1</infon><infon key="lpage">93</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Miyazaki;given-names:Yusuke</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Murase;given-names:Atsunobu</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Sahara;given-names:Ryosuke</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Angulo;given-names:Arturo</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Senou;given-names:Hiroshi</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1007/s11284-016-1409-0</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Ecological Research</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">32</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>10452</offset><text>Adding fish images taken in other countries to the biodiversity database of a Japanese public museum, with report of range extension of Labrisomus jenkinsi from the Pacific coast of Costa Rica</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">2383</infon><infon key="issue">9</infon><infon key="lpage">2391</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Miyazaki;given-names:Yusuke</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Murase;given-names:Atsunobu</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Shiina;given-names:Masato</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Naoe;given-names:Kenichi</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Nakashiro;given-names:Ryosuke</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Honda;given-names:Junichi</infon><infon key="name_6">surname:Yamaide;given-names:Junichiro</infon><infon key="name_7">surname:Senou;given-names:Hiroshi</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1007/s10531-014-0724-4</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Biodiversity and Conservation</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">23</infon><infon key="year">2014</infon><offset>10645</offset><text>Biological monitoring by citizens using Web-based photographic databases of fishes</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">541</infon><infon key="issue">4</infon><infon key="lpage">541</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Osawa;given-names:Takeshi</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1007/s11284-013-1049-6</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Ecological Research</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">28</infon><infon key="year">2013</infon><offset>10728</offset><text>Monitoring records of plant species in the Hakone region of Fuji-Hakone-Izu National Park, Japan, 2001–2010</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1160</infon><infon key="issue">5</infon><infon key="lpage">1167</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Osawa;given-names:Takeshi</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1007/s00267-015-0457-5</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">25813627</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Environmental Management</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">55</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>10838</offset><text>Importance of farmland in urbanized areas as a landscape component for barn swallows (Hirundo rustica) nesting on concrete buildings</text></passage><passage><infon key="comment">Japanese</infon><infon key="fpage">157</infon><infon key="lpage">165</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Osawa;given-names:T.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Yamanaka;given-names:T.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Nakatani;given-names:Y.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.18960/hozen.18.2_157</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Japanese Journal of Conservation Ecology</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">18</infon><infon key="year">2013</infon><offset>10971</offset><text>Establishing a canonical procedure for collecting biodiversity information from citizen scientists using mobile phones</text></passage><passage><infon key="comment">Japanese</infon><infon key="fpage">243</infon><infon key="lpage">248</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Sasaki;given-names:H.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Ohnishi;given-names:W.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Osawa;given-names:T.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.18960/hozen.21.2_243</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Japanese Journal of Conservation Ecology</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">21</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>11090</offset><text>Redefining ‘citizen science’ from several perspectives</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">467</infon><infon key="issue">9</infon><infon key="lpage">471</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Silvertown;given-names:Jonathan</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.tree.2009.03.017</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">19586682</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Trends in Ecology &amp; Evolution</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">24</infon><infon key="year">2009</infon><offset>11149</offset><text>A new dawn for citizen science</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">2282</infon><infon key="issue">10</infon><infon key="lpage">2292</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Sullivan;given-names:Brian L.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Wood;given-names:Christopher L.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Iliff;given-names:Marshall J.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Bonney;given-names:Rick E.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Fink;given-names:Daniel</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Kelling;given-names:Steve</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.biocon.2009.05.006</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Biological Conservation</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">142</infon><infon key="year">2009</infon><offset>11180</offset><text>eBird: A citizen-based bird observation network in the biological sciences</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">bdj-05-e21271-g001.jpg</infon><infon key="id">F3787936</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>11255</offset><text>Steps in the data-collection system</text></passage></document></collection>
