<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd">
<collection><source>PMC</source><date>20201221</date><key>pmc.key</key><document><id>5877015</id><infon key="license">CC BY</infon><passage><infon key="article-id_doi">10.3390/ijerph15030470</infon><infon key="article-id_pmc">5877015</infon><infon key="article-id_pmid">29518991</infon><infon key="article-id_publisher-id">ijerph-15-00470</infon><infon key="elocation-id">470</infon><infon key="issue">3</infon><infon key="kwd">bicycle bicycle route choice revealed preference naturalistic built environment physical activity route choice model</infon><infon key="license">Licensee MDPI, Basel, Switzerland. This article is an open access article distributed under the terms and conditions of the Creative Commons Attribution (CC BY) license (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/).</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Pritchard;given-names:Ray</infon><infon key="section_type">TITLE</infon><infon key="type">front</infon><infon key="volume">15</infon><infon key="year">2018</infon><offset>0</offset><text>Revealed Preference Methods for Studying Bicycle Route Choice—A Systematic Review</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>84</offset><text>One fundamental aspect of promoting utilitarian bicycle use involves making modifications to the built environment to improve the safety, efficiency and enjoyability of cycling. Revealed preference data on bicycle route choice can assist greatly in understanding the actual behaviour of a highly heterogeneous group of users, which in turn assists the prioritisation of infrastructure or other built environment initiatives. This systematic review seeks to compare the relative strengths and weaknesses of the empirical approaches for evaluating whole journey route choices of bicyclists. Two electronic databases were systematically searched for a selection of keywords pertaining to bicycle and route choice. In total seven families of methods are identified: GPS devices, smartphone applications, crowdsourcing, participant-recalled routes, accompanied journeys, egocentric cameras and virtual reality. The study illustrates a trade-off in the quality of data obtainable and the average number of participants. Future additional methods could include dockless bikeshare, multiple camera solutions using computer vision and immersive bicycle simulator environments.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>1252</offset><text>1. Introduction</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>1268</offset><text>The promotion of cycling is increasingly seen as an effective and efficient tool for reducing the negative environmental impacts of transport whilst improving quality of life. By enabling a shift from motorised transportation to cycling, cities can reduce both their greenhouse gas contribution and improve regional air quality through reduced motorised transportation. Increasing cycling rates in this manner has been demonstrated to have substantial health benefits, despite the increased exposure to air pollution and traffic.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>1798</offset><text>Traditionally transport planners have made use of such techniques as manual traffic volume counts at set points in a traffic network to create traffic demand models (for all modes of transport). Today, count data remains valuable in many respects and a wide variety of automated sensor technologies are available to provide continuous information on traffic flows. This type of data collection is not within the scope of this article, since it does not reveal details about bicyclist trip lengths, infrastructure preferences or network behaviour. However reviews and evaluations of the available technologies for the volume counting of bicycles can be found from the US National Cooperative Highway Research Program (NCHRP) and select other sources.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>2548</offset><text>This research systematically reviews the scientific literature for data collection techniques that allow researchers and planners to understand the route choice behaviour of bicycle users. It builds and expands upon earlier research concerning information technology dependent means for determining the location of physical activity—by considering also more traditional methods that have been used to determine bicycle route choice. Krenn et al. conducted a review of GPS studies in the scientific and grey literature that examine physical activity. Loveday et al. similarly explore the use of GPS in a comprehensive review of wearable or portable technologies that measure location. Buehler &amp; Dill conduct a review of the literature concerning the evaluation of bicycle networks and other bicycle infrastructure, meaning that a number of less technology dependent methods were uncovered. Lastly, a review by Romanillos et al. considered all big data technologies associated with cycling—covering GPS, crowdsourcing and smartphone related methods together with live point data and origin-destination data. In contrast to other review papers, this paper includes bicycling for all trip purposes, focuses on all methods that can be applied to the empirical determination of whole journey route choice and covers digital publications from all years up until late 2017. Whole journey route choice refers specifically to the route choice along an entire origin-destination journey, turn-by-turn.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>4043</offset><text>Route choice data based on actual cycling behaviour is well suited to context-specific applications such as the evaluation of new infrastructure, safety assessments or pollutant exposure. It should however be noted that tracing the whole journey of cyclists is not an entirely new endeavour. Individual travel surveys often request participants to recall recently traversed routes and the transport mode used. In recent years, GPS technology has become very affordable and increasingly omnipresent, allowing its use in large studies on travel behaviour. The goal of this paper is to compare the traditional and newer techniques that have been applied to the study of bicycle route selection.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>4735</offset><text>2. Methods</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>4746</offset><text>This paper systematically reviews the revealed preference methods that have been applied to the study of whole-journey bicycle route choice. Empirical data on bicycle route choice can also be collected through aggregate volume measures (like heat maps from the aggregated tracking of multiple users) and through naturalistic studies of point locations such as observations at intersections. Additionally stated preference techniques are often used for hypothetical route choice, where respondents are presented with a series of choices to compare against a trade-off such as time or cost. However, since such techniques do not review the full journey of the individual decision maker, the bicycle user, they are not covered in this review. The process through which the literature has been identified is described in detail below.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>5577</offset><text>To identify sources, searches were made in December 2017 in the Scopus (Elsevier) and Transport Research International Documentation (TRID) databases. The TRID database is a combination of the Transportation Research Board’s Transportation Research Information Services database and the Joint Transport Research Centre’s International Transport Research Documentation Database maintained by the Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development. The TRID database importantly contains transport-related theses and grey literature such as reports that are not published in Scopus or many other journal databases. Only English language records were reviewed with no publication date restrictions, using the query “route choice” or “naturalistic” or “revealed preference” in combination with any of the strings bicycl*, bik* or cycl* (where the asterisk indicates all iterations hereafter). Records were required to be available in digital format to be included in this review. The search strategy is summarised in Figure 1 below.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>6626</offset><text>In total, 112 empirical studies were uncovered by this search strategy. The principal selection criterion for empirical studies was that the methods had been applied to the study of bicycle route choice, and that the whole journey is captured by the method. The majority of these empirical studies were published in journals or as book chapters (65), followed by conference proceedings (30), reports (14) and theses (3).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>7047</offset><text>The following section presents the results, or introduction to the literature. This is followed by the discussion in which the timeline of publications, geographical distribution of research and the numbers of participants for different method families are displayed.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>7315</offset><text>3. Results</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>7326</offset><text>The results section of this paper is structured as follows. Firstly, the primary method families for classification purposes is explained. This is graphically illustrated in Figure 2, which displays the numbers of articles categorised in each family. Families are defined according to the primary method used to ascertain location/route choice, although in many studies, multiple methods are used that could provide this information. Detailed findings are subsequently discussed, with the further breakdown of the seven method families into 34 sub-groups. This second level of classification according to research design rather than method is used to ensure that no one sub-group contains more than ten studies, simplifying the summary of findings. A tabularised summary of the literature using this method family and sub-group structure is introduced in Appendix A, Table A1. Because many of the studies utilise multiple methods, the Table A1 includes a column qualitatively indicating the frequency of method combination for each sub-group. The other methods are not restricted to route choice, but may be supplementary data sources such as accelerometer measurements, heart rate monitors or cameras. More checks in the ‘integration with other methods’ column indicates more frequent combination with other methods.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>8648</offset><text>Method families must have a substantially different methodological set-up to other families. Hence, even though the first three families make use of GPS technology, they are split into separate families due to differences in research design (researcher acquisition of GPS device, participant GPS ownership through smartphone, and collection of crowdsourced GPS data). A summary of the literature in each family is made using the same structure (sub-groups) as in Table A1. In many cases, empirical studies make use of two or more methods for ascertaining route choice, however only the principal method (or the method that is considered most important for determining route choice) is used for classification in Table A1.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>9370</offset><text>3.1. GPS Devices</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>9387</offset><text>A total of 47 articles were found that discuss unique data collection efforts using Global Positioning System (GPS) devices (excluding smartphone GPS and crowdsourcing studies but inclusive of GPS integrated into other devices such as helmet cameras or sports watches). A study of the accuracy of Smartphone GPS relative to enhanced GPS units demonstrated that whilst GPS devices were significantly more accurate than smartphone GPS, no statistically significant difference was found between smartphone manufacturers. Additionally other data sources are required to be able to determine the street position of cyclists (on bicycle lane, footpath or traffic lane).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>10051</offset><text>The frequency of geo-located point provision and thus geospatial accuracy of GPS devices was reported in 21 of the 47 studies. Frequency values ranged from 0.2 Hz to 10 Hz, with a median of 1 Hz (or one position located per second). Such frequencies were not experienced to be problematic for recording route choices, although other issues including lack of signal, inaccurate positioning or loss of battery power were significant causes of data loss. The review article from Krenn et al. also reports data loss issues concerning charging of GPS units for eight of 24 included studies.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>10637</offset><text>Missing data was also a problem for a longitudinal study of children’s school journeys in northern England conducted in 2007 where an estimated 39% of journeys were not recorded due to problems obtaining an initial position fix from satellites. One Portland-based study used a Personal Digital Assistant (PDA) with GPS functionality, meaning that it was simple to set up to ask travel survey questions prior to beginning or finishing a trip segment. The user interface was a contributing element to getting participants to check battery charge, resulting in the relatively low data loss of 8%.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>11233</offset><text>Most of the 34 studies that utilise an instrumented bicycle setup (two or more devices attached to either a research-team or participant-owned bicycle) utilised GPS devices rather than smartphones. As might be expected, the use of portable GPS loggers improves satellite fix and accuracy in comparison to smartphone-embedded GPS units. It should be noted however that weatherproofing of GPS devices and other instrumentation (or failure to!) for use in longer terms studies can also create signal issues. Thus, special consideration should be given to this during testing phases of future research projects.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>11841</offset><text>Three of the earliest studies, published between 2007 and 2010 found that data collection was very time intensive for the research teams due to the need to extract data every few days from the units.. This became less of an issue in subsequent research that made use of wireless mobile data transmission, shorter data collection periods such as for test tracks or predetermined routes or simply had larger memory cards.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>12261</offset><text>Since many of the studies published after 2010 use largely similar GPS devices, the remaining studies are discussed according to five sub-groups, as outlined in Table A1. Each sub-group has sufficiently different methodological design to justify a distinction, with the intent to have no more than 10 articles per sub-group. It should be noted that the distinction between what constitutes an “instrumented” set-up as opposed to a standard GPS study was small, however for this paper “instrumented” refers to studies in which two or more separate devices are carried or mounted to a bicycle/vehicle.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>12869</offset><text>3.1.1. Instrumented Research Bicycles/Pedelecs</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>12916</offset><text>Instrumented research bicycles were generally loaned out to participants to obtain data over relatively short time periods, and are sometimes also referred to as bicycle Data Acquisition Systems or Instrumented Probe Bicycle. Instrumented research bicycles were used in studies of both conventionally powered and pedal-assisted electric bicycles (pedelec). The bicycles are loaned to participants in a configured state (with GPS as the primary means of determining route choice), and the use of a single bicycle type can have benefits when observing such phenomena as steering, overtaking distances or acceleration/vibration. This is because minor differences in suspension and steering between different bicycle models are removed as a confounding factor. Instrumented research bicycles and pedelecs are used most often in the context of specific research designs, usually focussing on a specific area or even fixed route. Thus participants are generally only required to cycle for a limited time—typically one to two trips. An exception was a pedelec study in which participants were loaned an instrumented bicycle for a period of two weeks.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>14062</offset><text>3.1.2. Instrumented Participant Bicycles/Pedelecs</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>14112</offset><text>Other instrumented bicycle studies made use of similar experimental set-ups mounted to participants’ conventional bikes. Some of these studies required participants to use their bicycles in an instrumented form for a week or more, whilst the others were similar to the instrumented research bicycles in their experimental design, requiring users to make only one to two trips. A smaller number of studies instrumented participants’ pedelec bicycles, for between 4 and 30 weeks. The four week study investigated the behaviour of both conventional bicyclists (n = 31), pedelec users (n = 49) and higher-powered s-pedelec users (n = 10) in Germany. The longer term 30 weeks study occurred amongst 61 pedelec users in Ghent, Belgium but without any additional user involvement such as through the completion of a travel diary. Long-term measurements were enabled by having automatic activation when the pedelec is in use, and whilst neither study specified charging routines for the instrumentation, it could be expected that the use of the pedelec battery would significantly reduce the effort required of participants.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>15233</offset><text>3.1.3. Instrumented Quasi-Bikeshare</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>15269</offset><text>A third type of instrumented bicycle study incorporating GPS devices is for quasi bikeshare schemes. Unlike public bikeshare in which any paying member of the public can use a bicycle, quasi bikeshare is available only for a subset of the population. In this review, two studies were uncovered that discuss pilot bikeshare schemes for exclusive use within university environments. One was implemented at the University of Tennessee, USA in which seven pedelecs and six conventional bicycles in the same bikeshare system were configured with GPS devices for the use of around 100 mostly undergraduate student users. The other study discusses a university bikeshare system at UMONS in Belgium but only a detailed description of the proposed sensor configuration to be implemented was included. It should be noted that GPS equipped bikeshare bicycles used in bicycle route choice research are categorised according to research design rather than bicycle type, resulting in two more bikeshare papers being discussed in results Section 3.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>16303</offset><text>3.1.4. Instrumented Participant (Two or More Devices)</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>16357</offset><text>Four studies make use of a collection of instruments, but as wearable devices rather than bicycle-mounted systems. All of these studies required participants to carry instrumentation with them for a minimum of one week. A longitudinal study of children’s school route and mode choice in northern England made use of a smartphone with external GPS receiver to allow annotation of journeys as they are made. A pollution focused study in Colorado USA made 45 participants travelling with all modes to wear a modified backpack containing GPS together with air intake tubes connected to air quality instrumentation. Lastly two before and after infrastructure evaluation studies in Portland and Salt Lake City, USA required 341 and 939 participants respectively to wear both a GPS device and accelerometer.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>17160</offset><text>3.1.5. Participant-Borne/Wearable GPS Devices</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>17206</offset><text>Other wearable GPS devices included helmet cameras with built in GPS functionality, whilst all bar one of the remaining studies used GPS devices that were either wearable, participant-borne or mounted to participants’ bicycles/vehicle.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>17444</offset><text>GPS device data have been collected much earlier in the context of travel surveys, but these studies tend not to contain the search terms used by this paper.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>17602</offset><text>3.2. Smartphone Applications</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>17631</offset><text>There are 20 papers that discuss the use of smartphone applications to capture travel behaviour, of which 16 specifically collect data related to cyclists, two are for all transport modes, and two are for vulnerable road users. Broadly speaking, smartphone applications for route choice studies can be split into two categories of passive or active user registration. Passive smartphone studies require mode identification or be involved in instrumented research bicycle set-ups where mode is no longer a variable. Active studies meanwhile tend to focus solely on cycling, and require the user to manually start and stop GPS logging via the application interface. This section will start by discussing generic issues related to smartphone applications followed by a focus on passive and active smartphone apps.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>18442</offset><text>Frequency of data provision was reported by five of the smartphone-based studies, all of which recorded data at 1 Hz (or one position located per second). It should be noted that four of these studies were in association with active applications, whilst the remaining study used a smartphone in a long term instrumented pedelec study. The instrumented pedelec research group sought to actively minimised battery drain, despite the connection of the instrumentation to the large pedelec battery. This was achieved by recording the accelerometer and GPS readings for the first four seconds of every minute, and using this information to determine if the bicycle was in motion. When no motion was recorded, the smartphone would return to a low energy sleep mode. Active smartphone applications however require the user to start and stop GPS recording. The total length of active GPS time is strongly correlated with battery consumption, however because it is mostly inactive, battery use was rarely reported to be a concern. One exception was for an active smartphone study that also included a bicycle courier sub-group, who could be expected to flatten a smartphone battery when recording for a full day of cycling. The solution was to provide this group dedicated GPS devices with larger battery capacity. Thus battery concerns are mostly restricted to the passive smartphone application subset, however only the aforementioned instrumented pedelec study mentioned battery concerns.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>19925</offset><text>Similar to GPS devices, smartphones can experience connectivity issues in obtaining a satellite fix. Such problems can be worse because the devices are not specifically designed to provide optimum location information, but also because the GPS sensor in the mobile is frequently shielded by clothes or items in a bag. The connectivity issues in smartphones can be alleviated through combination with other integrated sensors such as cellular network location. Wearable and bicycle-mounted options minimise shielding, increasing chances of a fast connection to satellites.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>20497</offset><text>3.2.1. Passive Smartphone Application</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>20535</offset><text>The oldest paper describes the development and pilot testing of a smartphone application called TRAC-IT, which explores the potential to replace traditional travel surveys. It additionally investigates techniques for mode detection and the practicality of a critical points algorithm, intended to reduce data transfer requirements to that which is necessary for reconstructing a route. A similar study specifically for Blackberry phones sought to develop a mode classifier integrated with trip segmentation using 658 verified trips. This was the only smartphone application study not to use either Google Android or Apple’s iPhone Operating System (iOS).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>21192</offset><text>A separate passive study focussed on the development of an app called LogYard, for automatic crash notification for vulnerable road users and in particular all-terrain vehicle users. The authors tested the concept in a pilot study on cyclists, which, after the collection of simulated crash and bicycle movement data, demonstrated an algorithm that could detect accidents.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>21565</offset><text>3.2.2. Passive Smartphone Application for Instrumented Research Bicycle/Pedelec</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>21645</offset><text>An instrumented research bicycle set up similar to those mentioned in results section 1 was used in four studies, three of which were implemented on pedelecs. All of the pedelec studies utilised wireless data transfer, whilst a fourth instrumented bicycle study used a conventional bicycle with four helmet-mounted video cameras, requiring manual data download. The conventional instrumented bicycle was used in a fixed route experiment by researchers in Portland. In addition to the helmet cameras and 1 Hz smartphone GPS location, the experiment also included a galvanic skin response stress sensor and a power meter. In total six subjects rode the instrumented bicycle at different times of day in order to ascertain the impact of variable traffic levels.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>22404</offset><text>A similar fixed route setup was made in Austria, with the instrumentation of two different types of electric bicycles in combination with a test of electrically and conventionally powered mopeds. The e-bike experiment collected data from altogether 145 participants, with a fish-eye camera complementing the smartphone-integrated GPS. A custom-designed app allowed remote operator control of the instrumented bicycle via a Wireless Local Area Network base station at the experiment site.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>22892</offset><text>A larger study in Brighton, UK equipped a fleet of 35 e-bikes with a smartphone and power assistance sensors in a so-called Smart E-bike Monitoring System (SEMS). SEMS was powered by the e-bike battery and saved energy by running in a low power sleep state for the majority of the time. Every 25 s the phone woke and queried the accelerometer for 1.5 s. The system was kept active if movement was detected, otherwise the phone returned to the sleep state. Ninety-three participants took ownership of the research bicycles for up to eight weeks, and were provided with real-time feedback about their cycling activity via an online portal.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>23530</offset><text>A year-long field trial of 31 smartphone-instrumented electric bicycles was performed at the University of Waterloo in Canada. Unlike most instrumented research designs, the pedelecs were given to users in return for their participation, and were not rotated amongst a larger pool of participants. External sensors were limited to battery usage and performance, whilst discharge of the battery was minimised by keeping the phone in a sleep mode most of the time, only querying location and battery indicators for the first four seconds of every minute.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>24083</offset><text>3.2.3. Existing Active Smartphone Applications </text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>24131</offset><text>Active user smartphone apps are commonly used in the literature, where users are required to manually start and stop GPS recording. One benefit of active user apps is that the frequency of GPS recordings can be relatively high without battery depletion concerns (where passive apps frequently need to optimise energy use through reduced sensitivity). Several of the apps are specifically designed for research and planning purposes, such as CycleTracks, originally developed by the San Francisco County Transportation Authority and used in a five month study of 1083 users in the same city. GPS data is collected and stored locally on the device, with uploads data upon completion of a trip. The same application was also used in studies of three other US cities: Austin, Texas with 317 bicyclists, Seattle with 197 bicyclists over a 3.5 years period and Columbus, Ohio with 76 cyclists. The CycleTracks application was developed with specific consideration to minimise battery drain whilst in use, turning off when the phone battery level reaches 10%.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>25184</offset><text>The success of the CycleTracks application in multiple studies lead to its replication in a number of other regions, who built their own version of the application based on the original code. Three studies of this nature were found including: ORCycle in Oregon with 381 users, CycleAtlanta with 1529 users and CycleLane in Eugene, Oregon with 103 users.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>25538</offset><text>One smartphone study made use of the recreational tracking application Map My Tracks to collect the GPS traces of cyclists and bike couriers in Madrid. The study required participants to upload their tracks collected in the tracking application or with GPS devices to either the project website or application, making the required level of involvement from users higher than most other studies in this category. Note that studies that directly obtain data from sports or recreational applications without researcher input, are considered by this study to be crowdsourcing, and are discussed in the next section.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>26150</offset><text>3.2.4. Other Customised Active Smartphone Applications</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>26205</offset><text>A similar tailor-made app was commercially developed for use by the City of Toronto, confusingly called CycleTrack, which achieved a high level of participation: 4556 users and 33,220 journeys recorded over nine months. Interestingly over half of participants reported that they had not cycled since they were children, a contrast from most other smartphone-based studies, whose participants were mostly experienced riders.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>26629</offset><text>Other customised apps includes the Mon RésoVélo smartphone application created by McGill researchers, who obtained 10,000 trips from nearly 1000 users in Montreal, Canada, during four months of 2013. BeCity is a customised application built in same manner as the sports monitoring application Endomondo, but provides users with routing feedback due to the lack of other commercial actors performing this for cycling. Other customised smartphone apps for research or planning purposes were implemented in Gothenburg, Sweden, with 15 bicyclists instructed to ride on selected routes and in a route choice model study using data from 774 cyclists for Transport for London. These studies did not provide details concerning the application development or frequency of geo-located positions.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>27417</offset><text>3.3. Crowdsourcing</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>27436</offset><text>Thirteen papers make use of crowdsourcing as the principal method for obtaining location, amongst which ten utilised smartphone GPS applications and the one remaining study used a crowdsourcing platform for GPS devices. The ten crowdsourcing smartphone studies are split into sports applications (Strava, Sports Tracker and Endomondo), research/planning-oriented smartphone applications (Fiets Telweek, BikePRINT, RiderLog), a citizen science platform (Amazon Mechanical Turk) and individually donated GPS logs.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>27948</offset><text>3.3.1. Recreational/Sports Applications</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>27988</offset><text>Three studies included in this paper make use of the bicycle training oriented smartphone application Strava and the associated paid service StravaMetro, however none showed the full routes of individuals. Instead the studies made use of origin-destination data, link/street counts or node counts. This is because of StravaMetro’s policy of data aggregation whereby it is not possible to see how any individual route looks, most likely due to the privacy interests of users. Despite not meeting the inclusion criteria for this paper, Strava was included nonetheless because of the size of the dataset, the potential for individual route data to become available (it is deliberately reduced in quality) and because individual users can still opt to donate their routes to researchers. One such data donation initiative is the Bike Data Project, started after the 2015 release of Frederick Gertten’s Bikes Vs Cars documentary, which easily links to the user accounts of three sports applications Moves, Runkeeper and Strava (). Whilst Strava does not presently provide the individual route traces as a crowdsource, it has been used as a supplementary method by researchers for ride-along and ethnographic studies. More information on ride-along as a method is found in results Section 3.5.1. Lastly, it should be noted that Strava also allows for the input of GPS data from bicycle computers and GPS devices other than smartphones.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>29422</offset><text>A similar mobile application called Sports Tracker was used in a separate study focussed on providing automatic popularity-based routing in Helsinki. In this study, the full route trace of individuals was used, with a public dataset of nearly 30,000 routes from 1994 users. An issue witnessed by the researchers was the skewed distribution of routes, where 5% of the users had recorded 50% of the tracks. High variation in participation is however an issue across the crowdsourcing studies, and effects also the studies using GPS devices.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>29961</offset><text>Endomondo, the final sports application to be included here, was used in the context of the European Cycling Challenge (ECC) in 2013. The ECC is an annual initiative in the month of May that seeks to gamify cycling across participating European cities (). The Bologna dataset obtained by the researchers contained no information about the numbers of users, but approximately 5900 routes were available in the raw data. Subsequent years of the ECC have used different mobile tracking applications, but in general, the cities participate for a nominal fee on the basis that they subsequently own the data collected by their residents. The ECC website displays heat maps of different cities and a leader board of top cities (per capita and in total) to gamify the experience and motivate use, whilst at the end of May the top cities are presented prizes.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>30813</offset><text>The study that did not use smartphones instead gathered crowdsourced data from GPS devices (such as sports watches and cycling computers) through the recreation-oriented web platform RouteYou, a data sharing platform to enable users to find appropriate routes for recreational travel. In this study, 190,610 bicycle-related records were collected over two years from 6300 unique users living in East Flanders, Belgium.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>31232</offset><text>3.3.2. Customised Applications for Nationwide Data Collection</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>31294</offset><text>A practice-oriented smartphone application called RiderLog was used by researchers in Sydney to validate an agent-based model and census data for the same region. RiderLog is similar to the ECC in terms of goals, but rather than utilising a commercial application was specifically developed for the Australian Bicycle Network. The application is intended to stimulate cycling as an active transportation mode and provides users with a platform to monitor their progress.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>31765</offset><text>Fiets Telweek, or Bicycle Counting Week, is an initiative from The Netherlands (similarly performed in Flanders) to crowdsource cycling data to better understand the behaviour of Dutch cyclists. The event has occurred for a single week each September since 2015, and it was this first year of data that was used in one study of Amsterdam cyclists. The Amsterdam dataset available to the researchers included 12,413 trips from around 5000 users, and approximately one quarter of these trips were subsequently used in their creation of a discrete choice model for cyclist behaviour.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>32346</offset><text>Prior to the start of Fiets Telweek in 2015, BikePRINT was developed to make use of smartphone GPS data through a custom-designed app, whilst displaying data in an interactive map that made it more user friendly. The graphical interfaces demonstrated in the article do not reveal individual routes, but neither is it explicitly stated that the data is aggregated like Strava. Unfortunately, little detail is given about the process of data collection, however BikePRINT’s commercial successor The Urban Future (a spinoff from the NHTV Breda University of Applied Sciences), is at the time of writing hosting the 2015 to 2017 data for Fiets Telweek ().</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>33000</offset><text>3.3.3. Volunteered (Post-Collection) Data</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>33042</offset><text>A small study collected volunteered GPS log files from both smartphones and GPS devices via Korean bicyclist groups. Data collection efforts here demonstrated a greater representation bias than other crowdsourcing studies, as it focused only on enthusiast cyclists, all 54 of whom were male and aged between 19 and 42. Should the aforementioned Bike Data Project or similar platforms supporting volunteered data donation grow to represent many users, these representation problems could disappear.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>33540</offset><text>3.3.4. Instrumented Public Bikeshare</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>33577</offset><text>Two studies made use of instrumented bicycles in regular bikesharing schemes, whereby the first study retrofitted 130 Capital Bikeshare bicycles in Washington DC with GPS units. The devices were retrieved after four weeks deployment, during which time 36 GPS units were lost, together with their data. The recovered units recorded data for two weeks on average prior to the battery running out, and recorded in total 3596 trips. Loss of trip data was avoided in the second bikeshare study due to the use of real-time location from the GPS-enabled Grid Bikeshare in Phoenix, USA. The frequency of GPS readings was, however, relatively low, varying from one per minute to 25 per minute; a frequency sufficient for bikeshare fleet operators but not always sufficient for bicycle route analysis.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>34369</offset><text>Although no studies in this review made use of dockless bicycles, their increasing presence in cities around the world warrants their brief mention. Public dockless bikeshare systems use GPS-enabled bicycles in distributed fleets without specific docking stations. GPS is a necessity for the system to work since users can locate bicycles in real time via a smartphone application. Like the Grid Bikeshare study, data from dockless bicycles could potentially be obtained via fleet operators, representing a very significant future source of empirical route choice data.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>34939</offset><text>3.3.5. Citizen Science Crowdsourcing Platform</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>34985</offset><text>Finally, a pilot demonstration of Amazon Mechanical Turk (AMT), a citizen science crowdsourcing platform, was used to gather participants for a smartphone GPS study. Ten participants are reported on in this paper, however the research project aimed to collect data for 200 participants in total. AMT is a platform matching a large pool of workers and employers (called ‘requesters’) to perform relatively simple tasks such as data categorisation or image labelling. The researchers collected data in this manner for a payment level of $5, requiring participants to install a smartphone app, use the app for three days, upload the trip data, answer a survey and finally recruit somebody outside of the AMT network to do the same. Although a large number of potential workers is available, they are geographically dispersed, meaning that findings collected from participants may not be representative for a particular city or region. Qualitative research may however find the disperse worker pool to be of an advantage for comparative studies of cycling environments.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>36055</offset><text>3.4. Participant Recalled Route—Hand-Drawn, Web-Based or Verbal/Written Description </text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>36142</offset><text>3.4.1. Hand-Drawn (Paper-Based) Route Collection</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>36191</offset><text>The collection of hand-drawn route data requires very few resources, making it highly versatile for implementation in various studies, most commonly in combination with interviews or paper-based surveys, distributed in various manners. Many of the 15 studies in this category use a largely similar research design, thus in the interests of brevity, only the major methods are discussed in this category, whilst the remainder have been summarised in Table A2.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>36650</offset><text>The first study using hand-drawn routes was conducted Davis, California where the implementation of an on-street bicycle lane was to be evaluated. Interviews were conducted before (n = 254) and after (n = 110) the bike lane was built, in which cyclists in households north of the implementation area were asked to draw their usual route to downtown or campus (which lay south of the area of interest). A number of other studies make use of similar interview techniques, but generally for intercepted cyclists in a specific study area.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>37185</offset><text>Two Dutch studies investigate the implementation of a bicycle network scheme in Delft, one focussing on the route choices of cyclists prior to network implementation in 1982, and the other discussing and comparing this with the detailed post-implementation data, collected three years later. The pre-intervention data collection was performed in a single day, with 15 roadside locations where bicycle counts for bicycles were performed, together with interviews during which cyclists were given a mail-back route choice questionnaire. In total, 60% or 2194 cyclists returned the route choice survey, whose main question concerned plotting the entirety of the journey undertaken on the day the interview. The second study, a project summary report, summarises the impacts of the initiatives in Delft. The study reports that “about 58% of the observed changes in bicycle volumes are caused by route shifts” but that “compared to travel time and directness, the type of facility is as such an unimportant route choice factor”.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>38217</offset><text>Mail-back surveys were also given to passers-by in a study in Guelph, Canada whilst another study by the same main author performed in Ottawa (n = 1603) and Toronto, Canada (n = 1360) used mail-back questionnaires attached to the parked bicycles. Response rates in the second study were between 45% and 53% for the two cities, which is noteworthy considering the single contact and lack of follow up of participants. Another study used this approach in combination with manual distribution and collection in Phoenix, USA (n = 150).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>38749</offset><text>The third major category of recruitment in this section is for studies that require participants to fill in paper surveys on-site without the same follow up as in interviews. This was done at large events where booths could be established or at workplaces or schools.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>39017</offset><text>Finally, one study utilised a travel diary concept for the recording of routes as part of an ethnographic study of 26 cycling activists in Quito, Ecuador. The participants in the study were asked to maintain a diary of incidents they had whilst cycling that were to be supplemented with freehand drawn mental maps (not assisted with a base map). Such an approach is highly dependent on the participants being very familiar with the area they cycle in and an ability to convey this information accurately in a sketch. Routes drawn in this manner may not have the same resolution as those that are map-assisted.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>39627</offset><text>3.4.2. Web-Based/Digitally Drawn Routes</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>39667</offset><text>The first study to use web-based or digitally drawn route choices was implemented amongst 142 staff and students of the University of Auckland. Route choices of both cyclists and potential cyclists were recorded in a web-based GIS tool, although the exact details of the method are not explained.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>39964</offset><text>The same concept was used in a second web-based data collection paper in the city of Copenhagen, for which 398 responses were received. The study required cyclists to identify locations along their most recent route (which they traced turn-for-turn) where they had up to three positive and three negative experiences, leading to 890 points being located. Such experiences could have been the perception of danger at a blind corner or a positive comment regarding a widened bicycle lane. This data was collected in a Google Maps Application Programming Interface (API), allowing for data to be entered directly by users into a mapping interface with relative simplicity.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>40634</offset><text>3.4.3. Verbal/Written Descriptions </text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>40670</offset><text>Seven participant recalled route choice studies were located that use principally written or verbal descriptions of routes rather than visual depictions. The oldest study in this systematic literature review uses a described route choice data collection protocol in New York, USA. Two methods were devised, the first of which asked 35 families to list the route (presumably with road names) of their most recent bicycle trip and the second of which involved a verbal description of current route in 155 intercept interviews.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>41195</offset><text>Three studies use even more limited descriptions of route choice, that only partially capture the route choice of cyclists—specifically through the inclusion of one to two additional points along a new piece of bicycle infrastructure in addition to origin and destination. The first of these evaluated the impact of a well-established off-road trail in Minneapolis, USA with 3121 cyclists stopped in a human intercept survey. The second study using access and egress points to cycling infrastructure collected data via an online survey of usual bicycle trips in Montreal. The study additionally asked for suggestions for new bicycle infrastructure locations. The high number of responses (n = 2917) was achieved through wide publication in conventional media formats, social networking websites and on the street. The third study uses only a single point (in addition to origin and destination) along a newly opened cycleway in Sydney to determine route choice; a point where 783 interviewed cyclists were intercepted as they waited at a traffic light. Although cyclists were asked if they had changed route after the cycleway was opened, it was not required for them to specifically provide details of the existing route.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>42420</offset><text>One approach to avoid poor geographical resolution is to interview cyclists about their route choice, where communication between interviewer and interviewee can ensure an accurate transcription of route choice details. This was done in a Vancouver telephone interview study with 74 participants for all modes, who had previously participated in a survey of cyclists and indicated willingness to be contacted for future research. A benefit of this particular methodological set up was that participants had previously received a cycling map of Vancouver they were prompted to use as a visual aid when discussing typical routes with the interviewer. Route descriptions were also requested of 100 bike share users in Santiago, Chile, who were intercepted at stations by interviewers with paper-based surveys.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>43227</offset><text>The poor ability of listing methods to accurately identify origin and destination mean that average trip lengths collected in this manner can be considerably shorter (or longer) than actual routes. Additionally many cyclists may not be sufficiently familiar with their environment to be able to give an accurate description of where they had or usually cycled. Benefits of this method are simplicity of execution, and in the case of interviews, the potential to gather richer open answers regarding variables that may have influenced route choice.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>43775</offset><text>3.5. Accompanied Journey—Ride-Along and Tracking Based</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>43832</offset><text>3.5.1. Ride-Along Survey</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>43857</offset><text>A technique with high potential for qualitative and ethnographic cycling research is the ride-along survey, a form of interview in which the interviewer accompanies the participant for part or their entire journey. Accompanied interviews were used to inform the design of a stated preference study from Transport for London. In this case, ride-along surveys were performed with 16 participants, who were approached by interviewers at traffic lights and bike parks and then accompanied for 10–15 min of the remainder of their journey. A short roadside interview was conducted post-ride in which cyclists were asked questions about their route choice. Participants chose their routes themselves and were offered a gift voucher in return for their participation. The qualitative results here were used to inform the design of an online stated preference survey, which tested three key attributes: type of cycle lane, type of road and journey time.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>44804</offset><text>The two remaining papers focussed upon more ethnographic research. The first of these incorporated ride-along interviews conducted with 15 inhabitants around Utrecht in The Netherlands, combining GPS tracking, tape-recording and video documentation (from interviewer perspective). Although GPS provides good location data, the video in this case provided information that was more important for the ethnographic study purpose (interaction with other road users during busy commuting times). This technique allowed researchers to retrace their ‘steps’ in visual field notes. Participants were recruited through an online discussion group and snowballing from contacts within the research group. Unlike the London study, the conducive environment to ‘conversational cycling’ in The Netherlands meant that the ride-along interview was indeed conducted mid-ride rather than post-ride, something the authors recognise may not be always be possible in other contexts.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>45774</offset><text>The other ethnographic study also makes use of GPS, although in this case, was intended to examine the use of dedicated ride-logging smartphone applications. Reflective diaries and structured interviews with 20 experienced club cyclists in and around Stoke-on-Trent, UK formed the basis of the research material whilst the author additionally accompanied the same cyclists on a number of group rides.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>46175</offset><text>Benefits of the study design using ride-along surveys are the ability to interpret gestures and body language, together with other shared experiential factors that are not easily captured through the majority of other techniques. A downside can be that the observed behaviour of the cyclist (particularly risk-taking behaviour or the breaking of traffic laws) is influenced because they are conscious of being recorded or observed. This phenomenon can be mitigated if trust is developed between the interviewer and participant through more immersive researcher participation, as was demonstrated in an aforementioned study of cycling activists in Quito, Ecuador.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>46838</offset><text>3.5.2. Tracking</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>46854</offset><text>One study made use of tracking, but was GPS-assisted using devices fitted to trackers’ bicycles to allow for simpler data collection. Methodologically the study involved tracking of 119 cyclists from a number of fixed destinations and a number of interception locations. A trip was considered finished after a cyclist dismounted. The route data for intercepted subjects is however incomplete since the initial part of the journey is not recorded. The research ethics of this methodology are not discussed in the article, although future studies should consider this.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>47423</offset><text>3.6. Camera</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>47435</offset><text>Three studies make use of egocentric cameras as the primary means for determining route choice. Two used helmet-cameras whilst one used two bicycle mounted cameras. This naturalistic bicycle data was used to gather first hand cyclist experiences in the context of traffic safety and planning for cycling. The most recent of these used the video footage taken by 24 commuter cyclists in Plymouth, UK to perform video-guided interviews with the participant post-ride. The researcher reviewed the videos prior to the interview in order to develop a customised set of interview questions for each participant. Participants were also able to reflect upon what they saw in the video and volunteer comments. Neither of the other studies included this element, one of which was intended to capture overtaking distances on specific routes by the researcher themselves, the other classifying accidents or near-accidents.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>48346</offset><text>Route choice was not explicitly a part of any of the studies, however all three studies have a forward-facing camera that shows the route being ridden. The video footage alone could be used to recreate route choices by a reviewer familiar with the area; however, those studies that were interested in both naturalistic behaviour and location tended to make use of cameras in GPS-instrumented bicycle set-ups as described in results Section 1 and Section 2.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>48803</offset><text>3.7. Virtual Reality (VR) Simulated Environments</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>48852</offset><text>A VR cycling simulator called Cycle SPACES was developed in Breda in The Netherlands and is discussed in a pilot study of a proposed cycle superhighway in the same city. A speed sensor allows users to adapt their speed in the virtual modelled environment (displayed with an Oculus Rift VR headset), whilst other variables such as time of day or the colour of the bicycle highway could be modified with push buttons on the handlebars. The participants were observed to react as expected in the different modelled environments, relaxing considerably in the future scenarios in which greater separation from traffic was displayed. Although route choices were not enabled in this experimental set-up, the addition of steering control together with eye-tracking, artificial intelligence of other road users, dynamic resistance and leaning have all been identified as future additions to the Cycle SPACES project.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>49760</offset><text>A Japanese bicycle simulator experiment with 23 university students tests two scenarios that each provide the rider with visual feedback regarding speed, whilst a control group performs the experiment without visual input. The experimental set up includes an exercise bicycle, speed sensor and large visual display. The first scenario shows a virtual bicycle icon on a Google map, which moves in accordance to pedalling speed, whilst the second scenario shows Google Street View images (taken at 10 m spacing) displayed in relation to pedalling speed. The route was fixed between the university and the nearest train station, without choice of route. Significant differences (p &lt; 0.05) were found between the control and street image groups for enjoyment, outdoor-feeling and speed of cycling. Although route choice was not a studied element of the study, this would be a logical future step for virtual reality research.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>50682</offset><text>Neither of the simulator-based VR studies study route choice unlike the majority of articles in this review, however as a relatively emergent field, the methods introduced here show promise for scaling up into this realm.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>50904</offset><text>4. Discussion</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>50918</offset><text>This study presents a systematic review of methods that have been applied to the study of whole journey bicycle movement. The research publications included within this review are mostly quite new, with 99 of the 112 studies published between 2010 and 2017. This is illustrated in Figure 3 below. In addition to the growth of research in general, much of the growth in research production can be attributed to the arrival of affordable GPS technology around the early-mid 2000s. GPS technology is used in over two thirds of the research papers collected through this systematic review, as illustrated in Figure 2 in the methods section. A modest increase in the number of papers utilising more mature methods like participant recalled routes can also be witnessed. Because the review required the digital availability of full-text articles, there is a systematic bias towards newer (especially post-internet) research, as is the case for the majority of review articles.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>51889</offset><text>The numbers of participants is displayed in Figure 3 as a box-and-whisker plot for all 92 articles that reported this figure. Four method families are shown, whilst the remainder are aggregated under ‘other’ due to the low number of articles in the method families: accompanied trips, camera and virtual reality. The graph shows that the lowest numbers of participants does not vary greatly, but median number of participants can be quite different based on method family.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>52366</offset><text>Crowdsourcing studies have understandably the highest median number of participants (1994), although it should be noted that many of the studies reported findings from Strava, which do not presently provide individual route journeys. The high participant numbers in Strava are also the reason for not displaying the plot for crowdsourcing in its entirety (13,684 unique users are captured in the largest study covered by this review). Smartphone GPS studies (316) and participant recalled route choice studies (254) follow next in median sample size, due most likely to the relative low-cost and simplicity of collecting data respectively. GPS devices, although utilising the same technology from crowdsourcing and smartphone studies, have a relatively lower median number of participants of 43, whilst the three remaining method families have a collective median of 18. This can be partly explained by each of the method families. Accompanied journey studies generally involved more qualitative methods (with generally lower sample sizes) making use of such techniques as interviews with participants. One notable exception involved tracking, unbeknown to 212 subjects. Camera based studies are generally focussed on traffic safety, and whilst the data collection is not so time consuming as for interviews, requires prohibitively large amounts of time for manual data processing in order to establish route choices of more than a small number of participants. Machine learning and other image recognition technologies may assist in reducing the time required for this method in future work. The final method categorised under “other” in Figure 4 is virtual reality, which comprised only two studies, both at the demonstration stage. For such simulator studies, considerable amounts of time is required in creating the virtual environment to test, however after a model is created, it should be reasonably possible to sample much larger numbers of participants.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>54333</offset><text>The geographical spread of research according to city of data collection is shown in Figure 5. The USA is the most prolific producer of articles included in this review at 31 papers, followed by the UK and Canada with 12 and 11 respectively. Of the 112 empirical articles that form the basis of this review, 109 were performed in developed countries, defined here as those countries with a very high Human Development Index (HDI) in the 2016 Human Development Report (). This means in practice that only 3% of the empirical data collected on whole-journey bicycle routes is in developing country contexts (China, Ecuador and South Africa). To put this in perspective, just over 20% of all research is produced by countries that do not have a very high HDI (based on submission institution of the ~33 million citable English language documents in Scopus from 1996 to 2016 ). Hence, whilst over-representation of developed countries is present across all fields of research, it is considerably higher for bicycle route research. This is surprising given the relatively low costs of collecting route choice data (especially for surveys and smartphone apps) compared to research as a whole. However, this observation could indicate that funding is far from the sole determinant of research production. Indeed the low amount of cycling research may be due to a different focus in the research performed in developing countries, where the promotion of bicycles for transportation may be less prioritised.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>55832</offset><text>4.1. Reasons for Route Choice</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>55862</offset><text>GPS is utilised in two thirds of all the research collected, providing a relatively high level of resolution for route choice behaviour between different streets and paths. However, with the exception of some smartphone studies and others with a user interface, the decision-making process behind the route choice is not typically revealed through this method. This is a common limitation of revealed preference studies, where the primary contribution is in showing the preference made rather than demonstrating why.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>56379</offset><text>To understand more about the decisions being made by bicyclists, the other methods can be used. Follow-up interviews or surveys as part of GPS based studies has been demonstrated to provide attitudinal parameters. Crowdsourcing as a method does not generally allow the study designer to ask questions of participants as the data is usually collected for a different purpose (sports applications for example), potentially some time ago. Participant recalled routes and accompanied journeys are typically performed as part of intercept surveys or organised interviews, which lend themselves well to establishing reasons for participants’ route choice. Cameras can be used to inform reasons for bicycle route choice, however in a limited manner since only visually identifiable reasons such as traffic or road surface condition in the immediate vicinity of the cyclist can be observed. The ideal situation is not only to accompany cyclists, but to record this on camera whilst interviewing cyclists, as was done in a qualitative study in Utrecht in the Netherlands. The final method family of virtual reality allows testing of past, current or future scenarios, limited only by the time needed to create these virtual environments. Users can be interviewed whilst participating in the simulator environment, or can provide real time feedback through handlebar mounted buttons as discussed in Section 3.7 above. VR technologies are thus highly promising for participatory planning and user consultation of bicycle infrastructure, and it can be expected that this subset of the research will grow in coming years.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>57990</offset><text>Revealed preference data alone does not however lack usefulness simply because it does not establish reasons for route choice. To the contrary, revealed preference data allows for large amounts of quantitative material to be collected, which combined with good sample representativeness, provides a holistic snapshot of a region’s cycling preferences. GPS based studies can sample many hundreds or even thousands of users, however combination with other methods such as cameras or follow-up interviews are necessary to begin to establish reasons for a particular route being chosen. Egocentric cameras alone can provide some of the context behind route choice, however data processing times for establishing a single route trace make this a more suitable supporting method to complement accompanied journeys or instrumented bicycle research designs. Surveys or interviews in which participants recall their routes can be highly informative across large samples, however generally only one to two routes can be recalled with reasonable accuracy. Short or infrequent trips, trip chains and trips taken some time ago are poorly represented in participant recalled route choice studies. Comprehensive travel diary studies that ask for route choice of all trips (together with the usual trip purpose and mode) are uncommon, potentially because of the effort of the recall is too great or the risk of incorrect routes being drawn too high. Such considerations should be made in the context of the target sample and research purpose. If the sample is young children, GPS based tracking may prove to be difficult because of increased privacy concerns from parents and research ethics committees. Likewise, if the purpose of the study were to quantitatively determine the surface riding quality, the use of accelerometers would be more useful than interviews.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>59843</offset><text>4.2. Representation</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>59863</offset><text>An issue that was witnessed repeatedly across different methods is the statistical representation of the participants. One study summarises the typical representation problems that occur in revealed preference bicycle studies: “the GPS participants were slightly older, were more likely to have a college degree, had higher incomes, and were more likely to have full-time jobs than other regular cyclists”. Similar results were found by other studies, despite large numbers of participants.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>60358</offset><text>In many cases the research aims target particular groups of participants, such as through the specific targeting of elderly bike users. The intention here is evidently not to assume representativeness by choosing one demographic, however other studies also chose specific users to the detriment of representation. The best example of this is the adult commuter cyclist target group, who are frequently chosen because they are simplest to recruit, although not necessarily most numerous or representative of the general population. Unless the sample is targeted with the specific aim to improve representativeness, we risk producing results that poorly demonstrate how bicyclists behave, let alone the target cycling population (those who do not presently use a bicycle regularly).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>61139</offset><text>A number of studies specifically avoided targeting a particular transport mode during recruitment in order to get a better picture of normal road user behaviour. It should be noted however that the lack of representation amongst cyclists targeted for GPS studies is not necessarily improved when considering all transport modes. One combined GPS and travel diary study reported participants were better educated, wealthier and older than the those captured by census data; similar attributes for the samples in much of the bicycle research.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>61680</offset><text>Adult men are highly overrepresented in many sports and recreation-focussed smartphone apps. In some low cycling areas, this may indeed be representative of the cycling population, however the consideration should also be made for the main target group of bicycle promotion initiatives: infrequent and non-cyclists. This is in contrast to most GPS data studies, which seek to achieve better gender and age balance during participant recruitment.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>62126</offset><text>Removing technology-based data collection methods from the discussion gives a different perspective. A large study of cyclists conducted in Groningen, The Netherlands (n = 1012) and Växjö, Sweden (n = 1003) stopped participants mid-journey to answer questions concerning trip purpose, origin-destination, actual route choice and route choice motive. The random sampling process meant that both gender and age were well represented, although the authors explain that the sampling sites were selected based on high vulnerable road user flows, and were thus not reflective of each city’s general population.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>62735</offset><text>The sampling methodology, as much as the actual data collection method can determine the representativeness of the sample. In the example above, random sampling was used together with a survey requiring little participant involvement—resulting in excellent representation for the area sampled. If the sampling methodology involves searching for potential participants on bicycle forums, it should be considered that the forums are not representative of the general cycling public, but rather a special-interest subgroup of cyclists. Similarly, the use of sports applications as a data collection method predetermines the sample to be biased towards middle-aged men. Good representation is not simple to achieve, but the targeting of everyday cyclists is best achieved through random sampling in the area of interest. This can mean more time is required to achieve the desired sample size, but can also be performed using randomised telephone directory lists or mail-out surveys.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>63716</offset><text>4.3. Future Research</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>63737</offset><text>Aerial drone and computer vision software (that automatically identifies mode, position and velocity of multiple road users) is being increasingly used in combination to record traffic behaviour. Presently this has been applied mostly to intersection or individual segments of interest, due to a limited scope in a single camera.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>64067</offset><text>Although elements of route choice can be easily observed in this manner, the capture of entire route choices of cyclists is unlikely to be possible unless either the drone tracks individuals or multiple elevated cameras are used to identify and subsequently re-identify the same users. This is prohibitively difficult in a manual video analysis study; however, advanced computer vision technology could allow the identification and subsequent re-identification at multiple points in a network of fixed elevated cameras. Surveillance and privacy related issues may however make both of these methods unworkable from a research ethics standpoint, and must be seriously considered prior to implementation.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>64770</offset><text>5. Conclusions</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>64785</offset><text>This literature review provides an overview of the techniques that are available to track whole-journey cyclist movements in the bicycle network and by doing so can allow for insights concerning the preferences of bicycle users. Sample selection must however be taken into consideration concerning the transferability of such insights. Samples should ideally be broadly representative of the general public or preferably the target audience (for example young children if the aim is to promote cycling to school). The prioritisation of infrastructure spending in accordance with what is demonstrated to have the greatest impact for a representative sample will most efficiently allow for an increase in cycling modal share.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>65509</offset><text>The literature review revealed some key findings regarding the collection of cyclist data. GPS-related data sources were used in two thirds of the empirical studies covered by this review. Experimental research designs using GPS-instrumented bicycle setups were common in the literature, however there appears to be more growth potential in the use of smartphone GPS and crowdsourcing. For these data sources, automatic mode-classification algorithms are often required. Less technology-oriented approaches involving participant recall of routes are demonstrated to be able to achieve similar levels of participation to smartphone-based approaches, although usually restricted to a single route. GPS alone does not provide the resolution necessary to determine the choice of infrastructure located on a single segment (such as footpath or bicycle lane), and in these cases camera technology, interviews or accompanied journeys is necessary.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>66450</offset><text>Data privacy was at times observed to hinder the participant recruitment process, especially when considering passive smartphone recorded data. The availability of location data from smartphones can reveal a significant amount of personal information including work, home, leisure activities and behaviour. It is thus essential that any proposed data collection approach ensures participant anonymity and is approved by a local research ethics committee prior to implementation. This includes not only personal details but also the obscuration of precise origins and destinations if these could be used to identify participants. Participants in travel surveys of this nature must also be well informed of the process by which the research is conducted.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>67203</offset><text>Finally crowdsourcing-based studies, together with virtual reality simulators and advanced computer vision processing of video data can be expected to develop significantly in the coming years, providing new and rich future data sources for the study of bicycle route choice.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">COMP_INT</infon><infon key="type">title</infon><offset>67479</offset><text>Conflicts of Interest</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">COMP_INT</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>67501</offset><text>The author declares no conflict of interest.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">APPENDIX</infon><infon key="type">title</infon><offset>67546</offset><text>Appendix A</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">ijerph-15-00470-t0A1.xml</infon><infon key="id">ijerph-15-00470-t0A1</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_caption</infon><offset>67557</offset><text>Classification of the 112 empirical studies based on principal route choice methods used into family and primary method group.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">ijerph-15-00470-t0A1.xml</infon><infon key="id">ijerph-15-00470-t0A1</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table</infon><infon key="xml">&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;table frame=&quot;hsides&quot; rules=&quot;groups&quot;&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-top:solid thin;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Family&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-top:solid thin;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Sub-Group&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-top:solid thin;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Main Benefits&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-top:solid thin;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Main Drawbacks&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-top:solid thin;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Integration with Other Methods&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-top:solid thin;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Sources&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;GPS device—not including smartphone GPS (47)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Instrumented research bicycle&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Pre-configured for data collection&lt;break/&gt; Flexible experimental set up&lt;break/&gt; Consistent data (same bicycle for all users)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Participants must charge instrumentation for longer term studies&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;√√√&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B17-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;17&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B25-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;25&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B26-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;26&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B30-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;30&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B32-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;32&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B33-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;33&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B34-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;34&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B35-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;35&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B36-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;36&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Instrumented research pedal-assisted electric bicycle (pedelec)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Same as for instrumented research bicycle&lt;break/&gt; Pedelec power source allows longer term data&lt;break/&gt; collection&lt;break/&gt; Simple activation of GPS on start up&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Initial purchase cost of bicycle&lt;break/&gt; Unfamiliarity of users with pedelecs can result in abnormal cycling behaviour&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;√√√&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B16-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;16&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B22-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;22&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B24-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;24&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B28-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;28&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B37-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;37&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Instrumented participant bicycle&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Familiarity with own bicycle gives good naturalistic data&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Difficulty of comparing secondary data sources such as vibration because of bicycle variety&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;√√&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B27-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;27&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B31-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;31&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B38-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;38&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B39-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;39&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B40-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;40&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B41-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;41&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Instrumented participant pedelec&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Pedelec power source allows longer term data collection&lt;break/&gt; Simple activation of GPS on start up&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Difficulty in recruiting participants (if low numbers of pedelecs used)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;√√√&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B15-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;15&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B42-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;42&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Instrumented quasi-bikeshare (university pilot scheme)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Comparison of many users possible with autonomous data retrieval&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Maintenance and purchase cost of pilot scheme&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;√√&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B23-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;23&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B43-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;43&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Instrumented participant (two or more devices borne by participant)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Intermodal&lt;break/&gt; Pre-configured for data collection&lt;break/&gt; User interface (if present) can assist engagement with user (for travel survey or to remember charging)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Mode identification necessary Can be troublesome for users to carry all instrumentation (depending on size)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;√√&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B14-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;14&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B19-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;19&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B46-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;46&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B47-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;47&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B48-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;48&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;GPS integrated in other device (excl. smartphone and accelerometer)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Intermodal&lt;break/&gt; User interface (if present) can assist engagement with user (for travel survey or to remember charging)&lt;break/&gt; Compact device, easy to carry in pocket or bag&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Mode identification necessary&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;√&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B20-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;20&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B49-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;49&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B50-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;50&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B51-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;51&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Wearable GPS device&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Intermodal&lt;break/&gt; Low participant burden&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Mode identification necessary&lt;break/&gt; Participants can forget to charge battery&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;√&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B52-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;52&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B53-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;53&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B54-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;54&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B55-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;55&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B56-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;56&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Participant-borne GPS device (no mention of wearability)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Intermodal&lt;break/&gt; Compact device, easy to carry in pocket or bag&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Mode identification necessary&lt;break/&gt; Participants can forget to take GPS on all journeys or to charge battery&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;√&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B18-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;18&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B21-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;21&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B29-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;29&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B57-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;57&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B58-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;58&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B59-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;59&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B60-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;60&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B61-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;61&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Handlebar-mounted GPS participant bicycle (without additional instrumentation)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;No need to perform mode identification&lt;break/&gt; Participant does not need to remember to take GPS on bicycle journeys&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Participants can easily forget to charge battery if taking infrequent bicycle trips&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;√&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B62-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;62&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Smartphone GPS—participants solicited for research (20)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Passive user registration—no input required from user, trips detected automatically&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Intermodal&lt;break/&gt; Can be combined with travel diary (participants can confirm mode/trip purpose)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Mode identification necessary&lt;break/&gt; Recruitment more difficult than for active user apps, where participant has more control over the data they record&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;√√&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B66-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;66&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B72-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;72&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B73-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;73&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Passive user registration—smartphone based instrumented research bicycle (and pedelec)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Same as for GPS -instrumented research bicycle/pedelec&lt;break/&gt; Simpler configuration of instrumentation with smartphone (if only basic sensors used)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Same as for GPS -instrumented research bicycle/pedelec&lt;break/&gt; Energy saving required, which reduces data quality&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;√√√&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B67-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;67&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B68-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;68&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B70-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;70&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B74-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;74&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Active user registration (user activates GPS through app)—using or developed from the app “CycleTracks”&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Few battery problems&lt;break/&gt; Proven method—readily obtainable for other studies&lt;break/&gt; User control over data provision (can opt to not record specific journeys)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;User must engage with trip to begin, pause and stop recording&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;√√&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B69-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;69&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B75-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;75&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B76-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;76&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B77-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;77&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B78-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;78&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B79-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;79&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B80-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;80&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Active user registration—other customised app specifically designed to provide data for planners/researchers&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Backend system allows simple access to necessary user data&lt;break/&gt; User control over data provision&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;User must engage with trip to begin, pause and stop recording&lt;break/&gt; App must be developed&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;√√&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B81-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;81&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B82-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;82&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B83-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;83&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B84-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;84&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B85-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;85&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Active user registration—via recreation-oriented apps&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Collating of data can be automated via access tokens&lt;break/&gt; No need to develop app&lt;break/&gt; User control over data provision&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;User must engage with trip to begin, pause and stop recording&lt;break/&gt; User must upload data in some experimental designs&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;√&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B71-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;71&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Crowdsourcing—data generally not solicited by researchers (13)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Recreational/sports application (smartphone)—data collection not solicited by researchers&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Data obtained en masse via some application owners&lt;break/&gt; Longitudinal data&lt;break/&gt; Detailed data can be volunteered&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Sports app users are not representative of general public&lt;break/&gt; Data privacy often restricts full access to individual trips&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;√&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B86-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;86&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B87-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;87&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B88-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;88&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B89-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;89&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B90-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;90&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B91-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;91&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Customised smartphone application for nationwide data collection (intended for data sharing)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Large dataset&lt;break/&gt; Whole country data for comparison&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Data privacy often restricts full access to individual trips&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;√√&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B92-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;92&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B93-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;93&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B94-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;94&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Volunteered data from previously collected routes (access to existing data solicited by researchers)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Same as for sports applications, but only for volunteered routes&lt;break/&gt; User control over data provision&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Representativeness&lt;break/&gt; Recruitment of GPS users can be difficult&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;√&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B95-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;95&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Instrumented public bikeshare bicycles&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Representativeness&lt;break/&gt; Large dataset&lt;break/&gt; Longitudinal access can be obtained via operators of GPS-enabled bikeshare fleet&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Generally limited to GPS only&lt;break/&gt; User data may be retained for data privacy reasons&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;√√&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B44-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;44&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B45-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;45&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Citizen science crowdsourcing platform (Amazon Mechanical Turk)—for smartphone study&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Affordable means of obtaining responses with low researcher burden&lt;break/&gt; Can sample from global network of users&lt;break/&gt; Cannot meet with participants readily&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Difficult to be geographically specific (platform users are spread globally)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;√√&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B96-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;96&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Participant recalled route—hand-drawn (15), web-based (2) or verbal/written description (6)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Hand drawn from interview of participants&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Interviewer can ask for clarification (including use of different parts of street) as route is drawn&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Accuracy—lack of familiarity with area&lt;break/&gt; Limited application beyond usual journey or most recent&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;√√&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B97-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;97&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B98-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;98&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B99-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;99&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Hand drawn from mail-back surveys after interception of passers-by&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Large numbers of respondents possible Interception not always practical or legal (some jurisdictions classify cyclists in a similar manner to motorised vehicle users)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Relies on map familiarity Limited application beyond usual journey or most recent&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;√&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B100-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;100&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B101-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;101&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B102-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;102&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B103-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;103&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Hand drawn from paper surveys completed on-site (at destination)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Interviewers can assist as required&lt;break/&gt; Ease of recruiting large numbers of participants&lt;break/&gt; Can tailor map according to destination environment (such as workplace)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Relies on map familiarity&lt;break/&gt; Limited application beyond usual journey or most recent&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;√&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B105-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;105&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B106-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;106&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B107-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;107&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B108-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;108&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B109-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;109&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B110-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;110&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Hand drawn from printable survey distributed online/advertisements&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Large survey distribution possible (through forums, newspapers, noticeboards, bicycle shops etc.)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Relies on map familiarity&lt;break/&gt; Limited application beyond usual journey or most recent&lt;break/&gt; High participant burden to print survey&lt;break/&gt; Map detail vs. size trade-off (whole city is difficult to appropriately represent in map)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;√&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B104-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;104&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Hand drawn from mental mapping journal (specific target audience)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Longitudinal time frame (multiple journeys, not just most recent or usual)&lt;break/&gt; Participant reflection in journal&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;No map guidance&lt;break/&gt; Uncertainty in matching participant-recalled routes to reality&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;√&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B111-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;111&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Mapping Application Programming Interface (API) for online route tracing&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Low participant burden—large quantitative datasets possible&lt;break/&gt; Routing algorithms can be used to suggest routes for origin-destination&lt;break/&gt; Can be integrated with Public Participation Geographic Information System (PPGIS) for obtaining geo-located user feedback&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Only limited numbers of routes generally recalled&lt;break/&gt; Relies on map familiarity&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;√√&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B112-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;112&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B113-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;113&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Description using list of road names used&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Quick methodology, readily applicable to intercept interviews&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Accuracy—recall error/lack of familiarity with road names&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;√&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B114-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;114&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Description using points/landmarks along route (verbal or online)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Quick methodology, readily applicable to intercept interviews&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Imprecise—often only two points along route&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;√&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B115-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;115&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B116-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;116&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B117-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;117&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Description from detailed interview&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Interviewer can ask for clarification&lt;break/&gt; Can be map-assisted&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Accuracy—lack of familiarity with area&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;√√&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B118-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;118&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B119-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;119&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Accompanied trip—ride-along (3) or tracking (1)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Ride-along&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Experiential ‘sensescapes’ can be captured and discussed real-time&lt;break/&gt; Best captures the context of the bicycle user&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Transcribing can be difficult (reduced clarity from participants when cycling in addition to noise)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;√√√&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B121-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;121&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B122-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;122&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Post ride-along interview&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Reasons for choices can be explained&lt;break/&gt; Suitable in environments where conversational cycling not practical&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Lack of real-time participant reflection compared to ride-along&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;√√√&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B120-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;120&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Unobtrusive tracking from distance&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Recruitment not necessary&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Lack of ‘participant’ consent&lt;break/&gt; Time intensive&lt;break/&gt; Difficult to capture journeys originating from homes&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;√&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B123-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;123&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Camera (3)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Egocentric camera on rider/bicycle (commonly used as a supplementary method)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Naturalistic behaviour and interactions can be captured including traffic violations and interactions with other road users&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Time intensive for route choice&lt;break/&gt; Requires researcher familiarity with area&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;√√&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B124-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;124&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B125-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;125&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B126-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;126&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Virtual Reality (VR) (2)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Immersion in virtual/photographed street environment&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Proposed changes to built environment can be evaluated in detail&lt;break/&gt; Non-cyclists’ revealed preference behaviour can be tested in a safe environment&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Modelling time requirement for virtual environment&lt;break/&gt; Some participants experience dizziness in VR simulators&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;√√&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B127-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;127&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B128-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;128&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
</infon><offset>67684</offset><text>Family	Sub-Group	Main Benefits	Main Drawbacks	Integration with Other Methods	Sources	 	GPS device—not including smartphone GPS (47)	Instrumented research bicycle	Pre-configured for data collection Flexible experimental set up Consistent data (same bicycle for all users)	Participants must charge instrumentation for longer term studies	√√√		 		Instrumented research pedal-assisted electric bicycle (pedelec)	Same as for instrumented research bicycle Pedelec power source allows longer term data collection Simple activation of GPS on start up	Initial purchase cost of bicycle Unfamiliarity of users with pedelecs can result in abnormal cycling behaviour	√√√		 		Instrumented participant bicycle	Familiarity with own bicycle gives good naturalistic data	Difficulty of comparing secondary data sources such as vibration because of bicycle variety	√√		 		Instrumented participant pedelec	Pedelec power source allows longer term data collection Simple activation of GPS on start up	Difficulty in recruiting participants (if low numbers of pedelecs used)	√√√		 		Instrumented quasi-bikeshare (university pilot scheme)	Comparison of many users possible with autonomous data retrieval	Maintenance and purchase cost of pilot scheme	√√		 		Instrumented participant (two or more devices borne by participant)	Intermodal Pre-configured for data collection User interface (if present) can assist engagement with user (for travel survey or to remember charging)	Mode identification necessary Can be troublesome for users to carry all instrumentation (depending on size)	√√		 		GPS integrated in other device (excl. smartphone and accelerometer)	Intermodal User interface (if present) can assist engagement with user (for travel survey or to remember charging) Compact device, easy to carry in pocket or bag	Mode identification necessary	√		 		Wearable GPS device	Intermodal Low participant burden	Mode identification necessary Participants can forget to charge battery	√		 		Participant-borne GPS device (no mention of wearability)	Intermodal Compact device, easy to carry in pocket or bag	Mode identification necessary Participants can forget to take GPS on all journeys or to charge battery	√		 		Handlebar-mounted GPS participant bicycle (without additional instrumentation)	No need to perform mode identification Participant does not need to remember to take GPS on bicycle journeys	Participants can easily forget to charge battery if taking infrequent bicycle trips	√		 	Smartphone GPS—participants solicited for research (20)	Passive user registration—no input required from user, trips detected automatically	Intermodal Can be combined with travel diary (participants can confirm mode/trip purpose)	Mode identification necessary Recruitment more difficult than for active user apps, where participant has more control over the data they record	√√		 		Passive user registration—smartphone based instrumented research bicycle (and pedelec)	Same as for GPS -instrumented research bicycle/pedelec Simpler configuration of instrumentation with smartphone (if only basic sensors used)	Same as for GPS -instrumented research bicycle/pedelec Energy saving required, which reduces data quality	√√√		 		Active user registration (user activates GPS through app)—using or developed from the app “CycleTracks”	Few battery problems Proven method—readily obtainable for other studies User control over data provision (can opt to not record specific journeys)	User must engage with trip to begin, pause and stop recording	√√		 		Active user registration—other customised app specifically designed to provide data for planners/researchers	Backend system allows simple access to necessary user data User control over data provision	User must engage with trip to begin, pause and stop recording App must be developed	√√		 		Active user registration—via recreation-oriented apps	Collating of data can be automated via access tokens No need to develop app User control over data provision	User must engage with trip to begin, pause and stop recording User must upload data in some experimental designs	√		 	Crowdsourcing—data generally not solicited by researchers (13)	Recreational/sports application (smartphone)—data collection not solicited by researchers	Data obtained en masse via some application owners Longitudinal data Detailed data can be volunteered	Sports app users are not representative of general public Data privacy often restricts full access to individual trips	√		 		Customised smartphone application for nationwide data collection (intended for data sharing)	Large dataset Whole country data for comparison	Data privacy often restricts full access to individual trips	√√		 		Volunteered data from previously collected routes (access to existing data solicited by researchers)	Same as for sports applications, but only for volunteered routes User control over data provision	Representativeness Recruitment of GPS users can be difficult	√		 		Instrumented public bikeshare bicycles	Representativeness Large dataset Longitudinal access can be obtained via operators of GPS-enabled bikeshare fleet	Generally limited to GPS only User data may be retained for data privacy reasons	√√		 		Citizen science crowdsourcing platform (Amazon Mechanical Turk)—for smartphone study	Affordable means of obtaining responses with low researcher burden Can sample from global network of users Cannot meet with participants readily	Difficult to be geographically specific (platform users are spread globally)	√√		 	Participant recalled route—hand-drawn (15), web-based (2) or verbal/written description (6)	Hand drawn from interview of participants	Interviewer can ask for clarification (including use of different parts of street) as route is drawn	Accuracy—lack of familiarity with area Limited application beyond usual journey or most recent	√√		 		Hand drawn from mail-back surveys after interception of passers-by	Large numbers of respondents possible Interception not always practical or legal (some jurisdictions classify cyclists in a similar manner to motorised vehicle users)	Relies on map familiarity Limited application beyond usual journey or most recent	√		 		Hand drawn from paper surveys completed on-site (at destination)	Interviewers can assist as required Ease of recruiting large numbers of participants Can tailor map according to destination environment (such as workplace)	Relies on map familiarity Limited application beyond usual journey or most recent	√		 		Hand drawn from printable survey distributed online/advertisements	Large survey distribution possible (through forums, newspapers, noticeboards, bicycle shops etc.)	Relies on map familiarity Limited application beyond usual journey or most recent High participant burden to print survey Map detail vs. size trade-off (whole city is difficult to appropriately represent in map)	√		 		Hand drawn from mental mapping journal (specific target audience)	Longitudinal time frame (multiple journeys, not just most recent or usual) Participant reflection in journal	No map guidance Uncertainty in matching participant-recalled routes to reality	√		 		Mapping Application Programming Interface (API) for online route tracing	Low participant burden—large quantitative datasets possible Routing algorithms can be used to suggest routes for origin-destination Can be integrated with Public Participation Geographic Information System (PPGIS) for obtaining geo-located user feedback	Only limited numbers of routes generally recalled Relies on map familiarity	√√		 		Description using list of road names used	Quick methodology, readily applicable to intercept interviews	Accuracy—recall error/lack of familiarity with road names	√		 		Description using points/landmarks along route (verbal or online)	Quick methodology, readily applicable to intercept interviews	Imprecise—often only two points along route	√		 		Description from detailed interview	Interviewer can ask for clarification Can be map-assisted	Accuracy—lack of familiarity with area	√√		 	Accompanied trip—ride-along (3) or tracking (1)	Ride-along	Experiential ‘sensescapes’ can be captured and discussed real-time Best captures the context of the bicycle user	Transcribing can be difficult (reduced clarity from participants when cycling in addition to noise)	√√√		 		Post ride-along interview	Reasons for choices can be explained Suitable in environments where conversational cycling not practical	Lack of real-time participant reflection compared to ride-along	√√√		 		Unobtrusive tracking from distance	Recruitment not necessary	Lack of ‘participant’ consent Time intensive Difficult to capture journeys originating from homes	√		 	Camera (3)	Egocentric camera on rider/bicycle (commonly used as a supplementary method)	Naturalistic behaviour and interactions can be captured including traffic violations and interactions with other road users	Time intensive for route choice Requires researcher familiarity with area	√√		 	Virtual Reality (VR) (2)	Immersion in virtual/photographed street environment	Proposed changes to built environment can be evaluated in detail Non-cyclists’ revealed preference behaviour can be tested in a safe environment	Modelling time requirement for virtual environment Some participants experience dizziness in VR simulators	√√		 	</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">ijerph-15-00470-t0A2.xml</infon><infon key="id">ijerph-15-00470-t0A2</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_caption</infon><offset>77126</offset><text>Hand-drawn route recall studies.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">ijerph-15-00470-t0A2.xml</infon><infon key="id">ijerph-15-00470-t0A2</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table</infon><infon key="xml">&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;table frame=&quot;hsides&quot; rules=&quot;groups&quot;&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-top:solid thin;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Reference&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-top:solid thin;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Main Field of Application&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-top:solid thin;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Respondents (Valid)&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-top:solid thin;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Type of Route Drawn&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-top:solid thin;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Recruitment Methods&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Lott et al., 1978 &lt;xref rid=&quot;B97-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;97&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Transport planning—before and after evaluation&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;364 cyclists in Davis, USA&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Usual route to downtown or campus (located on the other side of infrastructure)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Interviews of cyclists at their homes before and after the infrastructure development.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Van Maarseveen et al., 1985 &lt;xref rid=&quot;B100-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;100&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Transport planning—before evaluation&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;2194 cyclists in Delft, The Netherlands&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Current journey when intercepted&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Distributed mail-back survey to intercepted cyclists (60% return rate)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Wilmink &amp;amp; Hartman, 1987 &lt;xref rid=&quot;B101-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;101&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Transport planning—before and after network evaluation&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Cyclists in Delft, The Netherlands&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Current journey when intercepted&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Distributed mail-back survey to intercepted cyclists (return rate not stated)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Van Schagen, 1990 &lt;xref rid=&quot;B98-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;98&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Data collection to guide creation of a route choice model&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Cyclists in Groningen, The Netherlands (1012) and Växjö, Sweden (1003)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Current journey when intercepted&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Intercept interview in areas with high cyclist numbers&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Aultman-Hall, 1996 &lt;xref rid=&quot;B103-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;103&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Safety—bicycle routes and accident locations&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Bicycle commuters in Ottawa (1603) and Toronto, Canada (1360)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Current regular bicycle commute&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Mail-back questionnaires attached to the cross-bars of parked bicycles (49% returned)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Aultman-Hall et al., 1997 &lt;xref rid=&quot;B102-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;102&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Transport planning—GIS demonstration&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;338 cyclists in Guelph, Canada&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Commonly used bicycle journeys&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Mail out survey (10% return), distributed mail-back survey to intercepted cyclists and through placement in bicycle shops&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Hyodo et al., 2000 &lt;xref rid=&quot;B108-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;108&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Route choice model—railway station accessibility&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Cyclists in Utsunomiya (502) and Kurume, Japan (252)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Usual bike routes to school or work&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Distributed surveys at high schools, bicycle parking facilities and railway stations&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Howard &amp;amp; Burns, 2001 &lt;xref rid=&quot;B104-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;104&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Transport planning—level of stress&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;150 experienced commuter cyclists in Phoenix, USA&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Last journey to work, not map-assisted&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Printable survey distributed digitally through webpages, email, cycling list server, and advertised/physically distributed at bike shops/community meetings&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Suzuki et al., 2012 &lt;xref rid=&quot;B109-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;109&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Transport planning—traffic volume and bicycle network issues&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1419 cyclists in Takamatsu, Japan&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Written detailed route on map&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Paper survey sent to offices and high schools, interviews in downtown areas&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Manum &amp;amp; Nordström, 2013 &lt;xref rid=&quot;B107-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;107&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Transport planning—bikeability&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Commuter cyclists in Trondheim, Norway&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Route between home and workplace&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Paper survey distributed at three employer hubs in city centre&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Kang &amp;amp; Fricker, 2013 &lt;xref rid=&quot;B99-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;99&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Transport planning—on-street vs. off-street facility use&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;178 cyclists in West Lafayette, USA&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Route to university indicated visually on map (to interviewer)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Intercept interviews at bicycle racks at destination&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Yang &amp;amp; Mesbah, 2013 &lt;xref rid=&quot;B110-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;110&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Stated vs. revealed preference for factors influencing cycling&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;19 cyclists in Brisbane, Australia&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Last cycling trip ending at home&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Pilot study amongst university students and staff&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Manton et al., 2016 &lt;xref rid=&quot;B106-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;106&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Safety—cycling risk (also using stated preference)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;104 cyclists in Galway, Ireland&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Regularly used cycling routes, colour-coded according to perceived risk&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Paper based surveys completed at large university events&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Boettge et al., 2017 &lt;xref rid=&quot;B105-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;105&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Transport planning—cycling risk assessment for siting facilities&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;89 cyclists in St. Louis, USA&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Recently used bicycle route, colour-coded according to perceived risk&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Booths at cycling events allowing participants to complete survey on site&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Gamble, Snizek, &amp;amp; Nielsen, 2017 &lt;xref rid=&quot;B111-ijerph-15-00470&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;111&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Ethnography, understanding cycling activism&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;26 cyclists in Quito, Ecuador&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Freehand mental map of noteworthy recent journeys in journal (not map assisted)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:solid thin&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Specific target audience of cycling activists—who received a disposable camera and journal with prompts&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
</infon><offset>77159</offset><text>Reference	Main Field of Application	Respondents (Valid)	Type of Route Drawn	Recruitment Methods	 	Lott et al., 1978 	Transport planning—before and after evaluation	364 cyclists in Davis, USA	Usual route to downtown or campus (located on the other side of infrastructure)	Interviews of cyclists at their homes before and after the infrastructure development.	 	Van Maarseveen et al., 1985 	Transport planning—before evaluation	2194 cyclists in Delft, The Netherlands	Current journey when intercepted	Distributed mail-back survey to intercepted cyclists (60% return rate)	 	Wilmink &amp; Hartman, 1987 	Transport planning—before and after network evaluation	Cyclists in Delft, The Netherlands	Current journey when intercepted	Distributed mail-back survey to intercepted cyclists (return rate not stated)	 	Van Schagen, 1990 	Data collection to guide creation of a route choice model	Cyclists in Groningen, The Netherlands (1012) and Växjö, Sweden (1003)	Current journey when intercepted	Intercept interview in areas with high cyclist numbers	 	Aultman-Hall, 1996 	Safety—bicycle routes and accident locations	Bicycle commuters in Ottawa (1603) and Toronto, Canada (1360)	Current regular bicycle commute	Mail-back questionnaires attached to the cross-bars of parked bicycles (49% returned)	 	Aultman-Hall et al., 1997 	Transport planning—GIS demonstration	338 cyclists in Guelph, Canada	Commonly used bicycle journeys	Mail out survey (10% return), distributed mail-back survey to intercepted cyclists and through placement in bicycle shops	 	Hyodo et al., 2000 	Route choice model—railway station accessibility	Cyclists in Utsunomiya (502) and Kurume, Japan (252)	Usual bike routes to school or work	Distributed surveys at high schools, bicycle parking facilities and railway stations	 	Howard &amp; Burns, 2001 	Transport planning—level of stress	150 experienced commuter cyclists in Phoenix, USA	Last journey to work, not map-assisted	Printable survey distributed digitally through webpages, email, cycling list server, and advertised/physically distributed at bike shops/community meetings	 	Suzuki et al., 2012 	Transport planning—traffic volume and bicycle network issues	1419 cyclists in Takamatsu, Japan	Written detailed route on map	Paper survey sent to offices and high schools, interviews in downtown areas	 	Manum &amp; Nordström, 2013 	Transport planning—bikeability	Commuter cyclists in Trondheim, Norway	Route between home and workplace	Paper survey distributed at three employer hubs in city centre	 	Kang &amp; Fricker, 2013 	Transport planning—on-street vs. off-street facility use	178 cyclists in West Lafayette, USA	Route to university indicated visually on map (to interviewer)	Intercept interviews at bicycle racks at destination	 	Yang &amp; Mesbah, 2013 	Stated vs. revealed preference for factors influencing cycling	19 cyclists in Brisbane, Australia	Last cycling trip ending at home	Pilot study amongst university students and staff	 	Manton et al., 2016 	Safety—cycling risk (also using stated preference)	104 cyclists in Galway, Ireland	Regularly used cycling routes, colour-coded according to perceived risk	Paper based surveys completed at large university events	 	Boettge et al., 2017 	Transport planning—cycling risk assessment for siting facilities	89 cyclists in St. Louis, USA	Recently used bicycle route, colour-coded according to perceived risk	Booths at cycling events allowing participants to complete survey on site	 	Gamble, Snizek, &amp; Nielsen, 2017 	Ethnography, understanding cycling activism	26 cyclists in Quito, Ecuador	Freehand mental map of noteworthy recent journeys in journal (not map assisted)	Specific target audience of cycling activists—who received a disposable camera and journal with prompts	 	</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">title</infon><offset>80918</offset><text>References</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">43</infon><infon key="lpage">70</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Buehler;given-names:R.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Pucher;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1080/15568311003650531</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Int. J. Sustain. Transp.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">5</infon><infon key="year">2011</infon><offset>80929</offset><text>Sustainable Transport in Freiburg: Lessons from Germany’s Environmental Capital</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1</infon><infon key="lpage">26</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Macmillan;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Connor;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Witten;given-names:K.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Kearns;given-names:R.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Rees;given-names:D.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Woodward;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1289/ehp.1307250</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">24184886</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Environ. Health Perspect.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">122</infon><infon key="year">2014</infon><offset>81011</offset><text>The Societal Costs and Benefits of Commuter Bicycling: Simulating the Effects of Specific Policies Using System Dynamics Modeling</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1109</infon><infon key="lpage">1116</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:De Hartog;given-names:J.J.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Boogaard;given-names:H.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Nijland;given-names:H.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Hoek;given-names:G.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1289/ehp.0901747</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">20587380</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Environ. Health Perspect.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">118</infon><infon key="year">2010</infon><offset>81141</offset><text>Do the health benefits of cycling outweigh the risks?</text></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Ryus;given-names:P.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Ferguson;given-names:E.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Laustsen;given-names:K.M.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Schneider;given-names:R.J.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Proulx;given-names:F.R.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Hull;given-names:T.</infon><infon key="name_6">surname:Miranda-Moreno;given-names:L.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">NCHRP Web-Only Document 205: Methods and Technologies for Pedestrian and Bicycle Volume Data Collection</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">Volume D</infon><infon key="year">2014</infon><offset>81195</offset></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Ryus;given-names:P.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Butsick;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Proulx;given-names:F.R.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Schneider;given-names:R.J.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Hull;given-names:T.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">NCHRP Web-Only Document 229: Methods and Technologies for Pedestrian and Bicycle Volume Data Collection: Phase 2</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>81196</offset></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Nordback;given-names:K.L.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Ph.D. Thesis</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2012</infon><offset>81197</offset><text>Estimating Annual Average Daily Bicyclists and Analyzing Cyclist Safety at Urban Intersections,</text></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Minge;given-names:E.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Falero;given-names:C.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Lindsey;given-names:G.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Petesch;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Vorvick;given-names:T.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Bicycle and Pedestrian Data Collection Manual. Report MN/RC 2017-03</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>81293</offset></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">11</infon><infon key="lpage">18</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Kothuri;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Nordback;given-names:K.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Schrope;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Phillips;given-names:T.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Figliozzi;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.3141/2644-02</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Transp. Res. Rec. J. Transp. Res. Board</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">2644</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>81294</offset><text>Bicycle and Pedestrian Counts at Signalized Intersections Using Existing Infrastructure</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">508</infon><infon key="lpage">515</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Krenn;given-names:P.J.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Titze;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Oja;given-names:P.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Jones;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Ogilvie;given-names:D.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.amepre.2011.06.046</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">22011423</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Am. J. Prev. Med.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">41</infon><infon key="year">2011</infon><offset>81382</offset><text>Use of global positioning systems to study physical activity and the environment: A systematic review</text></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Loveday;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Sherar;given-names:L.B.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Sanders;given-names:J.P.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Sanderson;given-names:P.W.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Esliger;given-names:D.W.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.2196/jmir.4761</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">26245157</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J. Med. Internet Res.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">17</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>81484</offset><text>Technologies that assess the location of physical activity and sedentary behavior: A systematic review</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1</infon><infon key="lpage">19</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Buehler;given-names:R.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Dill;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1080/01441647.2015.1069908</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Transp. Rev.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">1647</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>81587</offset><text>Bikeway Networks: A Review of Effects on Cycling</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">114</infon><infon key="lpage">133</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Romanillos;given-names:G.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Zaltz Austwick;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Ettema;given-names:D.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:De Kruijf;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1080/01441647.2015.1084067</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Transp. Rev.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">36</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>81636</offset><text>Big Data and Cycling</text></passage><passage><infon key="elocation-id">e1000097</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Moher;given-names:D.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Liberati;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Tetzlaff;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Altman;given-names:D.G.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Altman;given-names:D.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Antes;given-names:G.</infon><infon key="name_6">surname:Atkins;given-names:D.</infon><infon key="name_7">surname:Barbour;given-names:V.</infon><infon key="name_8">surname:Barrowman;given-names:N.</infon><infon key="name_9">surname:Berlin;given-names:J.A.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1371/journal.pmed.1000097</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">19621072</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">PLoS Med.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">6</infon><infon key="year">2009</infon><offset>81657</offset><text>Preferred reporting items for systematic reviews and meta-analyses: The PRISMA statement</text></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Lindsey;given-names:G.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Hankey;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Wang;given-names:X.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Chen;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Gorjestani;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Feasibility of Using GPS to Track Bicycle Lane Positioning. Report CTS 13-16</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2013</infon><offset>81746</offset></passage><passage><infon key="elocation-id">190</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Lopez;given-names:A.J.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Astegiano;given-names:P.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Gautama;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Ochoa;given-names:D.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Tampère;given-names:C.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Beckx;given-names:C.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.3390/ijgi6070190</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">ISPRS Int. J. Geo-Informat.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">6</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>81747</offset><text>Unveiling E-Bike Potential for Commuting Trips from GPS Traces</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">217</infon><infon key="lpage">226</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Dozza;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Bianchi Piccinini;given-names:G.F.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Werneke;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.trf.2015.04.003</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Transp. Res. Part F Traffic Psychol. Behav.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">41</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>81810</offset><text>Using naturalistic data to assess e-cyclist behavior</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">127</infon><infon key="lpage">137</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Garcia;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Gomez;given-names:F.A.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Llorca;given-names:C.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Angel-Domenech;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.aap.2015.02.019</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">25779982</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Accid. Anal. Prev.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">78</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>81863</offset><text>Effect of width and boundary conditions on meeting maneuvers on two-way separated cycle tracks</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">25</infon><infon key="lpage">34</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Plazier;given-names:P.A.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Weitkamp;given-names:G.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Berg;given-names:A.E.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.jtrangeo.2017.09.017</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J. Transp. Geogr.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">65</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>81958</offset><text>Van Den “Cycling was never so easy!” An analysis of e-bike commuters’ motives, travel behaviour and experiences using GPS-tracking and interviews</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">948</infon><infon key="lpage">965</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Pooley;given-names:C.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Whyatt;given-names:D.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Walker;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Davies;given-names:G.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Coulton;given-names:P.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Bamford;given-names:W.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1068/a41405</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Environ. Plan. A</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">42</infon><infon key="year">2010</infon><offset>82110</offset><text>Understanding the school journey: Integrating data on travel and environment</text></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Dill;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Gliebe;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Understanding and Measuring Bicycling Behavior: A Focus on Travel Time and Route Choice. Report OTREC-RR-08-03</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2008</infon><offset>82187</offset></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Harvey;given-names:F.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Krizek;given-names:K.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Commuter Bicyclist Behavior and Facility Disruption. Report MN/RC-2007-15</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2007</infon><offset>82188</offset></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1</infon><infon key="lpage">4</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Paefgen;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Michahelles;given-names:F.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Boll;given-names:s.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Schöning;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Proceedings of the 3rd International Workshop on Location and the Web—LocWeb ’10;</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2010</infon><offset>82189</offset><text>Inferring usage characteristics of electric bicycles from position information</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1647</infon><infon key="lpage">1657</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Ioakimidis;given-names:C.S.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Rycerski;given-names:P.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Koutra;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Genikomsakis;given-names:K.N.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">EVS29 International Battery, Hybrid and Fuel Cell Electric Vehicle Symposium</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>82268</offset><text>A university e-bike sharing system used as a real-time monitoring emissions tool under a smart city concept</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">201</infon><infon key="lpage">217</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Allemann;given-names:D.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Raubal;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Bacao;given-names:F.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Santos;given-names:M.Y.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Painho;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">AGILE 2015, Geographic Information Science as an Enabler of Smarter Cities and Communities</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">Volume 217</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>82376</offset><text>Usage Differences between Bikes and E-Bikes</text></passage><passage><infon key="comment">Report TRCLC15-01</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Oh;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Kwigizile;given-names:V.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Ro;given-names:K.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Feizi;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Kostich;given-names:W.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Abdullah;given-names:R.</infon><infon key="name_6">surname:Hasan;given-names:H.</infon><infon key="name_7">surname:Mousa;given-names:F.A.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Effect of Cycling Skills on Bicycle Safety and Comfort Associated with Bicycle Infrastructure and Environment</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>82420</offset></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">3339</infon><infon key="lpage">3344</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Lai;given-names:C.H.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Doong;given-names:J.L.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Chuang;given-names:K.H.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Hsu;given-names:C.C.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.promfg.2015.07.492</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Procedia Manuf.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">3</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>82421</offset><text>The Likelihoods of Bicyclist Steering Patterns in Response to Being Passed by Motorists</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">55</infon><infon key="lpage">64</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Kircher;given-names:K.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Ahlstrom;given-names:C.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Palmqvist;given-names:L.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Adell;given-names:E.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.trf.2014.11.006</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Transp. Res. Part F Traffic Psychol. Behav.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">28</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>82509</offset><text>Bicyclists’ speed adaptation strategies when conducting self-paced vs. system-paced smartphone tasks in traffic</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">7</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Berntsen;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Malnes;given-names:L.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Langåker;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Bere;given-names:E.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1186/s12966-017-0513-z</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">28103935</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Int. J. Behav. Nutr. Phys. Act.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">14</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>82623</offset><text>Physical activity when riding an electric assisted bicycle</text></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Shin;given-names:D.K.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Ph.D. Thesis</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>82682</offset><text>Explanation of Factors Influencing Cyclists’ Route Choice Using Actual Route Data from Cyclists</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">2619</infon><infon key="lpage">2624</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Jahangiri;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Elhenawy;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Rakha;given-names:H.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Dingus;given-names:T.A.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Proceedings of the 2016 IEEE 19th International Conference on Intelligent Transportation Systems (ITSC)</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>82780</offset><text>Investigating cyclist violations at signal-controlled intersections using naturalistic cycling data</text></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Lin;given-names:P.-S.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Kourtellis;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Katkoori;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Chen;given-names:C.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Cruse;given-names:L.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Naturalistic Bicycling Behavior Pilot Study. Report BDV25-977-13</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>82880</offset></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">32</infon><infon key="lpage">41</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Chuang;given-names:K.H.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Hsu;given-names:C.C.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Lai;given-names:C.H.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Doong;given-names:J.L.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Jeng;given-names:M.C.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.aap.2013.03.029</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">23587736</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Accid. Anal. Prev.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">56</infon><infon key="year">2013</infon><offset>82881</offset><text>The use of a quasi-naturalistic riding method to investigate bicyclists’ behaviors when motorists pass</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">14</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Jarjour;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Jerrett;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Westerdahl;given-names:D.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:de Nazelle;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Hanning;given-names:C.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Daly;given-names:L.</infon><infon key="name_6">surname:Lipsitt;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_7">surname:Balmes;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1186/1476-069X-12-14</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">23391029</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Environ. Health</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">12</infon><infon key="year">2013</infon><offset>82986</offset><text>Cyclist route choice, traffic-related air pollution, and lung function: A scripted exposure study</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">376</infon><infon key="lpage">384</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Dozza;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Fernandez;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1109/TITS.2013.2279687</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">IEEE Trans. Intell. Transp. Syst.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">15</infon><infon key="year">2014</infon><offset>83084</offset><text>Understanding bicycle dynamics and cyclist behavior from naturalistic field data (November 2012)</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">13</infon><infon key="lpage">23</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Bigazzi;given-names:A.Y.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Figliozzi;given-names:M.A.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.trd.2015.09.008</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Transp. Res. Part D Transp. Environ.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">41</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>83181</offset><text>Roadway determinants of bicyclist exposure to volatile organic compounds and carbon monoxide</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1</infon><infon key="lpage">8</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Etemad;given-names:H.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Costello;given-names:S.B.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Wilson;given-names:D.J.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">IPENZ Transport Group Conference</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>83274</offset><text>Using an instrumented bicycle to help understand cyclists’ perception of risk</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">28</infon><infon key="lpage">43</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Kovácsová;given-names:N.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:de Winter;given-names:J.C.F.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Schwab;given-names:A.L.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Christoph;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Twisk;given-names:D.A.M.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Hagenzieker;given-names:M.P.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.trf.2016.06.018</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Transp. Res. Part F Traffic Psychol. Behav.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">42</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>83354</offset><text>Riding performance on a conventional bicycle and a pedelec in low speed exercises: Objective and subjective evaluation of middle-aged and older persons</text></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Cole-Hunter;given-names:T.A.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Ph.D. Thesis</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2012</infon><offset>83506</offset><text>Effects of Air Pollution Exposure on Adult Bicycle Commuters: An Investigation of Respiratory Health, Motorised Traffic Proximity and the Utility of Commute Re-Routing,</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">286</infon><infon key="lpage">298</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Gustafsson;given-names:L.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Archer;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.aap.2012.06.004</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">22795396</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Accid. Anal. Prev.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">58</infon><infon key="year">2013</infon><offset>83675</offset><text>A naturalistic study of commuter cyclists in the greater Stockholm area</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">415</infon><infon key="lpage">425</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Bíl;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Andrášik;given-names:R.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Kubeček;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.trc.2015.05.007</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Transp. Res. Part C Emerg. Technol.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">56</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>83747</offset><text>How comfortable are your cycling tracks? A new method for objective bicycle vibration measurement</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">335</infon><infon key="lpage">341</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Parkin;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Rotheram;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.tranpol.2010.03.001</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Transp. Policy</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">17</infon><infon key="year">2010</infon><offset>83845</offset><text>Design speeds and acceleration characteristics of bicycle traffic for use in planning, design and appraisal</text></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Gelhert;given-names:T.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Traffic Safety of Electric Bicycles</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2014</infon><offset>83953</offset></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">220</infon><infon key="lpage">226</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Langford;given-names:B.C.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Chen;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Cherry;given-names:C.R.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.aap.2015.05.016</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">26093098</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Accid. Anal. Prev.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">82</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>83954</offset><text>Risky riding: Naturalistic methods comparing safety behavior from conventional bicycle riders and electric bike riders</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">12</infon><infon key="lpage">21</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Wergin;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Buehler;given-names:R.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.3141/2662-02</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Transp. Res. Rec. J. Transp. Res. Board</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">2662</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>84073</offset><text>Where Do Bikeshare Bikes Actually Go?</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">141</infon><infon key="lpage">149</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Khatri;given-names:R.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Cherry;given-names:C.R.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Nambisan;given-names:S.S.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Han;given-names:L.D.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.3141/2587-17</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Transp. Res. Rec. J. Transp. Res. Board</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">2587</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>84111</offset><text>Modeling Route Choice of Utilitarian Bikeshare Users with GPS Data</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">397</infon><infon key="lpage">404</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Good;given-names:N.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Mölter;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Ackerson;given-names:C.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Bachand;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Carpenter;given-names:T.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Clark;given-names:M.L.</infon><infon key="name_6">surname:Fedak;given-names:K.M.</infon><infon key="name_7">surname:Kayne;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_8">surname:Koehler;given-names:K.</infon><infon key="name_9">surname:Moore;given-names:B.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1038/jes.2015.68</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">26507004</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J. Expo. Sci. Environ. Epidemiol.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">26</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>84178</offset><text>The Fort Collins Commuter Study: Impact of route type and transport mode on personal exposure to multiple air pollutants</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">S74</infon><infon key="lpage">S78</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Dill;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:McNeil;given-names:N.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Broach;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Ma;given-names:L.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.ypmed.2014.10.006</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">25456802</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Prev. Med.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">69</infon><infon key="year">2014</infon><offset>84299</offset><text>Bicycle boulevards and changes in physical activity and active transportation: Findings from a natural experiment</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">357</infon><infon key="lpage">365</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Brown;given-names:B.B.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Tharp;given-names:D.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Tribby;given-names:C.P.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Smith;given-names:K.R.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Miller;given-names:H.J.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Werner;given-names:C.M.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.jth.2016.04.001</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">27672561</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J. Transp. Health</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">3</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>84413</offset><text>Changes in bicycling over time associated with a new bike lane: Relations with kilocalories energy expenditure and body mass index</text></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Johnson;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Chong;given-names:D.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Carroll;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Katz;given-names:R.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Oxley;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Charlton;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Naturalistic Cycling Study: Identifying Risk Factors for Cyclists in the Australian Capital Territory. Report 322</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2014</infon><offset>84544</offset></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1</infon><infon key="lpage">15</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Hamann;given-names:C.J.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Pooley;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:McGehee;given-names:D.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Peek-Asa;given-names:C.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Proceedings of the International Cycling Safety Conference;</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>84545</offset><text>A naturalistic study of child and adult bicycling behaviours and risk exposure</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">91</infon><infon key="lpage">99</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Hatfield;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Dozza;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Patton;given-names:D.A.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Maharaj;given-names:P.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Boufous;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Eveston;given-names:T.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.aap.2017.08.025</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">28865315</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Accid. Anal. Prev.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">108</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>84624</offset><text>On the use of naturalistic methods to examine safety-relevant behaviours amongst children and evaluate a cycling education program</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">14</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Casello;given-names:J.M.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Rewa;given-names:K.C.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Nour;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Proceedings of the Transportation Research Board 91st Annual Meeting</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>84755</offset><text>An Analysis of Empirical Evidence of Cyclists’ Route Choice and Its Implications for Planning</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1</infon><infon key="lpage">18</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Casello;given-names:J.M.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Nour;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Rewa;given-names:K.C.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Hill;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Proceedings of the Transportation Research Board 90th Annual Meeting</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>84851</offset><text>Analysis of Stated-Preference and GPS Data for Bicycle Travel Forecasting</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1</infon><infon key="lpage">19</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Wati;given-names:K.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Burke;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Sipe;given-names:N.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Dodson;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Australasian Transport Research Forum</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2013</infon><offset>84925</offset><text>Children’s cycling trends, accessibility to and utilisation of urban facilities in selected Australian urban environments</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">7</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Krenn;given-names:P.J.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Oja;given-names:P.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Titze;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1186/1479-5868-11-31</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">24457004</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Int. J. Behav. Nutr. Phys. Act.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">11</infon><infon key="year">2014</infon><offset>85049</offset><text>Route choices of transport bicyclists: A comparison of actually used and shortest routes</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">11</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Dessing;given-names:D.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:de Vries;given-names:S.I.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Hegeman;given-names:G.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Verhagen;given-names:E.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:van Mechelen;given-names:W.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Pierik;given-names:F.H.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1186/s12966-016-0373-y</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">26821926</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Int. J. Behav. Nutr. Phys. Act.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">13</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>85138</offset><text>Children’s route choice during active transportation to school: difference between shortest and actual route</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">754</infon><infon key="lpage">765</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Menghini;given-names:G.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Carrasco;given-names:N.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Schüssler;given-names:N.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Axhausen;given-names:K.W.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.tra.2010.07.008</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Transp. Res. Part A Policy Pract.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">44</infon><infon key="year">2010</infon><offset>85249</offset><text>Route choice of cyclists in Zurich</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">219</infon><infon key="lpage">229</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Dalton;given-names:A.M.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Jones;given-names:A.P.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Panter;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Ogilvie;given-names:D.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.jth.2014.10.001</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">26682132</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J. Transp. Health</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">2</infon><infon key="year">2014</infon><offset>85284</offset><text>Are GIS-modelled routes a useful proxy for the actual routes followed by commuters?</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">189</infon><infon key="lpage">210</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Yeboah;given-names:G.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Alvanides;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Jokar Arsanjani;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Zipf;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Mooney;given-names:P.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Helbich;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">OpenStreetMap in GIScience</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>85368</offset><text>Route Choice Analysis of Urban Cycling Behaviors Using OpenStreetMap: Evidence from a British Urban Environment</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">63</infon><infon key="lpage">69</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Apparicio;given-names:P.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Carrier;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Gelb;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Séguin;given-names:A.M.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Kingham;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.jtrangeo.2016.09.014</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J. Transp. Geogr.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">57</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>85480</offset><text>Cyclists’ exposure to air pollution and road traffic noise in central city neighbourhoods of Montreal</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1</infon><infon key="lpage">14</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Montini;given-names:L.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Antoniou;given-names:C.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Axhausen;given-names:K.W.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Proceedings of the Transportation Research Board 96th Annual Meeting</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>85584</offset><text>Route and Mode Choice Models Using GPS Data</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1</infon><infon key="lpage">17</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Luo;given-names:D.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Ma;given-names:X.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Proceedings of the 3rd International Cycling Safety Conference</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>85628</offset><text>Analysis of Cyclist Behavior Using Naturalistic Data: Data Processing for Model Development</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">125</infon><infon key="lpage">134</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Wolf;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Guensler;given-names:R.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Bachman;given-names:W.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.3141/1768-15</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Transp. Res. Rec. J. Transp. Res. Board</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">1768</infon><infon key="year">2001</infon><offset>85720</offset><text>Elimination of the Travel Diary: Experiment to Derive Trip Purpose from Global Positioning System Travel Data</text></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Wolf;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Proceedings of the International Conference on Transport Survey Quality and Innovation</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>85830</offset><text>Application of New Technologies in Travel Surveys</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">449</infon><infon key="lpage">466</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Doherty;given-names:S.T.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Noël;given-names:N.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Gosselin;given-names:M.-L.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Sirois;given-names:C.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Ueno;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Murakami;given-names:E.</infon><infon key="name_6">surname:Pisarski;given-names:A.E.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">TRB Transportation Research Circular—Personal Travel. The Long and Short of It</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">1999</infon><offset>85880</offset><text>Moving Beyond Observed Outcomes: Integrating Global Positioning Systems and Interactive Computer-Based Travel Behavior Surveys</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">6</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Sandsjö;given-names:L.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Sjöqvist;given-names:B.A.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Candefjord;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Proceedings of the International Technical Conference on the Enhanced Safety of Vehicles (ESV)</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>86007</offset><text>A Concept for Naturalistic Data Collection for Vulnerable Road Users Using a Smartphone-Based Platform</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">79</infon><infon key="lpage">88</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Kiefer;given-names:C.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Behrendt;given-names:F.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1049/iet-its.2014.0251</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">IET Intell. Transp. Syst.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">10</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>86110</offset><text>Smart e-bike monitoring system: real-time open source and open hardware GPS assistance and sensor data for electrically-assisted bicycles</text></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Liu;given-names:F.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Figliozzi;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Caviedes;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Le;given-names:H.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Mai;given-names:L.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Utilizing Egocentric Video and Sensors to Conduct Naturalistic Bicycling Studies. Report NITC-RR-805</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>86248</offset></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Watkins;given-names:K.E.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:LeDantec;given-names:C.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Using Crowdsourcing to Prioritize Bicycle Route Network Improvements. Report FHWA-GA-16-1439</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>86249</offset></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1</infon><infon key="lpage">6</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Rios;given-names:I.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Golab;given-names:L.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Keshav;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Proceedings of the Workshop on Electric Vehicle Systems, Data, and Applications—EV-SYS ’16</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>86250</offset><text>Analyzing the usage patterns of electric bicycles</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1218</infon><infon key="lpage">1226</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Romanillos;given-names:G.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Zaltz Austwick;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1080/17445647.2015.1088901</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J. Maps</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">12</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>86300</offset><text>Madrid cycle track: Visualizing the cyclable city</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1265</infon><infon key="lpage">1276</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Gonzalez;given-names:P.A.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Weinstein;given-names:J.S.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Barbeau;given-names:S.J.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Labrador;given-names:M.A.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Winters;given-names:P.L.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Georggi;given-names:N.L.</infon><infon key="name_6">surname:Perez;given-names:R.A.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Proceedings of the 15th World Congress on Intelligent Transport Systems</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>86350</offset><text>Automating Mode Detection Using Neural Networks and Assisted GPS Data Collected Using GPS-Enabled Mobile Phones</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">16</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Nour;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Casello;given-names:J.M.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Hellinga;given-names:B.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Proceedings of the Transportation Research Board 94th Annual Meeting</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>86462</offset><text>Developing and Optimizing a Transportation Mode Inference Model Utilizing Data from GPS Embedded Smartphones</text></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Saleh;given-names:P.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Otte;given-names:D.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Krettek;given-names:C.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">E-bicycles—Bicycles or mopeds? Overview about the project “SEEKING—SAFE E-BIKING.” In International Conference on ESAR “Expert Symposium on Accident Research”</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2014</infon><offset>86571</offset></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1</infon><infon key="lpage">10</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Charlton;given-names:B.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Sall;given-names:E.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Schwartz;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Hood;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Proceedings of The Transportation Research Board 90th Annual Meeting</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>86572</offset><text>Bicycle Route Choice Data Collection using GPS-Enabled Smartphones</text></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Hudson;given-names:J.G.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Duthie;given-names:J.C.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Rathod;given-names:Y.K.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Larsen;given-names:K.A.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Meyer;given-names:J.L.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Using Smartphones to Collect Bicycle Travel Data in Texas. DOT Grant No. DTRT06-G-0044</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2012</infon><offset>86639</offset></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1</infon><infon key="lpage">14</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Chen;given-names:P.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Shen;given-names:Q.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Childress;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1080/15568318.2017.1349222</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Int. J. Sustain. Transp.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>86640</offset><text>A GPS data-based analysis of built environment influences on bicyclist route preferences</text></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Akar;given-names:G.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Park;given-names:Y.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Tracking Bicyclists’ Route Choices, Case Study: The Ohio State University. NEXTRANS Project No. 171OSUY2.2</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>86729</offset></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Figliozzi;given-names:M.A.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Blanc;given-names:B.P.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Evaluating the Use of Crowdsourcing as a Data Collection Method for Bicycle Performance Measures and Identification of Facility Improvement Needs. Report SPR 768</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>86730</offset></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">183</infon><infon key="lpage">196</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Zimmermann;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Mai;given-names:T.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Frejinger;given-names:E.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.trc.2016.12.009</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Transp. Res. Part C Emerg. Technol.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">75</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>86731</offset><text>Bike route choice modeling using GPS data without choice sets of paths</text></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Li;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Muresan;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Fu;given-names:L.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Proceedings of the Transportation Research Board 96th Annual Meeting</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>86802</offset><text>Cycling in Toronto: Route Choice Behaviour and Implications to Infrastructure Planning</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">155</infon><infon key="lpage">171</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Strauss;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Miranda-Moreno;given-names:L.F.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.trd.2017.09.001</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Transp. Res. Part D Transp. Environ.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">57</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>86889</offset><text>Speed, travel time and delay for intersections and road segments in the Montreal network using cyclist Smartphone GPS data</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1</infon><infon key="lpage">4</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Torres;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Lalanne;given-names:F.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:del Canto;given-names:G.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Morales;given-names:F.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Bustos-Jimenez;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Reyes;given-names:P.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Proceedings of the 34th International Conference of the Chilean Computer Science Society (SCCC)</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>87012</offset><text>BeCity: Sensing and sensibility on urban cycling for smarter cities</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1379</infon><infon key="lpage">1394</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Manum;given-names:B.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Nordström;given-names:T.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Gil;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Nilsson;given-names:L.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Marcus;given-names:L.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Proceedings of the 11th International Space Syntax Symposium;</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>87080</offset><text>Modelling bikeability; Space syntax based measures applied in examining speeds and flows of bicycling in Gothenburg</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1</infon><infon key="lpage">26</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Crockett;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:O’Hare;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Barritt;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Gordon;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Inayathusein;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Forrest;given-names:R.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">European Transport Conference</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>87196</offset><text>In the Peleton or in the Break—Factors Affecting Cyclists Route Choice in London</text></passage><passage><infon key="elocation-id">274</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Sun;given-names:Y.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Mobasheri;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.3390/ijerph14030274</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">28282865</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Int. J. Environ. Res. Public Health</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">14</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>87279</offset><text>Utilizing Crowdsourced Data for Studies of Cycling and Air Pollution Exposure: A Case Study Using Strava Data</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">10</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Norman;given-names:G.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Kesha;given-names:N.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Institution of Professional Engineers New Zealand (IPENZ) Transportation Conference</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>87389</offset><text>Using smartphones for cycle planning</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">898</infon><infon key="lpage">905</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Musakwa;given-names:W.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Selala;given-names:K.M.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.dib.2016.11.002</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">27872887</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Data Br.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">9</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>87426</offset><text>Mapping cycling patterns and trends using Strava Metro data in the city of Johannesburg, South Africa</text></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Bergman;given-names:C.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Oksanen;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1111/tgis.12192</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Trans. GIS</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>87528</offset><text>Conflation of OpenStreetMap and Mobile Sports Tracking Data for Automatic Bicycle Routing</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">244</infon><infon key="lpage">250</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Schweizer;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Bernardi;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Rupi;given-names:F.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1049/iet-its.2015.0135</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">IET Intell. Transp. Syst.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">10</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>87618</offset><text>Map-matching algorithm applied to bicycle global positioning system traces in Bologna</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">422</infon><infon key="lpage">435</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Baker;given-names:K.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Ooms;given-names:K.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Verstockt;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Brackman;given-names:P.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:De Maeyer;given-names:P.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Van de Walle;given-names:R.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1080/15230406.2016.1192486</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Cartogr. Geogr. Inf. Sci.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">44</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>87704</offset><text>Crowdsourcing a cyclist perspective on suggested recreational paths in real-world networks</text></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Leao;given-names:S.Z.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Pettit;given-names:C.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Namazi-Rad;given-names:M.-R.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Padgham;given-names:L.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Perez;given-names:P.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Nagel;given-names:K.</infon><infon key="name_6">surname:Bazzan;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Lecture Notes in Computer Science</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">Volume 10051</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>87795</offset><text>Agent Based Modelling of Urban Systems</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">75</infon><infon key="lpage">82</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Ton;given-names:D.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Cats;given-names:O.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Duives;given-names:D.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Hoogendoorn;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.3141/2662-09</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Transp. Res. Rec. J. Transp. Res. Board</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">2662</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>87834</offset><text>How Do People Cycle in Amsterdam? Estimating cyclists’ route choice determinants using GPS data from an urban area</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1</infon><infon key="lpage">17</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Bussche;given-names:D.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Van de Coevering;given-names:P.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">European Transport Conference</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>87951</offset><text>BikePRINT—In Depth Analysis of Cyclist Behaviour and Cycle Network Performance Using Extensive Gps-Track Data</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">383</infon><infon key="lpage">386</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Lee;given-names:D.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Park;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Hahn;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Proceedings of the 2014 IEEE Asia Pacific Conference on Circuits and Systems (APCCAS)</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2014</infon><offset>88063</offset><text>A study on bicycle crash risk based on GPS trajectories collected from bidirectional traffic</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">378</infon><infon key="lpage">382</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Assemi;given-names:B.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Schlagwein;given-names:D.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Safi;given-names:H.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Mesbah;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Wirtz;given-names:G.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Townend;given-names:P.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">2015 IEEE Symposium on Service-Oriented System Engineering</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">Volume 30</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>88156</offset><text>Crowdsourcing as a Method for the Collection of Revealed Preferences Data</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">40</infon><infon key="lpage">46</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Lott;given-names:D.F.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Tardiff;given-names:T.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Lott;given-names:D.Y.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Transp. Res. Rec. J. Transp. Res. Board</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">683</infon><infon key="year">1978</infon><offset>88230</offset><text>Evaluation by experienced riders of a new bicycle lane in an Established Bikeway System</text></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Van Schagen;given-names:I.N.L.G.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Pedestrians and Pedal Cyclists in a British, Dutch and Swedish Modelling Area</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">1990</infon><offset>88318</offset></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">887</infon><infon key="lpage">902</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Kang;given-names:L.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Fricker;given-names:J.D.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1007/s11116-013-9453-x</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Transportation</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">40</infon><infon key="year">2013</infon><offset>88319</offset><text>Bicyclist commuters’ choice of on-street versus off-street route segments</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">15</infon><infon key="lpage">23</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Van Maarseveen;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Jansen;given-names:G.R.M.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Bovy;given-names:P.H.L.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Transp. Res. Rec. J. Transp. Res. Board</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">1045</infon><infon key="year">1985</infon><offset>88395</offset><text>Estimating OD Tables Using Empirical Route-Choice Information with Application to Bicycle Traffic</text></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Wilmink;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Hartman;given-names:J.B.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Evaluation of the Delft Bicycle Network Plan. Final Summary Report</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">1987</infon><offset>88493</offset></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">102</infon><infon key="lpage">110</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Aultman-Hall;given-names:L.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Hall;given-names:F.L.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Baetz;given-names:B.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.3141/1578-13</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Transp. Res. Rec. J. Transp. Res. Board</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">1578</infon><infon key="year">1997</infon><offset>88494</offset><text>Analysis of bicycle commuter routes using geographic information systems: implications for bicycle planning</text></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Aultman-Hall;given-names:L.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Ph.D. Thesis</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">1996</infon><offset>88602</offset><text>Commuter Bicycle Route Choice: Analysis of Major Determinants and Safety Implications,</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">39</infon><infon key="lpage">46</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Howard;given-names:C.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Burns;given-names:E.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.3141/1773-05</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Transp. Res. Rec. J. Transp. Res. Board</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">1773</infon><infon key="year">2001</infon><offset>88689</offset><text>Cycling to Work in Phoenix: Route Choice, Travel Behavior, and Commuter Characteristics</text></passage><passage><infon key="elocation-id">241</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Boettge;given-names:B.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Hall;given-names:D.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Crawford;given-names:T.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.3390/su9020241</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Sustainability</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">9</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>88777</offset><text>Assessing the Bicycle Network in St. Louis: A PlaceBased User-Centered Approach</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">138</infon><infon key="lpage">149</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Manton;given-names:R.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Rau;given-names:H.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Fahy;given-names:F.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Sheahan;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Clifford;given-names:E.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.aap.2015.12.017</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">26760689</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Accid. Anal. Prev.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">88</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>88857</offset><text>Using mental mapping to unpack perceived cycling risk</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">14</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Manum;given-names:B.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Nordström;given-names:T.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Kim;given-names:Y.O.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Park;given-names:H.T.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">International Space Syntax Symposium</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2013</infon><offset>88911</offset><text>Integrating Bicycle Network Analysis in Urban Design: Improving bikeability in Trondheim by combining space syntax and GIS-methods using the place syntax tool</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">70</infon><infon key="lpage">76</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Hyodo;given-names:T.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Suzuki;given-names:N.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Takahashi;given-names:K.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.3141/1705-11</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Transp. Res. Rec. J. Transp. Res. Board</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">1705</infon><infon key="year">2000</infon><offset>89070</offset><text>Modeling of Bicycle Route and Destination Choice Behavior for Bicycle Road Network Plan</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">558</infon><infon key="lpage">570</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Suzuki;given-names:K.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Kanda;given-names:Y.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Doi;given-names:K.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Tsuchizaki;given-names:N.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.sbspro.2012.04.129</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Procedia Soc. Behav. Sci.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">43</infon><infon key="year">2012</infon><offset>89158</offset><text>Proposal and Application of a New Method for Bicycle Network Planning</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1</infon><infon key="lpage">17</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Yang;given-names:C.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Mesbah;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Bunker;given-names:J.M.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Burke;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Australasian Transport Research Forum</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2013</infon><offset>89228</offset><text>Route Choice Behaviour of Cyclists by Stated Preference and Revealed Preference</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">167</infon><infon key="lpage">177</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Gamble;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Snizek;given-names:B.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Nielsen;given-names:T.S.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.jtrangeo.2017.03.004</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J. Transp. Geogr.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">60</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>89308</offset><text>From people to cycling indicators: Documenting and understanding the urban context of cyclists’ experiences in Quito, Ecuador</text></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Wang;given-names:J.Y.T.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Mirza;given-names:L.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Cheung;given-names:A.K.L.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Moradi;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Hughes;given-names:B.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Petkoff;given-names:I.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Australasian Transport Research Forum</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2012</infon><offset>89436</offset><text>Transforming Auckland into a bicycle-friendly city: Understanding factors influencing choices of cyclists and potential cyclists</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">227</infon><infon key="lpage">233</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Snizek;given-names:B.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Sick Nielsen;given-names:T.A.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Skov-Petersen;given-names:H.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.jtrangeo.2013.02.001</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J. Transp. Geogr.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">30</infon><infon key="year">2013</infon><offset>89565</offset><text>Mapping bicyclists’ experiences in Copenhagen</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">484</infon><infon key="lpage">487</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Kobas;given-names:G.V.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Drury;given-names:C.G.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1177/154193127602002102</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Hum. Factors Ergon. Soc. Annu. Meet.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">20</infon><infon key="year">1976</infon><offset>89613</offset><text>The Bicyclist’s Exposure to Risk</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">611</infon><infon key="lpage">624</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Krizek;given-names:K.J.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:El-Geneidy;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Thompson;given-names:K.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1007/s11116-007-9130-z</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Transportation</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">34</infon><infon key="year">2007</infon><offset>89648</offset><text>A detailed analysis of how an urban trail system affects cyclists’ travel</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">172</infon><infon key="lpage">177</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Larsen;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:El-Geneidy;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.trd.2010.07.011</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Transp. Res. Part D Transp. Environ.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">16</infon><infon key="year">2011</infon><offset>89724</offset><text>A travel behavior analysis of urban cycling facilities in Montréal, Canada</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">255</infon><infon key="lpage">266</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Standen;given-names:C.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Crane;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Collins;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Greaves;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Rissel;given-names:C.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.jth.2016.10.004</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J. Transp. Health</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">4</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>89800</offset><text>Determinants of mode and route change following the opening of a new cycleway in Sydney, Australia</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1</infon><infon key="lpage">10</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Winters;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Teschke;given-names:K.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Grant;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Setton;given-names:E.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Brauer;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.3141/2190-01</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Transp. Res. Rec. J. Transp. Res. Board</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">2190</infon><infon key="year">2010</infon><offset>89899</offset><text>How Far Out of the Way Will We Travel?</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">407</infon><infon key="lpage">423</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:González;given-names:F.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Melo-Riquelme;given-names:C.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:de Grange;given-names:L.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1007/s11116-015-9581-6</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Transportation</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">43</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>89938</offset><text>A combined destination and route choice model for a bicycle sharing system</text></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Salmon;given-names:R.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Chinnock;given-names:C.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Duckenfield;given-names:T.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Cycle Route Choice. Final Survey and Model Report</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2012</infon><offset>90013</offset></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">234</infon><infon key="lpage">243</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Van Duppen;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Spierings;given-names:B.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.jtrangeo.2013.02.006</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J. Transp. Geogr.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">30</infon><infon key="year">2013</infon><offset>90014</offset><text>Retracing trajectories: The embodied experience of cycling, urban sensescapes and the commute between “neighbourhood” and “city” in Utrecht, NL</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">328</infon><infon key="lpage">336</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Barratt;given-names:P.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.healthplace.2016.09.009</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">28029434</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Health Place</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">46</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>90166</offset><text>Healthy competition: A qualitative study investigating persuasive technologies and the gamification of cycling</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">17</infon><infon key="lpage">22</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Zacharias;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Zhang;given-names:R.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.3141/2587-03</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Transp. Res. Rec. J. Transp. Res. Board</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">2587</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>90277</offset><text>Revealed Bicyclist Route Preferences and Street Conditions</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">426</infon><infon key="lpage">447</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Simpson;given-names:P.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1177/0308518X16669510</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Environ. Plan. A</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">49</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>90336</offset><text>A sense of the cycling environment: Felt experiences of infrastructure and atmospheres</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">275</infon><infon key="lpage">283</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Johnson;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Charlton;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Oxley;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Newstead;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">21050610</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Ann. Adv. Automot. Med.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">54</infon><infon key="year">2010</infon><offset>90423</offset><text>Naturalistic cycling study: Identifying risk factors for on-road commuter cyclists</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">307</infon><infon key="lpage">316</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Stewart;given-names:K.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:McHale;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.3846/16484142.2014.953205</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Transport</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">29</infon><infon key="year">2014</infon><offset>90506</offset><text>Cycle lanes: their effect on driver passing distances in urban areas</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1</infon><infon key="lpage">15</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:De Leeuw;given-names:G.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:de Kruijf;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">European Transport Conference</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>90575</offset><text>The Act of (Future) Cycling: Testing Urban Designs and Conducting Research in Virtual Reality</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">65</infon><infon key="lpage">70</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Hirose;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Kitamura;given-names:Y.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1007/978-3-319-20306-5</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Persuas. Technol.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">9072</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>90669</offset><text>Preliminary evaluation of virtual cycling system using google street view</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">59</infon><infon key="lpage">96</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Heinen;given-names:E.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:van Wee;given-names:B.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Maat;given-names:K.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1080/01441640903187001</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Transp. Rev.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">30</infon><infon key="year">2010</infon><offset>90743</offset><text>Commuting by Bicycle: An Overview of the Literature</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">ijerph-15-00470-g001.jpg</infon><infon key="id">ijerph-15-00470-f001</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>90795</offset><text>Pathway diagram of included and excluded articles in review.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">ijerph-15-00470-g002.jpg</infon><infon key="id">ijerph-15-00470-f002</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>90856</offset><text>Seven method families for categorisation of the literature (numbers of articles in parentheses).</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">ijerph-15-00470-g003.jpg</infon><infon key="id">ijerph-15-00470-f003</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>90953</offset><text>Revealed preference bicycle route choice publications for whole journeys (112) sorted by method family.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">ijerph-15-00470-g004.jpg</infon><infon key="id">ijerph-15-00470-f004</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>91057</offset><text>Reported number of participants by method family (number of included studies in parentheses). The category other includes accompanied trips, camera and VR.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">ijerph-15-00470-g005.jpg</infon><infon key="id">ijerph-15-00470-f005</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>91213</offset><text>Geographical spread of the empirical research (112) by location of data collection.</text></passage></document></collection>
