<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd">
<collection><source>PMC</source><date>20210422</date><key>pmc.key</key><document><id>6109031</id><infon key="license">CC BY-NC</infon><passage><infon key="article-id_doi">10.1007/s13555-018-0242-5</infon><infon key="article-id_pmc">6109031</infon><infon key="article-id_pmid">29876724</infon><infon key="article-id_publisher-id">242</infon><infon key="fpage">405</infon><infon key="issue">3</infon><infon key="kwd">Clinical research Digital Psoriasis Internet Patient-reported outcomes Online Portal Psoriatic arthritis Quality of life Symptoms</infon><infon key="license">This article is distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/), which permits any noncommercial use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided you give appropriate credit to the original author(s) and the source, provide a link to the Creative Commons license, and indicate if changes were made.</infon><infon key="lpage">423</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Sanchez;given-names:Isabelle M.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Shankle;given-names:Lindsey</infon><infon key="name_10">surname:Orbai;given-names:Ana-Maria</infon><infon key="name_11">surname:Takeshita;given-names:Junko</infon><infon key="name_12">surname:Gelfand;given-names:Joel M.</infon><infon key="name_13">surname:Armstrong;given-names:April W.</infon><infon key="name_14">surname:Siegel;given-names:Michael P.</infon><infon key="name_15">surname:Liao;given-names:Wilson</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Wan;given-names:Marilyn T.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Afifi;given-names:Ladan</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Wu;given-names:Jashin J.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Doris;given-names:Frank</infon><infon key="name_6">surname:Bridges;given-names:Alisha</infon><infon key="name_7">surname:Boas;given-names:Marc</infon><infon key="name_8">surname:Lafoy;given-names:Brian</infon><infon key="name_9">surname:Truman;given-names:Sarah</infon><infon key="section_type">TITLE</infon><infon key="title">Keywords</infon><infon key="type">front</infon><infon key="volume">8</infon><infon key="year">2018</infon><offset>0</offset><text>Building a Citizen Pscientist: Advancing Patient-Centered Psoriasis Research by Empowering Patients as Contributors and Analysts</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract_title_1</infon><offset>129</offset><text>Introduction</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>142</offset><text>To design and implement a novel cloud-based digital platform that allows psoriatic patients and researchers to engage in the research process.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract_title_1</infon><offset>285</offset><text>Methods</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>293</offset><text>Citizen Pscientist (CP) was created by the National Psoriasis Foundation (NPF) to support and educate the global psoriatic disease community, where patients and researchers have the ability to analyze data. Psoriatic patients were invited to enroll in CP and contribute health data to a cloud database by responding to a 59-question online survey. They were then invited to perform their own analyses of the data using built-in visualization tools allowing for the creation of “discovery charts.” These charts were posted on the CP website allowing for further discussion.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract_title_1</infon><offset>870</offset><text>Results</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>878</offset><text>As of May 2017, 3534 patients have enrolled in CP and have collectively contributed over 200,000 data points on their health status. Patients posted 70 discovery charts, generating 209 discussion comments.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract_title_1</infon><offset>1084</offset><text>Conclusion</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>1095</offset><text>With the growing influence of the internet and technology in society, medical research can be enhanced by crowdsourcing and online patient portals. Patient discovery charts focused on the topics of psoriatic disease demographics, clinical features, environmental triggers, and quality of life. Patients noted that the CP platform adds to their well-being and allows them to express what research questions matter most to them in a direct and quantifiable way. The implementation of CP is a successful and novel method of allowing patients to engage in research. Thus, CP is an important tool to promote patient-centered psoriatic disease research.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>1743</offset><text>Introduction</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>1756</offset><text>Psoriasis is a common chronic autoimmune and inflammatory disease that affects the skin and causes a significant impact on quality of life, affecting approximately 2–4% of the US population. It is characterized by sharply demarcated, scaly, and erythematous skin lesions most commonly affecting the scalp, elbows, knees, feet, and trunk. Psoriatic arthritis (PsA), depression, anxiety, physical inactivity, and social isolation may also develop, which contribute further to the social stigma and burden caused by psoriasis. Psoriasis is also strongly associated with diabetes and major cardiovascular events, with excess mortality seen in patients with psoriasis affecting 10% or more of the body surface area. An important aspect of managing psoriatic disease is to address the psychosocial and physical symptoms through support, in which patients often benefit from sharing their experiences with a community of psoriatic patients.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>2692</offset><text>Traditionally, patients have not been included in contributing to research design and analysis because of under-recognition of the value of their contributions as research partners. There is a broader challenge of engaging patients in research that includes the lack of patient expertise or involvement. If only the perspective of researchers is represented, topics of less importance to patients may be explored, thus providing results that are of limited use. Given increasing social media utilization and the proportion of adults that seek health information from the internet, online crowdsourcing platforms have become innovative tools that actively engage patients in the research process. Crowdsourcing solicits creative ideas from paid consumers who complete a requested task. Although crowdsourcing in its most general sense involves non-selective participation, a major advantage of disease-specific portals is their potential for optimization of patient groups that have different needs than the general population.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">Tab1.xml</infon><infon key="id">Tab1</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_caption</infon><offset>3719</offset><text>Online disease portals with network health science</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">Tab1.xml</infon><infon key="id">Tab1</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table</infon><infon key="xml">&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;table xmlns:xlink=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink&quot; frame=&quot;hsides&quot; rules=&quot;groups&quot;&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Project name, condition(s), (website)&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Innovative features&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Role in medical research&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; colspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;Specific condition(s)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Citizen Pscientist&lt;xref ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot; rid=&quot;CR27&quot;&gt;27&lt;/xref&gt;, psoriasis and psoriatic arthritis, (www.citizenpscientist.org)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;First organization in USA to crowdsource psoriasis and psoriatic arthritis patient information&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Consists of over 3500 members&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Users can analyze data and create graphs&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overseen by a governing council composed of in-house research staff, patients, dermatology, and rheumatology researchers&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cloud-based data set for analysis and to understand research priorities that are most important to patients&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Exploration of innovative hypotheses of psoriatic demographics and clinical outcomes&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Citizen Science&lt;xref ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot; rid=&quot;CR78&quot;&gt;78&lt;/xref&gt;, cancer, (&lt;ext-link ext-link-type=&quot;uri&quot; xlink:href=&quot;http://www.cancerresearchuk.org&quot;&gt;http://www.cancerresearchuk.org&lt;/ext-link&gt;)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;World’s first organization to crowdsource cancer research by incorporating data analysis into apps and games&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Consists of 500,000 global volunteers&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Project was set up on the basis of the idea that collective efforts could free up specialists’ time&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Study showed that crowdsourcing the general public could provide accurate estrogen receptor data using cell images&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Creaky Joints Arthritis Power&lt;xref ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot; rid=&quot;CR79&quot;&gt;79&lt;/xref&gt;, arthritis, (&lt;ext-link ext-link-type=&quot;uri&quot; xlink:href=&quot;https://arthritispower.creakyjoints.org/%23one&quot;&gt;https://arthritispower.creakyjoints.org/#one&lt;/ext-link&gt;)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Arthritis Power allows patients to track symptoms, treatment, and other health information&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Can be used for patients to track their symptoms over time&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;De-identified data will be analyzed by researchers to advance personalized medicine&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Digital Alzheimer Center (DAC)&lt;xref ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot; rid=&quot;CR80&quot;&gt;80&lt;/xref&gt;, Alzheimer’s disease, (&lt;ext-link ext-link-type=&quot;uri&quot; xlink:href=&quot;https://www.alzheimercentrum.nl&quot;&gt;https://www.alzheimercentrum.nl&lt;/ext-link&gt;)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first patient portal on dementia care in the Netherlands&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Offers information on dementia to enhance social activities, provides support and peer-to-peer contact&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tested the usability and usefulness of an internet portal for patients and their caregivers&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mixed methods were used: observations of patients and caregivers while they perform prescribed tasks on the DAC; an online survey among patients and caregivers; and semistructured interviews with patients, caregivers, and healthcare professionals&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Global Parents for Eczema Research&lt;xref ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot; rid=&quot;CR22&quot;&gt;22&lt;/xref&gt;, pediatric atopic dermatitis, (&lt;ext-link ext-link-type=&quot;uri&quot; xlink:href=&quot;http://www.parentsforeczemaresearch.org&quot;&gt;http://www.parentsforeczemaresearch.org&lt;/ext-link&gt;)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Developed a computer technique from Natural Language Processing called topic modeling to summarize and analyze patient and caregiver posts from seven online social networks with active atopic dermatitis communities, which then underwent human review by a parent/caregiver of AD on the team&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Analyzed 10,000 online posts and following the analysis by the parent/caregiver; 37 topics emerged from the batch—the most common topics dealt with issues related to topical treatment such as moisturizers and ointments, side effects of steroids, and connection between AD and diet (in that order)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Precision Medicine Advances using Nationally Crowdsourced Comparative Effectiveness Research (PRANCCER)&lt;xref ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot; rid=&quot;CR81&quot;&gt;81&lt;/xref&gt;, cardiovascular disease, (&lt;ext-link ext-link-type=&quot;uri&quot; xlink:href=&quot;http://www.heart.org&quot;&gt;http://www.heart.org&lt;/ext-link&gt;)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;A joint effort between Patient-Centered Outcomes Research Institute (PCORI) and the American Heart Association that used crowdsourcing with input from patients, clinicians, family caregivers, and researchers&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Identify priorities for ideation in cardiovascular disease research&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Crohn &amp;amp; Colitis Foundation of America (CCFA) Partners, (&lt;ext-link ext-link-type=&quot;uri&quot; xlink:href=&quot;https://ccfa.med.unc.edu/research&quot;&gt;https://ccfa.med.unc.edu/research&lt;/ext-link&gt;)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;CCFA Partners is an internet-based study of patients with Crohn’s disease or ulcerative colitis&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Patients fill out a survey twice a year&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As of July 2017, 156 proposed questions, 1800 votes cast, 270 comments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Patients can cast up to five “votes” to prioritize research projects and propose new topics&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; colspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;Multiple conditions&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; CureTogether&lt;xref ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot; rid=&quot;CR23&quot;&gt;23&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot; rid=&quot;CR24&quot;&gt;24&lt;/xref&gt;, (http://curetogether.com)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Largest available, real-world database studying 576 conditions with over 3 million data points&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;12,000 members in 112 countries&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Uses crowdsourcing to quantify “collective patient experience”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Patients can report and track health outcomes (e.g., weight, pain) and connect with other users&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Emphasis on rare or underfunded diseases&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data on co-morbidities using only patient-contributed data&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; PatientsLikeMe&lt;xref ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot; rid=&quot;CR19&quot;&gt;19&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot; rid=&quot;CR20&quot;&gt;20&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot; rid=&quot;CR82&quot;&gt;82&lt;/xref&gt;, (https://www.patientslikeme.com)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Members can share symptoms, treatments, health data, and opinions&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;In-house research team that uses the large-scale data for different research outcomes&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Public-Led Online Trials-Infrastructure and Tools, (&lt;ext-link ext-link-type=&quot;uri&quot; xlink:href=&quot;http://www.ithinkwell.org&quot;&gt;http://www.ithinkwell.org&lt;/ext-link&gt;)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Crowdsources research ideas and health data&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Develop online randomized controlled trial (RCT) to assess shared decision-making for better health and well-being through building and testing infrastructure for valid online trials&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
</infon><offset>3770</offset><text>Project name, condition(s), (website)	Innovative features	Role in medical research	 	Specific condition(s)	 	 Citizen Pscientist, psoriasis and psoriatic arthritis, (www.citizenpscientist.org)	First organization in USA to crowdsource psoriasis and psoriatic arthritis patient informationConsists of over 3500 membersUsers can analyze data and create graphs	Overseen by a governing council composed of in-house research staff, patients, dermatology, and rheumatology researchersCloud-based data set for analysis and to understand research priorities that are most important to patientsExploration of innovative hypotheses of psoriatic demographics and clinical outcomes	 	 Citizen Science, cancer, (http://www.cancerresearchuk.org)	World’s first organization to crowdsource cancer research by incorporating data analysis into apps and gamesConsists of 500,000 global volunteersProject was set up on the basis of the idea that collective efforts could free up specialists’ time	Study showed that crowdsourcing the general public could provide accurate estrogen receptor data using cell images	 	 Creaky Joints Arthritis Power, arthritis, (https://arthritispower.creakyjoints.org/#one)	Arthritis Power allows patients to track symptoms, treatment, and other health informationCan be used for patients to track their symptoms over time	De-identified data will be analyzed by researchers to advance personalized medicine	 	 Digital Alzheimer Center (DAC), Alzheimer’s disease, (https://www.alzheimercentrum.nl)	The first patient portal on dementia care in the NetherlandsOffers information on dementia to enhance social activities, provides support and peer-to-peer contact	Tested the usability and usefulness of an internet portal for patients and their caregiversMixed methods were used: observations of patients and caregivers while they perform prescribed tasks on the DAC; an online survey among patients and caregivers; and semistructured interviews with patients, caregivers, and healthcare professionals	 	 Global Parents for Eczema Research, pediatric atopic dermatitis, (http://www.parentsforeczemaresearch.org)	Developed a computer technique from Natural Language Processing called topic modeling to summarize and analyze patient and caregiver posts from seven online social networks with active atopic dermatitis communities, which then underwent human review by a parent/caregiver of AD on the team	Analyzed 10,000 online posts and following the analysis by the parent/caregiver; 37 topics emerged from the batch—the most common topics dealt with issues related to topical treatment such as moisturizers and ointments, side effects of steroids, and connection between AD and diet (in that order)	 	 Precision Medicine Advances using Nationally Crowdsourced Comparative Effectiveness Research (PRANCCER), cardiovascular disease, (http://www.heart.org)	A joint effort between Patient-Centered Outcomes Research Institute (PCORI) and the American Heart Association that used crowdsourcing with input from patients, clinicians, family caregivers, and researchers	Identify priorities for ideation in cardiovascular disease research	 	 Crohn &amp; Colitis Foundation of America (CCFA) Partners, (https://ccfa.med.unc.edu/research)	CCFA Partners is an internet-based study of patients with Crohn’s disease or ulcerative colitisPatients fill out a survey twice a yearAs of July 2017, 156 proposed questions, 1800 votes cast, 270 comments	Patients can cast up to five “votes” to prioritize research projects and propose new topics	 	Multiple conditions	 	 CureTogether, (http://curetogether.com)	Largest available, real-world database studying 576 conditions with over 3 million data points12,000 members in 112 countriesUses crowdsourcing to quantify “collective patient experience”Patients can report and track health outcomes (e.g., weight, pain) and connect with other users	Emphasis on rare or underfunded diseasesData on co-morbidities using only patient-contributed data	 	 PatientsLikeMe, (https://www.patientslikeme.com)	Members can share symptoms, treatments, health data, and opinions	In-house research team that uses the large-scale data for different research outcomes	 	 Public-Led Online Trials-Infrastructure and Tools, (http://www.ithinkwell.org)	Crowdsources research ideas and health data	Develop online randomized controlled trial (RCT) to assess shared decision-making for better health and well-being through building and testing infrastructure for valid online trials	 	</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>8287</offset><text>There are several online portals that invite patients to participate in the research process by contributing health data or ideas and observing the participants’ results (Table 1). PatientsLikeMe allows patients to share information about their disease with other participants and companies to develop improved healthcare tools or services, in which 5789 psoriasis patients are registered. However, data is outsourced to partner pharmaceutical and clinical trials research companies, which some patients may not feel comfortable with. The Global Parents for Eczema Research analyzed “patient and caregiver chatter” from social networks for atopic dermatitis (AD), identifying topics on topical treatments, the side effects of steroids, and diet. CureTogether, a website with patient-generated symptom and treatment data on skin diseases, was created in order to diversify participants and increase participation and has 335 enrolled psoriasis patients. </text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>9248</offset><text>Similarly, Citizen Pscientist (CP) was developed as a method of support and education for the psoriatic disease community. However, CP is distinct from any other crowdsourced projects in that patients are directly involved in their own research as both data contributors and research analysts. The CP research project was created in 2015 by the National Psoriasis Foundation (NPF) and funded through a Pipeline-to-Proposal Award from a US non-profit organization, the PCORI. The objective of CP is to engage psoriasis patients in the research process, as the role of both subjects and “pscientists.” The initiation and implementation of CP were overseen by a CP governing council of patients, psoriatic disease researchers, and NPF staff. Here, we describe a novel approach of patient-driven research and share the experience of implementing a psoriatic disease-specific interactive patient database through CP.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>10164</offset><text>Methods</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>10172</offset><text>CP Structure and Survey</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>10196</offset><text>A CP governing council, composed of patients, researchers, and NPF staff generated 59 initial survey questions asking about health data on demographics, family history, symptoms, disease onset, psoriasis subtypes, disease severity, triggers, quality of life, associated co-morbidities, and response to interventions. The CP survey followed the Checklist for Reporting Results of Internet E-Surveys (CHERRIES) reporting criteria.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>10625</offset><text>Patient Recruitment and Enrollment</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>10660</offset><text>Patients were invited to enroll in CP through a website (www.citizenpscientist.org) promoted by NPF. Individuals registered on the CP portal with a valid e-mail address, which allowed for the establishment of a single user profile. Electronic informed consent was obtained from all participants at enrollment.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>10970</offset><text>Recruitment was conducted through NPF’s patient membership listserve, main website, social media outlets, the Patient Navigation Center, Psoriasis Advance magazine, and promotional materials used at NPF in-person events. The NPF currently has a strong social media presence for adequate marketing potential, as demonstrated by 71,190 “likes” and 68,054 followers on Facebook, 19,700 followers on Twitter, and 2180 followers on Linked-In.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>11414</offset><text>Patient-Generated Data</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">13555_2018_242_Fig1_HTML.jpg</infon><infon key="id">Fig1</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>11437</offset><text>Workflow process of Citizen Pscientist. The CP Governing Council helps develop survey questions, which the CP patients answer. This data is then stored in a de-identified cloud database. Then, CP patients and the psoriatic research community can analyze the data, post discoveries, and generate discussion about the findings. These activities inform future survey questions and CP initiatives</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>11830</offset><text>CP’s most unique aspect allows patients to explore de-identified patient-generated data and examine the relationship between any two variables from the intake survey. Such findings are posted as charts on the website, which are named “discovery charts.” After the results are posted online, any of the users can comment on the output. The features of openly publishing results to the CP community promote further explorations or allow patients to discuss or relate the findings to their own experiences or knowledge about their condition. Researchers, such as those at academic universities, are also able to analyze the data (Fig. 1). </text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>12474</offset><text>The content of new survey questions can be informed by patient input. The CP governing council previously published on patient priorities for comparative effectiveness research (CER) within the CP community and our survey reflects these topics of importance identified by patients.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>12756</offset><text>Data Analysis</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>12770</offset><text>Patient demographics and clinical characteristics were tabulated by frequency using Microsoft Excel and STATA Special Edition, version 14.2 (College Station, TX). Geographical data was analyzed using ArcGIS Online mapping software (Environmental Systems Research Institute, Redlands, CA, USA). All patient-generated discovery charts up to September 2017 were analyzed for the content of topics. Missing data were included in the analysis and were specified as “no response” in the results table.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>13270</offset><text>Compliance with Ethics Guidelines</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>13304</offset><text>Institutional review board (IRB) approval for CP was obtained from Genetic Alliance, which includes patients outside of the USA.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>13433</offset><text>Results</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>13441</offset><text>Patient Participation</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">13555_2018_242_Fig2_HTML.jpg</infon><infon key="id">Fig2</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>13463</offset><text>Geographical distribution of CP users in the USA, October 2017</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">13555_2018_242_Fig3_HTML.jpg</infon><infon key="id">Fig3</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>13526</offset><text>Worldwide geographical distribution of CP users, October 2017, n = 3404</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>13602</offset><text>As of May 2017, there were 3534 users on the CP platform contributing over 200,000 data points. CP members were well distributed geographically in the USA; there were members from every state and territory (Fig. 2). Globally, CP members were primarily from the USA, UK, France, India, and Australia (Fig. 3). CP members were also observed from Fiji, Samoa, New Zealand, Iceland, Saudi Arabia, Singapore, Taipei, Finland, Syria, Greece, Austria, Russia, the Caribbean, and South Africa, among others. </text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>14105</offset><text>The activity of CP users over time is monitored. Unique visits to the site averaged 800 per month from May to December 2017 for a total of 6409 visits by CP users, and the highest activity was in July and August.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>14318</offset><text>Patient Demographics</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">Tab2.xml</infon><infon key="id">Tab2</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_caption</infon><offset>14339</offset><text>Demographics of CP members, May 2017</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">Tab2.xml</infon><infon key="id">Tab2</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table</infon><infon key="xml">&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;table frame=&quot;hsides&quot; rules=&quot;groups&quot;&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Member characteristic&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Frequency, &lt;italic&gt;n&lt;/italic&gt; (%)&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;Disease&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Psoriasis&lt;sup&gt;a&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td char=&quot;(&quot; align=&quot;char&quot;&gt;3246 (91.9)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Psoriasis with psoriatic arthritis&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td char=&quot;(&quot; align=&quot;char&quot;&gt;1545 (43.7)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; No response&lt;sup&gt;a&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td char=&quot;(&quot; align=&quot;char&quot;&gt;288 (8.1)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;Age&lt;sup&gt;a&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Under 18&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td char=&quot;(&quot; align=&quot;char&quot;&gt;56 (1.6)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; 18–30&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td char=&quot;(&quot; align=&quot;char&quot;&gt;383 (10.8)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; 31–40&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td char=&quot;(&quot; align=&quot;char&quot;&gt;541 (15.3)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; 41–50&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td char=&quot;(&quot; align=&quot;char&quot;&gt;699 (19.8)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; 51–65&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td char=&quot;(&quot; align=&quot;char&quot;&gt;1105 (31.3)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Over 65&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td char=&quot;(&quot; align=&quot;char&quot;&gt;354 (10.0)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; No response&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td char=&quot;(&quot; align=&quot;char&quot;&gt;396 (11.2)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;Gender&lt;sup&gt;b&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Female&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td char=&quot;(&quot; align=&quot;char&quot;&gt;2151 (60.9)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Male&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td char=&quot;(&quot; align=&quot;char&quot;&gt;964 (27.3)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; No response&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td char=&quot;(&quot; align=&quot;char&quot;&gt;419 (11.8)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;Racial/ethnic background*&lt;sup&gt;,b&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; White/Caucasian&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td char=&quot;(&quot; align=&quot;char&quot;&gt;4918 (69.6)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Asian&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td char=&quot;(&quot; align=&quot;char&quot;&gt;346 (4.9)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Hispanic/Latino&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td char=&quot;(&quot; align=&quot;char&quot;&gt;317 (4.5)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; American Indian/Alaskan Native&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td char=&quot;(&quot; align=&quot;char&quot;&gt;242 (3.4)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Black/African American&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td char=&quot;(&quot; align=&quot;char&quot;&gt;122 (1.7)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Native Hawaiian/Pacific Islander&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td char=&quot;(&quot; align=&quot;char&quot;&gt;19 (0.3)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Other&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td char=&quot;(&quot; align=&quot;char&quot;&gt;1253 (17.7)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; No response&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td char=&quot;(&quot; align=&quot;char&quot;&gt;979 (13.9)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;Alcohol consumption (drinks per week)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; 1–3&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td char=&quot;(&quot; align=&quot;char&quot;&gt;972 (27.5)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; 4–6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td char=&quot;(&quot; align=&quot;char&quot;&gt;295 (8.3)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; 7–9&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td char=&quot;(&quot; align=&quot;char&quot;&gt;191 (5.4)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; 10 or more&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td char=&quot;(&quot; align=&quot;char&quot;&gt;191 (5.4)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; I don’t drink&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td char=&quot;(&quot; align=&quot;char&quot;&gt;1338 (37.9)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; No response&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td char=&quot;(&quot; align=&quot;char&quot;&gt;547 (15.4)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;Smoking (cigarettes per day)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; 1–10&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td char=&quot;(&quot; align=&quot;char&quot;&gt;208 (5.9)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; 11–20&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td char=&quot;(&quot; align=&quot;char&quot;&gt;167 (4.7)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; &amp;gt; 20&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td char=&quot;(&quot; align=&quot;char&quot;&gt;57 (1.6)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Not daily smoker&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td char=&quot;(&quot; align=&quot;char&quot;&gt;179 (5.1)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Non-smoker&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td char=&quot;(&quot; align=&quot;char&quot;&gt;2365 (67.0)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; No response&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td char=&quot;(&quot; align=&quot;char&quot;&gt;558 (15.8)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Immediate family with psoriasis&lt;sup&gt;a&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td char=&quot;(&quot; align=&quot;char&quot;&gt;1296 (36.7)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Immediate family with psoriatic arthritis&lt;sup&gt;a&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td char=&quot;(&quot; align=&quot;char&quot;&gt;921 (26.1)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
</infon><offset>14376</offset><text>Member characteristic	Frequency, n (%)	 	Disease	 	 Psoriasisa	3246 (91.9)	 	 Psoriasis with psoriatic arthritis	1545 (43.7)	 	 No responsea	288 (8.1)	 	Agea	 	 Under 18	56 (1.6)	 	 18–30	383 (10.8)	 	 31–40	541 (15.3)	 	 41–50	699 (19.8)	 	 51–65	1105 (31.3)	 	 Over 65	354 (10.0)	 	 No response	396 (11.2)	 	Genderb	 	 Female	2151 (60.9)	 	 Male	964 (27.3)	 	 No response	419 (11.8)	 	Racial/ethnic background*,b	 	 White/Caucasian	4918 (69.6)	 	 Asian	346 (4.9)	 	 Hispanic/Latino	317 (4.5)	 	 American Indian/Alaskan Native	242 (3.4)	 	 Black/African American	122 (1.7)	 	 Native Hawaiian/Pacific Islander	19 (0.3)	 	 Other	1253 (17.7)	 	 No response	979 (13.9)	 	Alcohol consumption (drinks per week)	 	 1–3	972 (27.5)	 	 4–6	295 (8.3)	 	 7–9	191 (5.4)	 	 10 or more	191 (5.4)	 	 I don’t drink	1338 (37.9)	 	 No response	547 (15.4)	 	Smoking (cigarettes per day)	 	 1–10	208 (5.9)	 	 11–20	167 (4.7)	 	 &gt; 20	57 (1.6)	 	 Not daily smoker	179 (5.1)	 	 Non-smoker	2365 (67.0)	 	 No response	558 (15.8)	 	 Immediate family with psoriasisa	1296 (36.7)	 	 Immediate family with psoriatic arthritisa	921 (26.1)	 	</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">Tab2.xml</infon><infon key="id">Tab2</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_foot</infon><offset>15543</offset><text>*Total sum &gt; 100% because of multiple responses by subjects</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">Tab2.xml</infon><infon key="id">Tab2</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_foot</infon><offset>15607</offset><text>aCalculated using total number of subjects (n = 3534)</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">Tab2.xml</infon><infon key="id">Tab2</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_foot</infon><offset>15665</offset><text>bCalculated using ethnic data from both mother and father (n = 7068)</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>15738</offset><text>At baseline, 3246 (91.9%) reported having physician-diagnosed psoriasis and 1545 (43.7%) reported having physician-diagnosed psoriatic arthritis (Table 2). A small percentage of CP users (8.1%) did not specify psoriasis status. The majority of CP users are greater than 40 years of age; few users of the CP platform are below the age of 18 (1.6%). There is a female predominance (60.9%) among the CP community with male members only representing approximately 27.3%, though 11.8% did not answer data on sex. The racial background of the CP community was determined from questions on parental ancestry rather than self-report of ethnicity. The CP membership is predominantly White/Caucasian (69.6%), followed by Asian (4.9%), Hispanic/Latino (4.5%), American Indian/Alaskan Native (3.4%), Black/African American (1.7%), and Native Hawaiian/Pacific Islander (0.3%). </text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>16604</offset><text>Approximately 38% of CP users do not consume alcohol, while a similar proportion report having six drinks or less in 1 week and a minority consumes more than seven drinks per week (11%). The majority of CP users (67%) do not smoke, with 12.2% smoking one or more cigarettes per day. Regarding family history, 36.7% of the CP users report an immediate family member with psoriasis and 26.1% report an immediate family member with psoriatic arthritis.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>17055</offset><text>Clinical Characteristics</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">Tab3.xml</infon><infon key="id">Tab3</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_caption</infon><offset>17080</offset><text>Clinical characteristics of CP members, May 2017</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">Tab3.xml</infon><infon key="id">Tab3</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table</infon><infon key="xml">&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;table frame=&quot;hsides&quot; rules=&quot;groups&quot;&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Member characteristic&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Frequency, &lt;italic&gt;n&lt;/italic&gt; (%)&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;Comorbidities*&lt;sup&gt;,a&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; High blood pressure&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;790 (22.4)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; High cholesterol&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;709 (20.1)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Thyroid disease&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;396 (11.2)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Sleep apnea&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;357 (10.1)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; High triglycerides&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;341 (9.6)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Eczema/atopic dermatitis&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;431 (12.2)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Type 2 diabetes mellitus&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;193 (5.5)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Fatty liver disease&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;159 (4.5)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Cancer&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;144 (4.1)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Rheumatoid arthritis&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;136 (3.8)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Coronary artery disease&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;87 (2.5)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Uveitis&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;74 (2.1)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Sjögren’s syndrome&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;60 (1.7)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Liver disease&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;48 (1.4)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Celiac disease&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;49 (1.4)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Crohn disease&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;44 (1.2)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Stroke&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;43 (1.2)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Alopecia areata&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;31 (0.9)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Lupus&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;27 (0.8)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Type 1 diabetes mellitus&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;21 (0.6)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Multiple sclerosis&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;15 (0.4)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Cutaneous T cell lymphoma&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;4 (0.1)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Parkinson’s disease&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;5 (0.1)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Other&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;220 (6.2)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; None&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;675 (19.1)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; No response&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;349 (9.9)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;Psoriasis subtype*&lt;sup&gt;,a&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Plaque&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;2459 (69.6)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Guttate&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;573 (16.2)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Inverse&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;485 (13.7)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Pustular&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;350 (9.9)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Erythrodermic&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;116 (3.3)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Not sure&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;1 (&amp;lt; 0.1)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; No response&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;294 (8.3)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;Psoriasis location*&lt;sup&gt;,a&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Scalp&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;2100 (59.4)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Arm/legs&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;1948 (55.1)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Elbow/knees&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;1799 (50.9)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Ears&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;1521 (43.0)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Abdomen&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;1429 (40.4)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Nails&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;1173 (33.2)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Skin folds&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;1013 (28.7)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Face&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;932 (26.4)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Genitals&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;854 (24.2)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Palms of hands&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;584 (16.5)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Soles of feet&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;561 (15.9)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; No response&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;227 (6.4)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;Psoriasis severity&lt;sup&gt;a&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Mild: &amp;lt; 5% BSA&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;1303 (36.9)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Moderate: 5–10% BSA&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;1035 (29.3)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Severe: &amp;gt; 10% BSA&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;540 (15.3)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; No response&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;249 (18.6)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;Affected joints in psoriatic arthritis&lt;sup&gt;b&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Knuckles&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;823 (53.3)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Knees&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;815 (52.7)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Toes&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;709 (45.9)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Wrists&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;664 (43.0)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Spine&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;629 (40.7)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Ankles&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;618 (40.0)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Shoulders&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;581 (37.6)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Hips&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;559 (36.2)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Neck&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;546 (35.3)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Elbows&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;485 (31.4)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; Jaw&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;241 (15.6)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; No response&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;5 (0.4)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
</infon><offset>17129</offset><text>Member characteristic	Frequency, n (%)	 	Comorbidities*,a	 	 High blood pressure	790 (22.4)	 	 High cholesterol	709 (20.1)	 	 Thyroid disease	396 (11.2)	 	 Sleep apnea	357 (10.1)	 	 High triglycerides	341 (9.6)	 	 Eczema/atopic dermatitis	431 (12.2)	 	 Type 2 diabetes mellitus	193 (5.5)	 	 Fatty liver disease	159 (4.5)	 	 Cancer	144 (4.1)	 	 Rheumatoid arthritis	136 (3.8)	 	 Coronary artery disease	87 (2.5)	 	 Uveitis	74 (2.1)	 	 Sjögren’s syndrome	60 (1.7)	 	 Liver disease	48 (1.4)	 	 Celiac disease	49 (1.4)	 	 Crohn disease	44 (1.2)	 	 Stroke	43 (1.2)	 	 Alopecia areata	31 (0.9)	 	 Lupus	27 (0.8)	 	 Type 1 diabetes mellitus	21 (0.6)	 	 Multiple sclerosis	15 (0.4)	 	 Cutaneous T cell lymphoma	4 (0.1)	 	 Parkinson’s disease	5 (0.1)	 	 Other	220 (6.2)	 	 None	675 (19.1)	 	 No response	349 (9.9)	 	Psoriasis subtype*,a	 	 Plaque	2459 (69.6)	 	 Guttate	573 (16.2)	 	 Inverse	485 (13.7)	 	 Pustular	350 (9.9)	 	 Erythrodermic	116 (3.3)	 	 Not sure	1 (&lt; 0.1)	 	 No response	294 (8.3)	 	Psoriasis location*,a	 	 Scalp	2100 (59.4)	 	 Arm/legs	1948 (55.1)	 	 Elbow/knees	1799 (50.9)	 	 Ears	1521 (43.0)	 	 Abdomen	1429 (40.4)	 	 Nails	1173 (33.2)	 	 Skin folds	1013 (28.7)	 	 Face	932 (26.4)	 	 Genitals	854 (24.2)	 	 Palms of hands	584 (16.5)	 	 Soles of feet	561 (15.9)	 	 No response	227 (6.4)	 	Psoriasis severitya	 	 Mild: &lt; 5% BSA	1303 (36.9)	 	 Moderate: 5–10% BSA	1035 (29.3)	 	 Severe: &gt; 10% BSA	540 (15.3)	 	 No response	249 (18.6)	 	Affected joints in psoriatic arthritisb	 	 Knuckles	823 (53.3)	 	 Knees	815 (52.7)	 	 Toes	709 (45.9)	 	 Wrists	664 (43.0)	 	 Spine	629 (40.7)	 	 Ankles	618 (40.0)	 	 Shoulders	581 (37.6)	 	 Hips	559 (36.2)	 	 Neck	546 (35.3)	 	 Elbows	485 (31.4)	 	 Jaw	241 (15.6)	 	 No response	5 (0.4)	 	</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">Tab3.xml</infon><infon key="id">Tab3</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_foot</infon><offset>18945</offset><text>BSA body surface area</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">Tab3.xml</infon><infon key="id">Tab3</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_foot</infon><offset>18967</offset><text>*Total sum &gt; 100% due to multiple responses by subjects</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">Tab3.xml</infon><infon key="id">Tab3</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_foot</infon><offset>19023</offset><text>aCalculated using total number of subjects (n = 3534)</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">Tab3.xml</infon><infon key="id">Tab3</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_foot</infon><offset>19081</offset><text>bCalculated using total number of subjects having psoriatic arthritis (n = 1545)</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>19166</offset><text>It is well known from the literature that psoriatic disease patients have an increased risk of cardiovascular and autoimmune diseases. The most frequently reported comorbidities among the CP users include high blood pressure (22.4%), high cholesterol (20.1%), high triglycerides (9.6%), sleep apnea (10.1%), thyroid disease (11.2%), and eczema/atopic dermatitis (12.2%) (Table 3). Approximately 20% of CP users report having an autoimmune-related comorbidity. One-fifth of CP users did not report any of the listed comorbid conditions.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>19703</offset><text>Psoriasis may be divided into several clinical subtypes. The majority of CP users reported having plaque psoriasis (69.6%), followed by guttate (16.2%), inverse (13.7%), pustular (9.9%), and erythrodermic (3.3%) variants. The scalp, elbows/knees, and arms/legs were the most frequently reported areas with psoriatic involvement (59.4%), followed by the ears and abdomen (43% and 40%, respectively). Psoriasis located on the face, genitals, and skin folds was in each case reported in about 25% of patients while the palms and soles of the hands and feet were reported among 17% of users. Approximately 33% of CP users report having nail psoriasis. In terms of psoriasis severity, 36.9% of the CP community reported less than 5% body surface area (BSA) involvement, 29.3% reported 5–10% BSA, and 15.3% reported greater than 10% BSA. Psoriatic arthritis most frequently affected the knees and knuckles (53%) followed by the toes, wrists, ankles, and spine (45%).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>20666</offset><text>Participant-Generated Analysis</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">13555_2018_242_Fig4_HTML.jpg</infon><infon key="id">Fig4</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>20697</offset><text>Patient-generated analysis of most bothersome psoriasis sites. Screenshot from the CP online patient portal. Note the diverse discussion and feedback from personal experiences</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>20873</offset><text>A unique aspect of CP is that users can analyze their own data instantly online and share their findings with other users to generate discussions. As of June 2017, patients had posted 70 discovery charts generating 209 comments by the CP community. To examine the content of these patient-generated charts, a consecutive subset of 31 charts were further analyzed. Discovery charts were focused on demographics or clinical features of psoriatic disease (35%), environmental triggers (32%), and quality of life (32%). The relationship of demographic characteristics was often displayed according to psoriasis severity, such as how smoking varies among those with different psoriasis severity. The discovery charts posted on clinical features examined, for example, which areas of the body were affected by psoriasis and which areas were the most bothersome stratified by psoriatic arthritis status (Fig. 4), and which areas correlated with sleep disturbance. In addition, the frequency of comorbidities was explored among different patient subsets. The subtype of psoriasis was compared to several variables, such as current treatments. </text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>22010</offset><text>The discovery charts that examined environmental triggers focused on the seasonal association of flares or flare triggers such as stress, skin injury, or smoking. Alternatively, exploration of exercise and meditation were identified to reduce flares. The association between stress reduction and psoriasis severity was examined.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>22339</offset><text>Quality of life was explored through several discovery charts examining activities that are prevented by psoriatic arthritis. The association between self-consciousness and gender was examined, as well as discussions of overall life satisfaction.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>22586</offset><text>Discussion</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>22597</offset><text>CP is a powerful tool that empowers the psoriatic disease community by allowing patients to take ownership in learning more about their disease and to contribute back through self-directed research. Though there have been several other disease portals that rely on crowdsourcing and online forums, CP is the only one that promotes direct analysis of data by the users and openly displays this information for rapid patient-directed education and support.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>23052</offset><text>Since CP attracts motivated patients who enroll and provide data through an online interface, it is expected that certain groups may be over-represented. Indeed, we observed a relatively high proportion of patients with psoriatic arthritis (43.7%), which is toward the upper limit of an estimated range of 7–48% seen in epidemiologic studies and is higher than population-based estimates of approximately 10%. This indicates that individuals suffering from psoriatic arthritis may be more motivated to enroll in CP or that patients with more severe disease (in which the prevalence of PsA is increased) are more motivated to enroll. Similarly, we observed a higher proportion of female patients, whereas large-scale epidemiological studies have found no clear gender predilection for psoriasis. Our results are consistent with the observation that women more often than men engage in health information-seeking behaviors.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>23976</offset><text>The ages of CP participants follow a skewed distribution favoring ages above 41. Interestingly, the majority of participants are between 51 and 65 years (31.3%). The current CP community has a relatively low number of minorities, possibly reflecting our advertising that was limited to NPF members. Though questions about socioeconomic status were not asked in the CP survey, the NPF membership from which the CP individuals were drawn from are typically of a higher educational and income status than the general population. Approximately 17% of CP users reported current smoking behaviors, which is slightly greater than smokers found from US population studies. According to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, 13.6% of women in the USA smoked compared to 16.7% of men in 2015. A study analyzing data from the Nurses’ Health Study, the Nurses’ Health Study II, and the Health Professionals’ Follow-up Study found that current or former smokers were more likely to develop psoriasis than nonsmokers and with increased smoking duration the risk for psoriasis increased. Approximately 47% of the CP members report alcohol consumption, with the majority consuming 1–3 drinks per week (27.5%) and only a minority reporting greater than 10 drinks per week (5.4%). Alcohol abuse has been associated with a greater risk for developing or worsening psoriasis. Overall, the low prevalence of alcohol use among the CP community may be due to the female predominance, as women are less likely to be alcohol misusers, and that patients who participate in the CP initiative may be also less likely to engage in alcohol consumption. Within the CP community, 37% of members reported at least one immediate family member with psoriasis. This is consistent with studies showing that approximately 40% of patients with psoriasis or psoriatic arthritis have a family history of these disorders in first-degree relatives.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>25901</offset><text>The high rate of disorders of impaired metabolism among the CP community is consistent with previous studies demonstrating a greater likelihood of obesity, hypertension, hypertriglyceridemia, hypercholesterolemia, diabetes, and sleep apnea. In addition, 20% of CP users reported an autoimmune-related comorbidity consistent with prior studies detecting an increased autoimmune disease prevalence among patients with psoriasis and PsA such as uveitis, alopecia areata, celiac disease, systemic sclerosis, and Crohn disease.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>26424</offset><text>The type, severity, and location of psoriasis reported among the CP users are parallel to findings in the literature, with the exception of pustular psoriasis occurring twice higher than expected. Chronic plaque psoriasis is the most common variant of psoriasis with the literature reporting 55–79% of patients with psoriasis identified as the plaque type. The majority of CP patients with psoriasis have moderate to severe disease, while population-based estimates have suggested that about 20% have moderate to severe psoriatic disease. The most common areas include the scalp, elbows or knees, and gluteal cleft. Psoriatic arthritis has several different patterns of joint involvement, and we also found a wide distribution of joint involvement among CP users with psoriatic arthritis, the most common areas being the knuckles, knees, toes, wrists, spine, and ankles.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>27297</offset><text>The patient-centered discoveries of CP add value to psoriasis knowledge by showing what patients consider important about their disease. The current literature is sparse for these high-priority topics identified by psoriasis patients. There are six studies that discuss environmental triggers of psoriasis, while 10 articles explore the seasonality of psoriasis. These articles do not provide clear answers, may be resource-intensive to develop, and might have limited quality in the setting of confounding variables. Thus, there is an opportunity for the CP platform to fill these gaps of highly prioritized topics for psoriasis patients.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>27937</offset><text>CP may redirect researchers to focus on studying disease factors that are the most important to patients. Furthermore, CP’s influence on research has the potential for enabling researchers and physicians to connect with ongoing questions generated by patients. For example, a survey that ranked the patient’s top priority CER topics showed that the following were the highest importance to CP patients: comparing the effectiveness, safety, risk, and costs of treatment; diet or remedies; and communication or management strategies. Specifically, the most popular CER questions were comparing biologics to methotrexate, treat-to-target management for psoriasis, comparisons of home versus office-based phototherapy, and differences between scalp psoriasis treatment formulations. Although patient–physician communication is important in determining patient needs, direct feedback from CP is valuable information for guiding future research efforts and patient care.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>28908</offset><text>Another unique aspect of CP is that messages can be posted by participants in response to the displayed discovery charts, which may result in further discussion and analysis. For example, a data-driven discussion debated whether the observed results had statistical significance. As a result of the high interest in the debated topic, researchers may consider following up on the discussion points raised by the users.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>29327</offset><text>The initial efforts of CP were focused in the USA, as recruitment was implemented through the NPF. However, we were surprised by the reach of the CP platform to countries outside of the USA. As the number of international participants continues to increase, we will translate the survey to other languages. The fact that the intake survey and CP website are in English and from a US-based website may also contribute to the limited diversity of the subjects in our summarized results.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>29812</offset><text>Additionally, the activity of CP by users has remained high over time, with the most active months during the Summer. The average of 800 visits per month and total unique visits of 6409 in 2017 suggest that users may be visiting the site multiple times, as the visits exceed the total count of registered CP users.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>30127</offset><text>Psoriasis patients have expressed that CP adds significant value to their view of research, their general psoriasis knowledge, and their well-being. One member stated that CP is valuable because it gives patients the ability to be part of the effort to find a cure. Even though discussion groups and online forums are valuable in letting patients share their experiences with others, CP is unique in that patients can influence the direction of future research. It lets researchers know what questions matter the most to patients in a direct and quantifiable way. In addition, patients stated that CP is valuable because it lets them know what other patients’ concerns are by means of quantifiable information in the form of easy-to-read and easy-to-understand charts and graphs. They get an instant picture of other patients’ concerns and trends in the entire community’s response to survey questions. Another CP member shared the fact that awareness of overlapping disease features between patients refines patients’ understanding of psoriasis further. Importantly, CP emphasizes to those living with psoriasis that they are not alone. Individuals can anonymously share their toughest moments experiencing psoriasis, which can be translated into impactful science.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>31404</offset><text>Limitations</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>31416</offset><text>With this interactive data tool, however, there is a risk of misinterpretation of the results by the CP users. For example, a comment was posted to a discovery chart stating that fizzy drinks and sugar could help psoriasis, which was the opposite interpretation of what the results displayed. Future enhancements to the platform could consider a dermatologist or research moderator to help users understand the results correctly. It is also possible that an analysis led by patients could induce potential conflicts of interests and biases that could favor inaccurate but desired health outcomes. Therefore, the CP discovery graphs must be interpreted with caution.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>32082</offset><text>Self-reported data may not provide accurate information, especially when examining clinical factors in comparison to deriving health information from electronic health records. However, more insight into patient priorities and a wider variety of patients are reached when mining CP crowdsourced data. A correlation between self-administered scoring of disease severity to physician-generated clinical measures of psoriasis severity using the Psoriasis Area Severity Index (PASI) has been reported, although a review of patient-reported outcomes determined that most do not assess validity. In our study, 91.9% of CP enrollees reported a physician-made diagnosis of psoriasis, but it is unclear if the remainder received a diagnosis of psoriasis from a different kind of provider or self-diagnosed their condition.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>32896</offset><text>To improve the reliability of CP patient-generated data, a validation of the self-reported diagnoses through a review of patient medical records will be performed by CP researchers. After 10% of our total CP patients are sampled and consented, their physicians will be asked to provide documentation of medical records that support or refute a patient’s psoriasis diagnosis. As more robust data is generated by CP, the NPF researchers will conduct a more formal analysis of summary data.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>33386</offset><text>Conclusions</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>33398</offset><text>CP is a unique research platform that encourages meaningful data exchange for psoriatic disease research. Other patient portals have used crowdsourced research for science innovation; however, none, to our knowledge, have integrated patients into the research development or analysis process. Patient-generated analyses in CP have demonstrated interest in demographics and clinical features of psoriasis, followed by environmental triggers and seasonality, indicating that the patient perspective can help guide future research areas.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>33933</offset><text>Future efforts to enhance CP will focus on several areas. One priority is recruitment of a more racially diverse population through comprehensive outreach methods. Another priority is maintaining the engagement of users, through new survey questions and by expanding the interface to a mobile application. A subset of the CP data is currently being validated with medical records to assess the accuracy and quality of the self-reported information. Finally, the addition of real-time activity, fitness tracking, and DNA or other biospecimens may also be explored. In these ways, CP can continue to contribute to patient-centered research that improves the quality of life of psoriatic patients globally.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">footnote</infon><offset>34637</offset><text>Enhanced digital features</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">footnote</infon><offset>34663</offset><text>To view enhanced digital features for this article go to 10.6084/m9.figshare.6269294.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">title</infon><offset>34749</offset><text>References</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1665</infon><infon key="issue">6</infon><infon key="lpage">1668</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Goff;given-names:KL</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Karimkhani;given-names:C</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Boyers;given-names:LN</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1111/bjd.13715</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">25645671</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Br J Dermatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">172</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>34760</offset><text>The global burden of psoriatic skin disease</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">512</infon><infon key="issue">3</infon><infon key="lpage">516</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Rachakonda;given-names:TD</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Schupp;given-names:CW</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Armstrong;given-names:AW</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2013.11.013</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">24388724</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Am Acad Dermatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">70</infon><infon key="year">2014</infon><offset>34804</offset><text>Psoriasis prevalence among adults in the United States</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">763</infon><infon key="issue">6</infon><infon key="lpage">770</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Bewley;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Burrage;given-names:DM</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Ersser;given-names:SJ</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Hansen;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Ward;given-names:C</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1111/jdv.12174</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">23663069</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">28</infon><infon key="year">2014</infon><offset>34859</offset><text>Identifying individual psychosocial and adherence support needs in patients with psoriasis: a multinational two-stage qualitative and quantitative study</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">377</infon><infon key="issue">3</infon><infon key="lpage">390</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Takeshita;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Grewal;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Langan;given-names:SM</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2016.07.064</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">28212759</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Am Acad Dermatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">76</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>35012</offset><text>Psoriasis and comorbid diseases: epidemiology</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">515</infon><infon key="issue">3</infon><infon key="lpage">520</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Balato;given-names:N</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Megna;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Palmisano;given-names:F</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1111/jdv.12607</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">25132013</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">29</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>35058</offset><text>Psoriasis and sport: a new ally?</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">995</infon><infon key="issue">9</infon><infon key="lpage">1000</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Azfar;given-names:RS</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Seminara;given-names:NM</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Shin;given-names:DB</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Troxel;given-names:AB</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Margolis;given-names:DJ</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Gelfand;given-names:JM</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1001/archdermatol.2012.1401</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">22710320</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Arch Dermatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">148</infon><infon key="year">2012</infon><offset>35091</offset><text>Increased risk of diabetes mellitus and likelihood of receiving diabetes mellitus treatment in patients with psoriasis</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1735</infon><infon key="issue">14</infon><infon key="lpage">1741</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Gelfand;given-names:JM</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Neimann;given-names:AL</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Shin;given-names:DB</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Wang;given-names:X</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Margolis;given-names:DJ</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Troxel;given-names:AB</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1001/jama.296.14.1735</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">17032986</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">JAMA</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">296</infon><infon key="year">2006</infon><offset>35210</offset><text>Risk of myocardial infarction in patients with psoriasis</text></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Noe;given-names:MH</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Shin;given-names:DB</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Wan;given-names:MT</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Gelfand;given-names:JM</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Invest Dermatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>35267</offset><text>Objective measures of psoriasis severity predict mortality: a prospective population-based cohort study</text></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Wan;given-names:MT</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Shin;given-names:DB</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Hubbard;given-names:RA</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Noe;given-names:MH</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Mehta;given-names:NN</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Gelfand;given-names:JM</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Am Acad Dermatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>35371</offset><text>Psoriasis and the risk of diabetes: a prospective population-based cohort study</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">187</infon><infon key="issue">1</infon><infon key="lpage">203</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Ranard;given-names:BL</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Ha;given-names:YP</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Meisel;given-names:ZF</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1007/s11606-013-2536-8</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">23843021</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Gen Intern Med</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">29</infon><infon key="year">2014</infon><offset>35451</offset><text>Crowdsourcing—harnessing the masses to advance health and medicine, a systematic review</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">213</infon><infon key="issue">2</infon><infon key="lpage">236</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Boote;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Telford;given-names:R</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Cooper;given-names:C</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/S0168-8510(01)00214-7</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">12088893</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Health Policy</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">61</infon><infon key="year">2002</infon><offset>35541</offset><text>Consumer involvement in health research: a review and research agenda</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>35611</offset><text>Pew Research Center. Social media fact sheet. Pew Internet &amp; American Life Project. http://www.pewinternet.org/fact-sheet/social-media/#. Accessed 31 Aug 2017.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>35771</offset><text>Fox S. Mobile, social health. Pew Internet &amp; American Life Project. http://www.pewinternet.org/2010/07/08/mobile-social-health/. Accessed 31 Aug 2017.</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">201</infon><infon key="issue">1</infon><infon key="lpage">205</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Balato;given-names:N</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Megna;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Di Costanzo;given-names:L</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Balato;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Ayala;given-names:F</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1111/j.1365-2133.2012.11205.x</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">23240729</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Br J Dermatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">168</infon><infon key="year">2013</infon><offset>35922</offset><text>Educational and motivational support service: a pilot study for mobile-phone-based interventions in patients with psoriasis</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">405</infon><infon key="issue">6</infon><infon key="lpage">416</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Armstrong;given-names:AW</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Cheeney;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Wu;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Harskamp;given-names:CT</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Schupp;given-names:CW</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.2165/11634040-000000000-00000</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">23039257</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Am J Clin Dermatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">13</infon><infon key="year">2012</infon><offset>36046</offset><text>Harnessing the power of crowds: crowdsourcing as a novel research method for evaluation of acne treatments</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1153</infon><infon key="issue">10</infon><infon key="lpage">1155</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Armstrong;given-names:AW</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Harskamp;given-names:CT</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Cheeney;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Schupp;given-names:CW</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">23285714</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Drugs Dermatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">11</infon><infon key="year">2012</infon><offset>36153</offset><text>Crowdsourcing in eczema research: a novel method of data collection</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">15</infon><infon key="issue">3</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Armstrong;given-names:AW</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Harskamp;given-names:CT</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Cheeney;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Schupp;given-names:CW</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">22483526</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Dermatol Online J.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">18</infon><infon key="year">2012</infon><offset>36221</offset><text>Crowdsourcing for research data collection in rosacea</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>36275</offset><text>Armstrong AW, Wu J, Harskamp CT, Cheeney S, Schupp CW. Crowdsourcing for data collection: a pilot study comparing patient-reported experiences and clinical trial data for the treatment of seborrheic dermatitis. Skin Res Technol. 2013;19(1):55–7. 10.1111/j.1600-0846.2012.00667.x.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>36557</offset><text>PatientsLikeMe. https://www.patientslikeme.com/about. Accessed 6 Oct 2017.</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">20</infon><infon key="lpage">28</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:de la Loge;given-names:C</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Dimova;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Mueller;given-names:K</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.yebeh.2016.07.035</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Epilepsy Behav E&amp;B</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">63</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>36632</offset><text>PatientsLikeMe® Online Epilepsy Community: patient characteristics and predictors of poor health-related quality of life</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">e13</infon><infon key="issue">2</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Grajales;given-names:FJ;suffix:3rd</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Sheps;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Ho;given-names:K</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Novak-Lauscher;given-names:H</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Eysenbach;given-names:G</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.2196/jmir.2912</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">24518354</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Med Internet Res</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">16</infon><infon key="year">2014</infon><offset>36754</offset><text>Social media: a review and tutorial of applications in medicine and health care</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1414</infon><infon key="issue">12</infon><infon key="lpage">1416</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Capozza;given-names:K</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Shao;given-names:Y</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Zeng;given-names:Q</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1111/ijd.13359</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">27416358</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Int J Dermatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">55</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>36834</offset><text>“Crowdsourcing” a patient-centered research agenda for pediatric atopic dermatitis</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1273-81.e9</infon><infon key="issue">6</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Armstrong;given-names:AW</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Harskamp;given-names:CT</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Cheeney;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Wu;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Schupp;given-names:CW</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2012.05.013</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">22818792</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Am Acad Dermatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">67</infon><infon key="year">2012</infon><offset>36921</offset><text>Power of crowdsourcing: novel methods of data collection in psoriasis and psoriatic arthritis</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>37015</offset><text>Carmichael A RD. Cure Together. http://curetogether.com/. Accessed 6 Oct 2017.</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">393</infon><infon key="issue">2</infon><infon key="lpage">400</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Fleurence;given-names:R</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Selby;given-names:JV</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Odom-Walker;given-names:K</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1377/hlthaff.2012.1176</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Health Aff</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">32</infon><infon key="year">2013</infon><offset>37094</offset><text>How the Patient-Centered Outcomes Research Institute is engaging patients and others in shaping its research agenda</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">e34</infon><infon key="issue">3</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Eysenbach;given-names:G</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.2196/jmir.6.3.e34</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">15471760</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Med Internet Res</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">6</infon><infon key="year">2004</infon><offset>37210</offset><text>Improving the quality of Web surveys: the Checklist for Reporting Results of Internet E-Surveys (CHERRIES)</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">73</infon><infon key="issue">3</infon><infon key="lpage">80</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Afifi;given-names:L</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Shankle;given-names:L</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Armstrong;given-names:AW</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1177/247553031700200307</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">28825055</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Psoriasis Psoriatic Arthritis</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">2</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>37317</offset><text>National Psoriasis Foundation priorities for patient-centered research: proceedings from the 2016 conference</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">650-6.e3</infon><infon key="issue">4</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Egeberg;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Skov;given-names:L</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Joshi;given-names:AA</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2017.06.028</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">28826925</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Am Acad Dermatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">77</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>37426</offset><text>The relationship between duration of psoriasis, vascular inflammation, and cardiovascular events</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">347</infon><infon key="issue">2</infon><infon key="lpage">354</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Kremers;given-names:HM</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:McEvoy;given-names:MT</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Dann;given-names:FJ</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Gabriel;given-names:SE</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2007.02.007</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">17433490</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Am Acad Dermatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">57</infon><infon key="year">2007</infon><offset>37523</offset><text>Heart disease in psoriasis</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">40</infon><infon key="issue">1</infon><infon key="lpage">48</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Kim;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Choi;given-names:KH</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Hwang;given-names:SW</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Lee;given-names:YB</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Park;given-names:HJ</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Bae;given-names:JM</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2016.08.022</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">27793451</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Am Acad Dermatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">76</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>37550</offset><text>Inflammatory bowel disease is associated with an increased risk of inflammatory skin diseases: a population-based cross-sectional study</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">657907</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Bazso;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Szodoray;given-names:P</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Szappanos;given-names:A</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1155/2015/657907</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">26339139</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Mediators Inflamm</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">2015</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>37686</offset><text>Systemic autoimmune, rheumatic diseases and coinciding psoriasis: data from a large single-centre registry and review of the literature</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">924</infon><infon key="issue">5</infon><infon key="lpage">930</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Wu;given-names:JJ</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Nguyen;given-names:TU</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Poon;given-names:KY</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Herrinton;given-names:LJ</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2012.04.039</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">22664308</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Am Acad Dermatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">67</infon><infon key="year">2012</infon><offset>37822</offset><text>The association of psoriasis with autoimmune diseases</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">573</infon><infon key="issue">4</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Gelfand;given-names:JM</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Gladman;given-names:DD</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Mease;given-names:PJ</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2005.03.046</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">16198775</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Am Acad Dermatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">53</infon><infon key="year">2005</infon><offset>37876</offset><text>Epidemiology of psoriatic arthritis in the population of the United States</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1373</infon><infon key="issue">10</infon><infon key="lpage">1378</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Ibrahim;given-names:G</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Waxman;given-names:R</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Helliwell;given-names:PS</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1002/art.24608</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">19790120</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Arthritis Rheum</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">61</infon><infon key="year">2009</infon><offset>37951</offset><text>The prevalence of psoriatic arthritis in people with psoriasis</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">729</infon><infon key="issue">5</infon><infon key="lpage">735</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Mease;given-names:PJ</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Gladman;given-names:DD</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Papp;given-names:KA</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2013.07.023</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">23981683</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Am Acad Dermatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">69</infon><infon key="year">2013</infon><offset>38014</offset><text>Prevalence of rheumatologist-diagnosed psoriatic arthritis in patients with psoriasis in European/North American dermatology clinics</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">683</infon><infon key="issue">6</infon><infon key="lpage">691</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Radtke;given-names:MA</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Reich;given-names:K</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Blome;given-names:C</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Rustenbach;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Augustin;given-names:M</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1111/j.1468-3083.2009.03159.x</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">19309433</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">23</infon><infon key="year">2009</infon><offset>38147</offset><text>Prevalence and clinical features of psoriatic arthritis and joint complaints in 2009 patients with psoriasis: results of a German national survey</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1040</infon><infon key="issue">5</infon><infon key="lpage">1047</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Reich;given-names:K</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Kruger;given-names:K</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Mossner;given-names:R</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Augustin;given-names:M</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1111/j.1365-2133.2008.09023.x</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">19210498</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Br J Dermatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">160</infon><infon key="year">2009</infon><offset>38293</offset><text>Epidemiology and clinical pattern of psoriatic arthritis in Germany: a prospective interdisciplinary epidemiological study of 1511 patients with plaque-type psoriasis</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">377</infon><infon key="issue">2</infon><infon key="lpage">385</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Parisi;given-names:R</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Symmons;given-names:DP</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Griffiths;given-names:CE</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Ashcroft;given-names:DM</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1038/jid.2012.339</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">23014338</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Invest Dermatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">133</infon><infon key="year">2013</infon><offset>38460</offset><text>Global epidemiology of psoriasis: a systematic review of incidence and prevalence</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">25</infon><infon key="issue">1</infon><infon key="lpage">39</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Renahy;given-names:E</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Parizot;given-names:I</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Chauvin;given-names:P</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.3109/17538150903358784</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Informatics Health Social Care</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">35</infon><infon key="year">2010</infon><offset>38542</offset><text>Determinants of the frequency of online health information seeking: results of a Web-based survey conducted in France in 2007</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1205</infon><infon key="lpage">1211</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Jamal;given-names:AKB</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Neff;given-names:LJ</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Whitmill;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Babb;given-names:SD</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Graffunder;given-names:CM</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.15585/mmwr.mm6544a2</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Morb Mortal Wkly Rep</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">605</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>38668</offset><text>Current cigarette smoking among adults—United States, 2005–2015</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">402</infon><infon key="issue">5</infon><infon key="lpage">413</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Li;given-names:W</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Han;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Choi;given-names:HK</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Qureshi;given-names:AA</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1093/aje/kwr325</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">22247049</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Am J Epidemiol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">175</infon><infon key="year">2012</infon><offset>38736</offset><text>Smoking and risk of incident psoriasis among women and men in the United States: a combined analysis</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1053, e1–e16</infon><infon key="issue">6</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Murzaku;given-names:EC</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Bronsnick;given-names:T</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Rao;given-names:BK</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2014.08.019</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">25454037</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Am Acad Dermatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">71</infon><infon key="year">2014</infon><offset>38837</offset><text>Diet in dermatology: part II. Melanoma, chronic urticaria, and psoriasis</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1609</infon><infon key="issue">11</infon><infon key="lpage">1640</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Hasin;given-names:DS</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Grant;given-names:BF</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1007/s00127-015-1088-0</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">26210739</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Soc Psychiatry Psychiatr Epidemiol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">50</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>38910</offset><text>The National Epidemiologic Survey on Alcohol and Related Conditions (NESARC) Waves 1 and 2: review and summary of findings</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">586</infon><infon key="issue">3</infon><infon key="lpage">592</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Gladman;given-names:DD</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Anhorn;given-names:KA</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Schachter;given-names:RK</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Mervart;given-names:H</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">3735281</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Rheumatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">13</infon><infon key="year">1986</infon><offset>39033</offset><text>HLA antigens in psoriatic arthritis</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">556</infon><infon key="issue">3 Pt 1</infon><infon key="lpage">562</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Langan;given-names:SM</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Seminara;given-names:NM</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Shin;given-names:DB</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1038/jid.2011.365</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">22113483</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Invest Dermatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">132</infon><infon key="year">2012</infon><offset>39069</offset><text>Prevalence of metabolic syndrome in patients with psoriasis: a population-based study in the United Kingdom</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1173</infon><infon key="issue">10</infon><infon key="lpage">1179</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Yeung;given-names:H</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Takeshita;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Mehta;given-names:NN</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1001/jamadermatol.2013.5015</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">23925466</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">JAMA Dermatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">149</infon><infon key="year">2013</infon><offset>39177</offset><text>Psoriasis severity and the prevalence of major medical comorbidity: a population-based study</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">654</infon><infon key="issue">4</infon><infon key="lpage">662</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Armstrong;given-names:AW</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Harskamp;given-names:CT</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Armstrong;given-names:EJ</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2012.08.015</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">23360868</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Am Acad Dermatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">68</infon><infon key="year">2013</infon><offset>39270</offset><text>Psoriasis and metabolic syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis of observational studies</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">433</infon><infon key="issue">3</infon><infon key="lpage">442</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Armstrong;given-names:AW</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Harskamp;given-names:CT</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Armstrong;given-names:EJ</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1097/HJH.0b013e32835bcce1</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">23249828</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Hypertens</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">31</infon><infon key="year">2013</infon><offset>39367</offset><text>The association between psoriasis and hypertension: a systematic review and meta-analysis of observational studies</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">84</infon><infon key="issue">1</infon><infon key="lpage">91</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Armstrong;given-names:AW</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Harskamp;given-names:CT</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Armstrong;given-names:EJ</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1001/2013.jamadermatol.406</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">23407990</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">JAMA Dermatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">149</infon><infon key="year">2013</infon><offset>39482</offset><text>Psoriasis and the risk of diabetes mellitus: a systematic review and meta-analysis</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">419</infon><infon key="issue">4</infon><infon key="lpage">424</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Love;given-names:TJ</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Qureshi;given-names:AA</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Karlson;given-names:EW</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Gelfand;given-names:JM</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Choi;given-names:HK</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1001/archdermatol.2010.370</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">21173301</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Arch Dermatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">147</infon><infon key="year">2011</infon><offset>39565</offset><text>Prevalence of the metabolic syndrome in psoriasis: results from the National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey, 2003–2006</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">379</infon><infon key="issue">4</infon><infon key="lpage">382</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Qureshi;given-names:AA</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Choi;given-names:HK</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Setty;given-names:AR</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Curhan;given-names:GC</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1001/archdermatol.2009.48</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">19380659</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Arch Dermatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">145</infon><infon key="year">2009</infon><offset>39695</offset><text>Psoriasis and the risk of diabetes and hypertension: a prospective study of US female nurses</text></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Charlton;given-names:R</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Green;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Shaddick;given-names:G</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">29092855</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Ann Rheum Dis</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>39788</offset><text>Risk of uveitis and inflammatory bowel disease in people with psoriatic arthritis: a population-based cohort study</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1200</infon><infon key="issue">11</infon><infon key="lpage">1205</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Egeberg;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Khalid;given-names:U</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Gislason;given-names:GH</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Mallbris;given-names:L</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Skov;given-names:L</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Hansen;given-names:PR</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1001/jamadermatol.2015.1986</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">26222707</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">JAMA Dermatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">151</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>39903</offset><text>Association of psoriatic disease with uveitis: a Danish nationwide cohort study</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">486</infon><infon key="issue">5</infon><infon key="lpage">489</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Merola;given-names:JF</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Li;given-names:T</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Li;given-names:WQ</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Cho;given-names:E</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Qureshi;given-names:AA</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1111/ced.12805</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">26890045</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Clin Exp Dermatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">41</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>39983</offset><text>Prevalence of psoriasis phenotypes among men and women in the USA</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">979</infon><infon key="issue">6</infon><infon key="lpage">987</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Tollefson;given-names:MM</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Crowson;given-names:CS</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:McEvoy;given-names:MT</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Kremers Maradit;given-names:H</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2009.07.029</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">19962785</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Am Acad Dermatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">62</infon><infon key="year">2010</infon><offset>40049</offset><text>Incidence of psoriasis in children: a population-based study</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>40110</offset><text>Yeung H, Takeshita J, Fau-Mehta NN, et al. Psoriasis severity and the prevalence of major medical comorbidity: a population-based study. JAMA Dermatol. 2013;149(10):1173–9.10.1001/jamadermatol.2013.5015</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">733</infon><infon key="issue">5</infon><infon key="lpage">748</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Garg;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Gladman;given-names:D</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2010.02.061</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">20950737</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Am Acad Dermatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">63</infon><infon key="year">2010</infon><offset>40315</offset><text>Recognizing psoriatic arthritis in the dermatology clinic</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">777</infon><infon key="issue">5</infon><infon key="lpage">784</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Castelino;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Eyre;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Upton;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Ho;given-names:P</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Barton;given-names:A</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1093/rheumatology/ket319</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">24067887</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Rheumatology (Oxford)</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">53</infon><infon key="year">2014</infon><offset>40373</offset><text>The bacterial skin microbiome in psoriatic arthritis, an unexplored link in pathogenesis: challenges and opportunities offered by recent technological advances</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">258430</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Gunes;given-names:AT</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Fetil;given-names:E</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Akarsu;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Ozbagcivan;given-names:O</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Babayeva;given-names:L</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1155/2015/258430</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">26380315</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Immunol Res</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">2015</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>40533</offset><text>Possible triggering effect of influenza vaccination on psoriasis</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">672</infon><infon key="issue">5</infon><infon key="lpage">676</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Pattison;given-names:E</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Harrison;given-names:BJ</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Griffiths;given-names:CE</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Silman;given-names:AJ</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Bruce;given-names:IN</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1136/ard.2007.073932</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">17823200</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Ann Rheum Dis</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">67</infon><infon key="year">2008</infon><offset>40598</offset><text>Environmental risk factors for the development of psoriatic arthritis: results from a case-control study</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">491-9.e6</infon><infon key="issue">2</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Ruiz-Romeu;given-names:E</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Ferran;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Sagrista;given-names:M</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.jaci.2016.02.008</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">27056267</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Allergy Clin Immunol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">138</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>40703</offset><text>Streptococcus pyogenes-induced cutaneous lymphocyte antigen-positive T cell-dependent epidermal cell activation triggers TH17 responses in patients with guttate psoriasis</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">130</infon><infon key="issue">2</infon><infon key="lpage">135</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Sbidian;given-names:E</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Eftekahri;given-names:P</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Viguier;given-names:M</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1159/000362808</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">25171322</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Dermatology</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">229</infon><infon key="year">2014</infon><offset>40874</offset><text>National survey of psoriasis flares after 2009 monovalent H1N1/seasonal vaccines</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">756-8.e1</infon><infon key="issue">4</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Yan;given-names:D</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Afifi;given-names:L</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Jeon;given-names:C</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Cordoro;given-names:KM</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Liao;given-names:W</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2017.04.1109</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">28917456</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Am Acad Dermatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">77</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>40955</offset><text>A cross-sectional study of psoriasis triggers among different ethno-racial groups</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">555</infon><infon key="issue">8</infon><infon key="lpage">559</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Chua-Ty;given-names:G</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Goh;given-names:CL</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Koh;given-names:SL</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1111/j.1365-4362.1992.tb02717.x</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">1428445</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Int J Dermatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">31</infon><infon key="year">1992</infon><offset>41037</offset><text>Pattern of skin diseases at the National Skin Centre (Singapore) from 1989–1990</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">6</infon><infon key="issue">1</infon><infon key="lpage">11</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Hancox;given-names:JG</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Sheridan;given-names:SC</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Feldman;given-names:SR</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Fleischer;given-names:AB;suffix:Jr</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1111/j.1365-4632.2004.01828.x</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">14693014</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Int J Dermatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">43</infon><infon key="year">2004</infon><offset>41119</offset><text>Seasonal variation of dermatologic disease in the USA: a study of office visits from 1990 to 1998</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1115</infon><infon key="issue">10</infon><infon key="lpage">1118</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Harvell;given-names:JD</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Selig;given-names:DJ</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1111/ijd.13229</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">27061329</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Int J Dermatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">55</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>41217</offset><text>Seasonal variations in dermatologic and dermatopathologic diagnoses: a retrospective 15-year analysis of dermatopathologic data</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">e006450</infon><infon key="issue">1</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Kubota;given-names:K</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Kamijima;given-names:Y</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Sato;given-names:T</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2014-006450</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">25588781</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">BMJ Open</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">5</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>41345</offset><text>Epidemiology of psoriasis and palmoplantar pustulosis: a nationwide study using the Japanese national claims database</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">331</infon><infon key="issue">5</infon><infon key="lpage">335</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Nair;given-names:PA</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Diwan;given-names:NG</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Singhal;given-names:R</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Vora;given-names:RV</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.4103/idoj.IDOJ_308_16</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">28979865</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Indian Dermatol Online J</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">8</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>41463</offset><text>A prospective study of clinical profile in patients of palmoplantar dermatoses</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">523</infon><infon key="issue">3</infon><infon key="lpage">525</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Pascoe;given-names:VL</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Kimball;given-names:AB</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2015.06.001</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">26282801</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Am Acad Dermatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">73</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>41542</offset><text>Seasonal variation of acne and psoriasis: a 3-year study using the Physician Global Assessment severity scale</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1440</infon><infon key="issue">10</infon><infon key="lpage">1447</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Touma;given-names:Z</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Eder;given-names:L</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Zisman;given-names:D</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1002/acr.20530</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Arthritis Care Res</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">63</infon><infon key="year">2011</infon><offset>41652</offset><text>Seasonal variation in vitamin D levels in psoriatic arthritis patients from different latitudes and its association with clinical outcomes</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1370</infon><infon key="issue">8</infon><infon key="lpage">1373</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Touma;given-names:Z</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Thavaneswaran;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Chandran;given-names:V</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Gladman;given-names:DD</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1136/annrheumdis-2011-201208</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">22504562</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Ann Rheum Dis</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">71</infon><infon key="year">2012</infon><offset>41791</offset><text>Does the change in season affect disease activity in patients with psoriatic arthritis?</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">13</infon><infon key="lpage">30</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Watad;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Azrielant;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Bragazzi;given-names:NL</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.jaut.2017.06.001</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">28624334</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Autoimmun</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">82</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>41879</offset><text>Seasonality and autoimmune diseases: the contribution of the four seasons to the mosaic of autoimmunity</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">260</infon><infon key="issue">3</infon><infon key="lpage">264</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Wu;given-names:Y</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Lin;given-names:Y</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Liu;given-names:HJ</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Huang;given-names:CZ</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Feng;given-names:AP</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Li;given-names:JW</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1007/s12519-010-0213-0</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">20549408</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">World J Pediatr</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">6</infon><infon key="year">2010</infon><offset>41983</offset><text>Childhood psoriasis: a study of 137 cases from central China</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">228</infon><infon key="issue">2</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Patruno;given-names:C</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Ayala;given-names:F</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Megna;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Napolitano;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Balato;given-names:N</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">22421670</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Indian J Dermatol Venereol Leprol.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">78</infon><infon key="year">2012</infon><offset>42044</offset><text>Patient-physician relationship in patients with psoriasis</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">183</infon><infon key="issue">1</infon><infon key="lpage">186</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Feldman;given-names:SR</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Fleischer;given-names:AB;suffix:Jr</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Reboussin;given-names:DM</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1111/1523-1747.ep12329912</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">8592072</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Invest Dermatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">106</infon><infon key="year">1996</infon><offset>42102</offset><text>The self-administered psoriasis area and severity index is valid and reliable</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1210</infon><infon key="issue">5</infon><infon key="lpage">1221</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Kitchen;given-names:H</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Cordingley;given-names:L</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Young;given-names:H</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Griffiths;given-names:CE</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Bundy;given-names:C</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1111/bjd.13691</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">25677764</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Br J Dermatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">172</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>42180</offset><text>Patient-reported outcome measures in psoriasis: the good, the bad and the missing!</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">382</infon><infon key="issue">2</infon><infon key="lpage">383</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Feldman;given-names:SR</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Clark;given-names:AR</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Venkat;given-names:AP</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Fleischer;given-names:AB;suffix:Jr</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Anderson;given-names:RT</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Rajagopalan;given-names:R</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1111/j.1365-2133.2005.06351.x</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">15727666</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Br J Dermatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">152</infon><infon key="year">2005</infon><offset>42263</offset><text>The self-administered psoriasis area and severity index provides an objective measure of psoriasis severity</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">681</infon><infon key="issue">7</infon><infon key="lpage">689</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Candido Dos Reis;given-names:FJ</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Lynn;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Ali;given-names:HR</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.ebiom.2015.05.009</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">26288840</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">EBioMedicine</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">2</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>42371</offset><text>Crowdsourcing the general public for large scale molecular pathology studies in cancer</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>42458</offset><text>Arthritis Power: A Creakyjoints Initiative. https://arthritispower.creakyjoints.org. Accessed 6 Oct 2017.</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">e144</infon><infon key="issue">3</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Hattink;given-names:B</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Droes;given-names:RM</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Sikkes;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Oostra;given-names:E</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Lemstra;given-names:AW</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.2196/resprot.5040</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">27444209</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">JMIR Res Protoc</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">5</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>42564</offset><text>Evaluation of the Digital Alzheimer Center: testing usability and usefulness of an online portal for patients with dementia and their carers</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>42705</offset><text>American Heart Association. PCORI and AHA partner to identify critical research needed to improve care for cardiovascular diseases: new initiative will crowdsource to fill evidence gaps related to high-burden diseases. American Heart Association Newsroom. 2015. http://newsroom.heart.org/news/pcori-and-aha-partner-to-identify-critical-research-needed-to-improve-care-for-cardiovascular-diseases. Accessed 31 Aug 2017.</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">2501</infon><infon key="lpage">2517</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Kelman;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Robinson;given-names:CO</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Cochin;given-names:E</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.2147/PPA.S104396</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">28008236</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Patient Prefer Adherence</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">10</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>43124</offset><text>Communicating laboratory test results for rheumatoid factor: what do patients and physicians want?</text></passage></document></collection>
