<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd">
<collection><source>PMC</source><date>20201214</date><key>pmc.key</key><document><id>6519834</id><infon key="license">CC BY</infon><passage><infon key="alt-title">QDF for high-quality user replies and TFThs using CMs</infon><infon key="article-id_doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0215516</infon><infon key="article-id_pmc">6519834</infon><infon key="article-id_pmid">31091242</infon><infon key="article-id_publisher-id">PONE-D-18-15063</infon><infon key="elocation-id">e0215516</infon><infon key="issue">5</infon><infon key="license">This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Osman;given-names:Akram</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Salim;given-names:Naomie</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Saeed;given-names:Faisal</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Mumtaz;given-names:Wajid</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Salim;given-names:Naomie</infon><infon key="notes">Datasets can be downloaded from the following URL: https://osf.io/mqeza/?view_only=0b928f08bd00485fb21245ff2a300064 (DOI: 10.17605/OSF.IO/MQEZA).</infon><infon key="section_type">TITLE</infon><infon key="title">Data Availability</infon><infon key="type">front</infon><infon key="volume">14</infon><infon key="year">2019</infon><offset>0</offset><text>Quality dimensions features for identifying high-quality user replies in text forum threads using classification methods</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>121</offset><text>The Text Forum Threads (TFThs) contain a large amount of Initial-Posts Replies pairs (IPR pairs) which are related to information exchange and discussion amongst the forum users with similar interests. Generally, some user replies in the discussion thread are off-topic and irrelevant. Hence, the content is of different qualities. It is important to identify the quality of the IPR pairs in a discussion thread in order to extract relevant information and helpful replies because a higher frequency of irrelevant replies in the thread could take the discussion in a different direction and the genuine users would lose interest in this discussion thread. In this study, the authors have presented an approach for identifying the high-quality user replies to the Initial-Post and use some quality dimensions features for their extraction. Moreover, crowdsourcing platforms were used for judging the quality of the replies and classified them into high-quality, low-quality or non-quality replies to the Initial-Posts. Then, the high-quality IPR pairs were extracted and identified based on their quality, and they were ranked using three classifiers i.e., Support Vector Machine, Naïve Bayes, and the Decision Trees according to their quality dimensions of relevancy, author activeness, timeliness, ease-of-understanding, politeness, and amount-of-data. In conclusion, the experimental results for the TFThs showed that the proposed approach could improve the extraction of the quality replies and identify the quality features that can be used for the Text Forum Thread Summarization.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>1708</offset><text>Introduction</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>1721</offset><text>An increase in the web services has facilitated the manner in which people accessed and shared the knowledge in the form of User-Generated Content regarding specific subjects on the internet. The Text Forum Threads (TFThs) is the web service wherein the users can initiate discussions by posting Initial-Posts, asking for help and initiating conversations related to specific topics. Other users then read these Initial-Posts and reply accordingly. Hence, the Initial-Post generates many replies in a single thread. The Initial-Post along with its replies are compiled together in one thread. In this study, the authors have referred to the threads as Initial-Posts Replies pairs (IPR pairs). Fig 1 describes the manner in which every reply in the thread responds to the Initial-Posts on a particular topic. It can be seen that the discussion thread presented in the forum contains valuable information that is hidden in the forum texts. An effective use of this information in the User-Generated Content is an important topic of research in the field of thread retrieval. Determining important information in the text forums can become very difficult because of the information overloading.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">pone.0215516.g001.jpg</infon><infon key="id">pone.0215516.g001</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_title_caption</infon><offset>2913</offset><text>Structure of the text forum threads (Initial-post replies pairs).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>2979</offset><text>Additionally, the TFThs also have to face the heterogeneity of the content quality. Though the TFThs use monitoring processes for the user contents, it is impossible to monitor millions of text posts. The content from the TFThs is very comprehensive and more objective as compared to other search engines like Google (http://www.google.com) or Yahoo! (http://search.yahoo.com). One of the main challenges noted in the TFThs is that the quality of the text replies is distributed from irrelevant to relevant (high-quality) replies. This distribution is based on the user requirement and motivation, and diverse user backgrounds and the contents get published without undergoing any prior peer review process. Frequently posted irrelevant replies can affect the user’s impression about the TFThs. Thus, the user has to efficiently navigate through a huge repository of data to find the relevant information. Therefore, an automated assessment of the quality of the content in the TFThs is important. The quality of the content in the TFThs can be improved by distinguishing between the high-quality, low-quality and irrelevant replies. For this purpose, the authors have undertaken this classification task. In general, Quality Dimensions (QDs) are some common features that are applied for enhancing information and the thread retrieval. Many QDs features were used in this study for identifying the non-quality (irrelevant), low-quality (parity relevant) and high-quality (relevant) replies in the threads to their Initial-Posts. Additionally, the classification and the feature selection techniques were used for identifying appropriate features for the TFThs, which could help in achieving significant improvements in retrieval performance.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>4724</offset><text>The main objective of this study is to identify the quality features from the variety of quality dimensions that can help in classifying all the user replies to the Initial-Post in the TFThs. Furthermore, a survey on crowdsourcing platform community was conducted to judge the quality of each reply in the thread to Initial-Post.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>5054</offset><text>2.0 Background and related work</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>5086</offset><text>Identifying the quality features to extract quality replies to an Initial-Post in the TFThs can be difficult. Many studies have been carried out with regards to the issues seen in the TFThs. In this study, the authors have presented a literature review of the studies, which are directly related to this work.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>5396</offset><text>2.1 Textual features</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>5417</offset><text>One of the important text classification tasks includes the textual feature extraction. The feature extraction is conducted for extracting the important vocabulary words from all the textual data and representing them in an appropriate format that is needed by the machine learning algorithms for further data analysis. Some of the common textual features are the Term Frequency-Inverse Document Frequency (TF-IDF), Bag-of-Words (BoW), word n-grams, and the sentiment features. In the past several years, authors have applied several Machine-learning and statistical theory-based techniques for classifying the texts. Machine learning was seen to be a very popular computational method, which was used in many applications for an automated text classification. Some of these applications include the forum thread information extraction, post classification, thread retrieval, thread question-answer pair, product reviews, text summarisation, and forum summarisation. Usually, the machine-learning processes are used for determining the features which were helpful for classifying the text conversations. In this study, the authors have investigated the new TFTh classification features known as the Quality Dimensions (QDs) features.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>6651</offset><text>2.2 Quality dimensions features</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>6683</offset><text>The QDs features refer to the information quality which is vital for the data consumers. Retrieving the quality information in the TFThs is based on the user’s philosophical perspective, like the precise description of the topic, data exclusivity and important content. However, determining the information in the TFThs is complicated due to information overload. The TFThs consist of several thousand posts, which the users find to be time-consuming if they wish to browse or read through the thread. The QDs can measure the quality of each reply in the thread, which can then be used as an importance weighting for identifying the quality replies. It is essential to assess the content quality so that the good-quality content was given a higher weighting value than the low-quality content in the thread summarisation and retrieval systems. Many studies also indicated that controlling the content quality can significantly improve the performance of the functions included in the forums. For example, in, the authors stated that using a thread quality process could improve the thread retrieval. Also, in, the authors noted that the individuals using a social networking site in the TFThs Community could be a vital factor who improved the search precision regarding the quality replies in any thread. In another study, the authors proposed a model for evaluating the usage, reputation, content, temporal and structural features of the user-generated content in the TFThs for identifying the high-quality content. Furthermore, some authors also investigated the structural features along with the author activity features in a TFTh for determining the user knowledge-based adoption decisions (i.e., source credibility and argument quality. In, the authors have described four primary user features and used the aggregated post features for classifying the user expertise in all TFThs. In one study, the authors used quality features like the number of views and replies, which helped in developing a better forum crawler. Furthermore, in, the researchers studied two features which helped in developing the reply graph of the postings and evaluating the relevance of the posting compared to the initial topic. Some authors also aimed to understand the two thread activity features, i.e., decreasing volume of the active participants in the course and the deviation of the discussion, which did not in any way help the faculty members or students. In another study, the authors achieved the quality support in a stack overflowing discussion forum with the help of two features, i.e., the response time and the developer participation. In, the authors applied the relevancy dimension and the popularity dimension features for evaluating if the post was related to the topic of discussion or if the post was quoted or answered by other users in the thread. Some studies applied five feature classes, i.e., the lexical, syntactic, surface, forum specific and similarity features for assessing the forum post quality. On the other hand, the appropriateness of the lexical dimension features is not confirmed, since the thread postings of the web forum do not follow correct linguistic rules. One study also determined the linguistic features in various forum communities and noted that they were ineffective when they were investigated using automated quality assessment models since the models could not be adapted for the different writing styles or forum terminologies. In addition to the forum-related applications, some studies stated that quality features were also necessary for retrieving the web documents. Many studies indicated that leveraging the quality dimensions can significantly improve the forum summarisation and thread retrieval task. QDs were applied to various text content analytical tasks such as the thread retrieval, question-answer pairs in the TFThs, and product reviews etc. It must be noted that the QDs could improve the quality of all posts (replies) that were extracted from the discussion threads in the TFThs.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>10729</offset><text>2.3 Post retrieval</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>10748</offset><text>Several applications are based on the determination of relevant posts in the TFThs, like the post-retrieval in the online forums, question-answer pairs and the forum text summarisation. These applications are based on the basic concept that for any question or enquiry, there are several potential relevant posts, which differ in their ranking strategy or nature of the enquiry. In, the authors were able to extract the quality user replies using the knowledge of Chatbot from the online discussion forums. The authors identified all the replies that were relevant to the thread title using a Support Vector Machine (SVM) classifier and later ranked them with the SVM. In another study, the authors described a classification-based process to detect if the Initial-Post in the thread was a question and thereafter all the possible answers to the post were extracted from the replies to the thread. In, the author investigated methods for classifying posts based on a predicted quality label. The author used SVMs that were chosen for the classification and regression, because of their diversity, high fault tolerance, and generalizability from other problem domains. In, the authors proposed a system for assessing the quality of the forum posts based on the different discussion domains. This system used the SVM classification process which contained features like the lexical, syntactic, surface, forum specific and other similarity features. In, the automated categorisation of the online discussion posts was examined using three category sets, i.e., post topic, academic vs. general, and seek vs. contribute. Though these results were inconclusive, the authors stated that the performance of the process was satisfactory for monitoring the learning progress of the online educational discussion forums. In, the authors employed crowdsourcing to judge the quality of online forum threads based on some quality dimensions such as reliability, completeness, and usefulness of the information when people are searching for information. A task similar to the reply classification work carried out in this study was to identify the role played by every individual user message in the online discussion forums by. Here, the authors have aimed to identify the appropriateness of the replies to the inquiries asked in the Initial-Posts in the thread.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>13097</offset><text>2.4 Text forum thread summarization</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>13133</offset><text>The task of Text Forum Thread Summarization is aimed to provide a brief summary of the whole thread as users can find it difficult to read all the user replies in the thread and retrieve relevant information. The conventional text summarization processes are unable to determine the topic dependencies, scattered topics, drifting of the topics or the text sparseness and are plagued by such problems. In addition, several replies are in the form of short texts, written in an informal language and can contain no punctuations, capitalization, misspellings, grammatical errors, and use many non-standard abbreviations. The informal replies to a post can also be unreliable in comparison to the formal text like the news media. As per the survey conducted in a study,, many forum summarization studies considered the thread to a single document, combined all the Initial-Posts with their replies and thereafter the single document summarization approaches were applied to these documents. However, some other studies applied the multi-document summarization approaches after considering the Initial-Posts and their text replies as separate. Furthermore, some other studies applied the thread structural features. For example, in one study,, the authors exploited the explicit discourse structure in the discussion threads and thereafter applied the structural discourse relationship between the replies to generate a summary. In another study,, the authors observed that the interactions amongst the participants could be grouped as actions involved in seeking help and advice and providing an answer or advice. Rather than summarizing every reply, the summaries must be made for every post related to the post. Statistical methods like dialogue summarization can be very helpful. For example, in one study,, the author scored every reply in the discussion thread and selected the most significant replies in the summary. For this purpose, the authors suggested the application of several factors like uniqueness and length of the replies. Furthermore, the ‘term frequency’ was also added as a factor while scoring the replies. In, the authors stated that the issues related to the extraction of relevant replies from a discussion thread was a binary classification problem wherein the main task was to classify the replies and determine if they could/ could not be included in the final summary. In study,, the authors have established that it would be useful to train an extractive summarization model on a crowdsourced data of a similar model of an expert.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>15695</offset><text>Finally, it can be said that information retrieval in TFThs is a complex issue and discussions related to this issue is not present in the literature. There is a need to present novel quality features of TFThs, which can help in extracting relevant replies (high-quality) and then generating a better text summary.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>16010</offset><text>3.0 Methodology</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>16026</offset><text>In this study, a Classified Quality Initial-Post Replies Model (CQIPRM) is developed, which consists of five main components, as described in Fig 2. Details of every component is discussed as follows.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">pone.0215516.g002.jpg</infon><infon key="id">pone.0215516.g002</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_title_caption</infon><offset>16227</offset><text>A description of the classified quality initial-post replies model (CQIPRM).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>16304</offset><text>3.1 Data pre-processing</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>16328</offset><text>The initial component of data pre-processing of the threads (IPR pairs) is based on general discussion forums (https://www.tripadvisor.com.my/ShowForum-g28953-i4-New_York.html) and the official discussion forums (http://ubuntuforums.org). Every thread is analyzed with the help of conventional information retrieval processes like stop words removal, tokenization, and stemming, for extracting the terms for the indexing. The raw texts have to be pre-processed for representing them properly and using them effectively in all experiments.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>16867</offset><text>3.2 Quality dimensions features extraction</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>16910</offset><text>The replies were transformed into their QDs features for every IPR pairs using this component. Section 4 explains the way in which the features were extracted for every reply in the thread. Next, in order to increase the robustness of the overall classification process, the normalization process has been applied for all quality dimensions feature by giving a value between 0 and 1.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>17294</offset><text>3.3 Definition of initial-post replies pairs (IPR) quality</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>17353</offset><text>In this step, the CrowdFlower Platform (https://www.crowdflower.com/) was used for reading the raw texts and asked to judge the quality of the IPR pairs. The class labels were assigned for every IPR pairs as follows: the replies were labelled as “non-quality reply” if they were irrelevant to the Initial-Posts. They were labelled as “low-quality reply” when they were partially relevant to the Initial-Posts and were called as “high-quality” replies if they were completely relevant to the Initial-Posts. Thereafter, the final class labels for every reply were decided based on the trusted judgement for constructing a precise quality classifier. More details are provided in Section 5.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>18053</offset><text>3.4 Classification model construction</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>18091</offset><text>Here, the best QDs features for the IPR classification were determined using three classifier techniques. Thereafter, the training and the testing datasets were used in the suggested classification process for constructing the most accurate quality classifier. Further details are presented in Section 7.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>18396</offset><text>3.5 High-quality IPR pairs selection</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>18433</offset><text>Based on the results of the classification process, the authors selected the IPR pairs, which were categorised as “High-quality” replies.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>18575</offset><text>4.0 Description of the quality dimensions features</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>18626</offset><text>For understanding and evaluating the quality of the IPR pairs in the TFThs, the replies were classified into three categories. The authors used 28 different quality features, which were divided into six QDs like; relevancy (D1), author activeness (D2), timeliness (D3)) ease-of-understanding (D4), politeness (D5), and the amount-of-data (D6). Table 1 summarizes these QDs features, while Table 2 lists the QDs features formulas.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">pone.0215516.t001.xml</infon><infon key="id">pone.0215516.t001</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_title_caption</infon><offset>19056</offset><text>Quality dimensions features for the TFThs as the classification task.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">pone.0215516.t001.xml</infon><infon key="id">pone.0215516.t001</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table</infon><infon key="xml">&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;table frame=&quot;hsides&quot; rules=&quot;groups&quot;&gt;&lt;colgroup span=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; style=&quot;background-color:#BFBFBF&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;QDs&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; style=&quot;background-color:#BFBFBF&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Quality Features&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; style=&quot;background-color:#BFBFBF&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; style=&quot;background-color:#BFBFBF&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Code&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;10&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;D1&lt;break/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;The words in the reply overlap with the thread title&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Replies with words overlapping with the thread title are more relevant to the Initial-Posts.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;The words in the reply overlap with the Initial-Post.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Replies with words overlapping with the Initial-Posts are more relevant to the Initial-Posts.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Cosine similarity present between the replies and the thread title.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Replies with words having a higher similarity words with the thread title are more relevant to the Initial-Posts.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F3&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Cosine similarity present between the replies and the Initial-Posts.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Replies with words having a higher similarity words with the Initial-Posts are more relevant to the Initial-Posts.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Does the reply quote the previous posts?&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Replies which quote the Initial-Posts or previous replies are more relevant to the Initial-Posts.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F5&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;The centroid of the reply similar to the other replies in the thread.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Replies that have a high similarity score to the thread centroid vector are a better representation of the basic idea behind the Initial-Post.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;The reply overlaps the previous replies.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Replies with words overlapping with the other posts are irrelevant to the Initial-Post.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F7&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Does the reply mention the user-name of the person posting the Initial-Post?&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Replies which have mentioned the user-name of the person posting the Initial-Post are considered relevant.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Does the reply mention the names of other users?&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Replies which have mentioned the user-names of other people are considered irrelevant.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F9&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Does the reply have a URL?&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Replies with an URL are considered relevant.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F10&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;6&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;D2&lt;break/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Did the user post the Initial-Post?&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Replies given by the creator of the Initial-Post are relevant to the Initial-Post.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Total Number of the Initial-Posts created by the user in the threads.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;A high score indicates the user activeness and is relevant to the Initial-Post.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F12&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Total Number of replies given by the user in the current thread.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;A high score indicates the user activeness and is relevant to the Initial-Post.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F13&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Total Number of the replies given by the user in all the threads.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;A high score indicates the user activeness and is relevant to the Initial-Post.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F14&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Total Number of threads in which the user has participated.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;A high score indicates the user activeness and is relevant to the Initial-Post.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F15&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;The user’s reputation in all the threads.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;This feature determines the mean score of the user replies in all the threads. A high mean score indicates that the user is very important.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F16&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;4&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;D3&lt;break/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Measure the time elapsed between the Initial-Post and the current reply posted.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Age of a reply provides important insights into the relevance of the reply and whether it is still up-to-date. For instance, the replies could become outdated over a period of time, as the discussion in the thread progressed.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F17&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Measure the time elapsed between the posting of the previous and current replies, i.e., Absolute value.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Time elapsed between the posting of the previous and the current replies provides insights about the activeness of the thread. If there is a huge time difference between the replies, then the reply is inferred as inactive, and new replies would be irrelevant to the Initial-Post.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F18&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Measure the time elapsed between the posting of the current and the subsequent replies.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Time elapsed between the posting of the current and the subsequent replies provides insights about the activeness of the thread. A small time difference shows that the current reply has some value since it induces a timely response.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F19&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;The position of the text reply in the discussion thread.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Replies at the beginning of the discussion thread define the issue. Also, replies at the end of the discussion thread provide solutions which could be relevant to the Initial-Post.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F20&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;3&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;D4&lt;break/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Does the reply contain the WH question words?&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Replies containing the five 5Wh-Q words indicate inquiries or queries and are relevant to the Initial-Posts. The 5Wh-Q words are who, where, what, when, why, and how.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F21&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Does the reply contain a question mark (?)?&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Replies containing the question mark (?) indicate queries and are considered to be relevant to the Initial-Posts.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Does the reply contain an exclamation mark (!)?&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Replies containing the exclamation mark (!) reflect ambiguities and are considered relevant to the Initial-Post.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F23&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;2&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;D5&lt;break/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Does the reply contain words of positive feedback? &lt;underline&gt;Keywords:&lt;/underline&gt; Thanks, etc.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Replies containing words of positive feedback reflect the user satisfaction with the earlier replies responding to the Initial-Post and are considered relevant to the Initial-Post.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F24&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Does the reply contain words of negative feedback? &lt;underline&gt;Keywords:&lt;/underline&gt; does not, did not, etc.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Replies containing the negative feedback words reflect the user’s displeasure with the earlier replies responding to the Initial-Post and are considered as irrelevant to the Initial-Post.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F25&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;3&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;D6&lt;break/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Total numbers of words present in the reply&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Replies with a high number of words are considered more meaningful and are relevant to the Initial-Post.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F26&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Total numbers of unique words present in the reply.&lt;break/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;This feature estimates the amount of data present in the reply by counting the total number of unique words in the reply instead of the total words. High scores for the unique words indicate the relevance of the reply to the Initial-Post.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F27&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Total numbers of sentences present in the reply&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;This feature estimates the amount of data present in the reply by counting the total number of sentences in the reply. Replies with many sentences clarify the queries in the Initial-Post and are considered very relevant.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F28&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
</infon><offset>19126</offset><text>QDs	Quality Features	Description	Code	 	D1	The words in the reply overlap with the thread title	Replies with words overlapping with the thread title are more relevant to the Initial-Posts.	F1	 	The words in the reply overlap with the Initial-Post.	Replies with words overlapping with the Initial-Posts are more relevant to the Initial-Posts.	F2	 	Cosine similarity present between the replies and the thread title.	Replies with words having a higher similarity words with the thread title are more relevant to the Initial-Posts.	F3	 	Cosine similarity present between the replies and the Initial-Posts.	Replies with words having a higher similarity words with the Initial-Posts are more relevant to the Initial-Posts.	F4	 	Does the reply quote the previous posts?	Replies which quote the Initial-Posts or previous replies are more relevant to the Initial-Posts.	F5	 	The centroid of the reply similar to the other replies in the thread.	Replies that have a high similarity score to the thread centroid vector are a better representation of the basic idea behind the Initial-Post.	F6	 	The reply overlaps the previous replies.	Replies with words overlapping with the other posts are irrelevant to the Initial-Post.	F7	 	Does the reply mention the user-name of the person posting the Initial-Post?	Replies which have mentioned the user-name of the person posting the Initial-Post are considered relevant.	F8	 	Does the reply mention the names of other users?	Replies which have mentioned the user-names of other people are considered irrelevant.	F9	 	Does the reply have a URL?	Replies with an URL are considered relevant.	F10	 	D2	Did the user post the Initial-Post?	Replies given by the creator of the Initial-Post are relevant to the Initial-Post.	F11	 	Total Number of the Initial-Posts created by the user in the threads.	A high score indicates the user activeness and is relevant to the Initial-Post.	F12	 	Total Number of replies given by the user in the current thread.	A high score indicates the user activeness and is relevant to the Initial-Post.	F13	 	Total Number of the replies given by the user in all the threads.	A high score indicates the user activeness and is relevant to the Initial-Post.	F14	 	Total Number of threads in which the user has participated.	A high score indicates the user activeness and is relevant to the Initial-Post.	F15	 	The user’s reputation in all the threads.	This feature determines the mean score of the user replies in all the threads. A high mean score indicates that the user is very important.	F16	 	D3	Measure the time elapsed between the Initial-Post and the current reply posted.	Age of a reply provides important insights into the relevance of the reply and whether it is still up-to-date. For instance, the replies could become outdated over a period of time, as the discussion in the thread progressed.	F17	 	Measure the time elapsed between the posting of the previous and current replies, i.e., Absolute value.	Time elapsed between the posting of the previous and the current replies provides insights about the activeness of the thread. If there is a huge time difference between the replies, then the reply is inferred as inactive, and new replies would be irrelevant to the Initial-Post.	F18	 	Measure the time elapsed between the posting of the current and the subsequent replies.	Time elapsed between the posting of the current and the subsequent replies provides insights about the activeness of the thread. A small time difference shows that the current reply has some value since it induces a timely response.	F19	 	The position of the text reply in the discussion thread.	Replies at the beginning of the discussion thread define the issue. Also, replies at the end of the discussion thread provide solutions which could be relevant to the Initial-Post.	F20	 	D4	Does the reply contain the WH question words?	Replies containing the five 5Wh-Q words indicate inquiries or queries and are relevant to the Initial-Posts. The 5Wh-Q words are who, where, what, when, why, and how.	F21	 	Does the reply contain a question mark (?)?	Replies containing the question mark (?) indicate queries and are considered to be relevant to the Initial-Posts.	F22	 	Does the reply contain an exclamation mark (!)?	Replies containing the exclamation mark (!) reflect ambiguities and are considered relevant to the Initial-Post.	F23	 	D5	Does the reply contain words of positive feedback? Keywords: Thanks, etc.	Replies containing words of positive feedback reflect the user satisfaction with the earlier replies responding to the Initial-Post and are considered relevant to the Initial-Post.	F24	 	Does the reply contain words of negative feedback? Keywords: does not, did not, etc.	Replies containing the negative feedback words reflect the user’s displeasure with the earlier replies responding to the Initial-Post and are considered as irrelevant to the Initial-Post.	F25	 	D6	Total numbers of words present in the reply	Replies with a high number of words are considered more meaningful and are relevant to the Initial-Post.	F26	 	Total numbers of unique words present in the reply.	This feature estimates the amount of data present in the reply by counting the total number of unique words in the reply instead of the total words. High scores for the unique words indicate the relevance of the reply to the Initial-Post.	F27	 	Total numbers of sentences present in the reply	This feature estimates the amount of data present in the reply by counting the total number of sentences in the reply. Replies with many sentences clarify the queries in the Initial-Post and are considered very relevant.	F28	 	</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">pone.0215516.t002.xml</infon><infon key="id">pone.0215516.t002</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_title_caption</infon><offset>24781</offset><text>List of QDs features formula used in the TFThs process.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">pone.0215516.t002.xml</infon><infon key="id">pone.0215516.t002</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table</infon><infon key="xml">&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;table xmlns:xlink=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink&quot; xmlns:mml=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML&quot; frame=&quot;hsides&quot; rules=&quot;groups&quot;&gt;&lt;colgroup span=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; style=&quot;background-color:#BFBFBF&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;QDs&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; style=&quot;background-color:#BFBFBF&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Code&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; style=&quot;background-color:#BFBFBF&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Formula&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; style=&quot;background-color:#BFBFBF&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Description Symbols&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;10&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;D1&lt;break/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;pone.0215516.e001&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;graphic id=&quot;pone.0215516.e001g&quot; xlink:href=&quot;pone.0215516.e001&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M1&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;W&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;d&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;O&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;v&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;l&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;T&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;T&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;h&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;d&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;=&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mfrac&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;m&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;(&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;T&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;T&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;h&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;d&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;)&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;∩&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;m&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;(&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;)&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;m&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;(&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;)&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mfrac&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic&gt;Terms(TiThrd)&lt;/italic&gt; = the words in the title of thread.&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic&gt;Terms(Rei&lt;/italic&gt;) = the words in reply &lt;italic&gt;i&lt;/italic&gt;.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;pone.0215516.e002&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;graphic id=&quot;pone.0215516.e002g&quot; xlink:href=&quot;pone.0215516.e002&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M2&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;W&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;d&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;O&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;v&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;l&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;I&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;P&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;=&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mfrac&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;m&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;(&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;I&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;P&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;)&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;∩&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;m&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;(&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;)&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;m&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;(&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;)&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mfrac&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic&gt;Terms(IPst)&lt;/italic&gt; = the words in Initial-Post.&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic&gt;Terms(Rei&lt;/italic&gt;) = the words in reply &lt;italic&gt;i&lt;/italic&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F3&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;pone.0215516.e003&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;graphic id=&quot;pone.0215516.e003g&quot; xlink:href=&quot;pone.0215516.e003&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M3&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;C&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;n&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;S&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;m&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;l&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;T&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;T&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;h&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;d&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;=&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mfrac&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mo stretchy=&quot;false&quot;&gt;∑&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;T&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;T&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;h&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;d&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;.&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:msqrt&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mo stretchy=&quot;false&quot;&gt;∑&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:msup&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;(&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;T&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;T&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;h&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;d&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;)&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;2&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:msup&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:msqrt&gt;&lt;mml:msqrt&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mo stretchy=&quot;false&quot;&gt;∑&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:msup&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;(&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;)&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;2&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:msup&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:msqrt&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mfrac&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic&gt;Terms(TiThrd)&lt;/italic&gt; = the words in the title of thread.&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic&gt;Rei =&lt;/italic&gt; reply &lt;italic&gt;i&lt;/italic&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;pone.0215516.e004&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;graphic id=&quot;pone.0215516.e004g&quot; xlink:href=&quot;pone.0215516.e004&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M4&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;C&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;n&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;S&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;m&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;l&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;I&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;p&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;=&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mfrac&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mo stretchy=&quot;false&quot;&gt;∑&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;I&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;P&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;.&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:msqrt&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mo stretchy=&quot;false&quot;&gt;∑&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:msup&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;(&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;I&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;P&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;)&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;2&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:msup&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:msqrt&gt;&lt;mml:msqrt&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mo stretchy=&quot;false&quot;&gt;∑&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:msup&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;(&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;)&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;2&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:msup&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:msqrt&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mfrac&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic&gt;IPst&lt;/italic&gt; = Initial-Post.&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic&gt;Rei =&lt;/italic&gt; reply &lt;italic&gt;i&lt;/italic&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F5&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;pone.0215516.e005&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;graphic id=&quot;pone.0215516.e005g&quot; xlink:href=&quot;pone.0215516.e005&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M5&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;Q&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;u&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;P&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;=&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;{&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mtable columnalign=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mtr&gt;&lt;mml:mtd&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;1&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;mml:mspace width=&quot;2em&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;Q&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;u&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;=&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;m&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;I&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;p&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mtd&gt;&lt;/mml:mtr&gt;&lt;mml:mtr&gt;&lt;mml:mtd&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;0&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;mml:mspace width=&quot;5em&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;o&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;h&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;w&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mtd&gt;&lt;/mml:mtr&gt;&lt;/mml:mtable&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic&gt;ReQu&lt;/italic&gt; = words quoted by the reply&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic&gt;termsPst&lt;/italic&gt; = Posts words&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;pone.0215516.e006&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;graphic id=&quot;pone.0215516.e006g&quot; xlink:href=&quot;pone.0215516.e006&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M6&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;C&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;n&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;T&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;o&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;=&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mstyle displaystyle=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:munderover&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;∑&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;=&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;1&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;n&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:munderover&gt;&lt;/mml:mstyle&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mfrac&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;n&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mfrac&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic&gt;i =&lt;/italic&gt; the order of replies, &lt;italic&gt;Rei =&lt;/italic&gt; reply &lt;italic&gt;i&lt;/italic&gt;&lt;break/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F7&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;pone.0215516.e007&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;graphic id=&quot;pone.0215516.e007g&quot; xlink:href=&quot;pone.0215516.e007&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M7&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;O&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;v&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;l&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;P&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;=&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mfrac&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;m&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;(&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;)&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;∩&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;m&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;(&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;P&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;)&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;m&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;(&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;P&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;)&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mfrac&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic&gt;Terms(PrRei&lt;/italic&gt;) = the words in previous replies.&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic&gt;Terms(Rei&lt;/italic&gt;) = the words in reply &lt;italic&gt;i&lt;/italic&gt;.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;pone.0215516.e008&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;graphic id=&quot;pone.0215516.e008g&quot; xlink:href=&quot;pone.0215516.e008&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M8&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;M&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;I&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;P&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;=&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;{&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mtable columnalign=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mtr&gt;&lt;mml:mtd&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;1&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;mml:mspace width=&quot;2em&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;=&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;I&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;P&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;C&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mtd&gt;&lt;/mml:mtr&gt;&lt;mml:mtr&gt;&lt;mml:mtd&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;0&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;mml:mspace width=&quot;4em&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;o&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;h&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;w&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mtd&gt;&lt;/mml:mtr&gt;&lt;/mml:mtable&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic&gt;Rei =&lt;/italic&gt; reply &lt;italic&gt;i&lt;/italic&gt;&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic&gt;IPstCrtr&lt;/italic&gt; = name of the Initial-Post creator&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F9&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;pone.0215516.e009&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;graphic id=&quot;pone.0215516.e009g&quot; xlink:href=&quot;pone.0215516.e009&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M9&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;M&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;=&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;{&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mtable columnalign=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mtr&gt;&lt;mml:mtd&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;−&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;1&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;mml:mspace width=&quot;2em&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;j&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;M&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;=&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;C&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mtd&gt;&lt;/mml:mtr&gt;&lt;mml:mtr&gt;&lt;mml:mtd&gt;&lt;mml:mspace width=&quot;0.50em&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;0&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;mml:mspace width=&quot;5em&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;o&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;h&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;w&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mtd&gt;&lt;/mml:mtr&gt;&lt;/mml:mtable&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic&gt;RejMe = current reply j&lt;/italic&gt;&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic&gt;ReiCrtr&lt;/italic&gt; = name of creator reply &lt;italic&gt;i&lt;/italic&gt;.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F10&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;pone.0215516.e010&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;graphic id=&quot;pone.0215516.e010g&quot; xlink:href=&quot;pone.0215516.e010&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M10&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;U&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;l&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;=&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;{&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mtable columnalign=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mtr&gt;&lt;mml:mtd&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;1&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;mml:mspace width=&quot;2em&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;U&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;L&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;∈&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mtd&gt;&lt;/mml:mtr&gt;&lt;mml:mtr&gt;&lt;mml:mtd&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;0&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;mml:mspace width=&quot;1.75em&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;o&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;h&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;w&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mtd&gt;&lt;/mml:mtr&gt;&lt;/mml:mtable&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic&gt;URL =&lt;/italic&gt; Website link in the reply&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;6&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;D2&lt;break/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;pone.0215516.e011&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;graphic id=&quot;pone.0215516.e011g&quot; xlink:href=&quot;pone.0215516.e011&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M11&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;U&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;I&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;p&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;=&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;{&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mtable columnalign=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mtr&gt;&lt;mml:mtd&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;U&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;=&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;P&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;C&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mspace width=&quot;2em&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;1&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mtd&gt;&lt;/mml:mtr&gt;&lt;mml:mtr&gt;&lt;mml:mtd&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;U&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;P&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;C&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mspace width=&quot;0.75em&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;0&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mtd&gt;&lt;/mml:mtr&gt;&lt;/mml:mtable&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic&gt;UrRei =&lt;/italic&gt; reply i creates by user.&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic&gt;iPstCrtr =&lt;/italic&gt; name of users created Initial-Posts.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F12&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;pone.0215516.e012&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;graphic id=&quot;pone.0215516.e012g&quot; xlink:href=&quot;pone.0215516.e012&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M12&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;N&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;u&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;m&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;I&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;P&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;B&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;y&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;U&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;=&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;{&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mtable columnalign=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mtr&gt;&lt;mml:mtd&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;U&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;=&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;P&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;C&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mspace width=&quot;1.75em&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;1&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;mml:mspace width=&quot;1em&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;P&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;=&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;P&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;+&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;1&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mtd&gt;&lt;/mml:mtr&gt;&lt;mml:mtr&gt;&lt;mml:mtd&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;U&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;P&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;C&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mspace width=&quot;0.50em&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;0&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;mml:mspace width=&quot;1em&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;c&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;o&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;n&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;n&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;u&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mtd&gt;&lt;/mml:mtr&gt;&lt;/mml:mtable&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic&gt;UrRei =&lt;/italic&gt; reply i creates by user.&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic&gt;iPstCrtr =&lt;/italic&gt; name of users created Initial-Posts.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F13&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;pone.0215516.e013&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;graphic id=&quot;pone.0215516.e013g&quot; xlink:href=&quot;pone.0215516.e013&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M13&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;N&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;u&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;m&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;B&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;y&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;U&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;T&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;h&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;d&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;=&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;{&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mtable columnalign=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mtr&gt;&lt;mml:mtd&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;U&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;=&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;U&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;C&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mspace width=&quot;2em&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;1&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;mml:mspace width=&quot;1em&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;=&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;+&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;1&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mtd&gt;&lt;/mml:mtr&gt;&lt;mml:mtr&gt;&lt;mml:mtd&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;U&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;U&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;C&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mspace width=&quot;1.00em&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;0&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;mml:mspace width=&quot;1em&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;c&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;o&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;n&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;n&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;u&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mtd&gt;&lt;/mml:mtr&gt;&lt;/mml:mtable&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic&gt;UrRei =&lt;/italic&gt; reply creates by user.&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic&gt;UrCrtr =&lt;/italic&gt; name of users in the thread.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F14&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;pone.0215516.e014&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;graphic id=&quot;pone.0215516.e014g&quot; xlink:href=&quot;pone.0215516.e014&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M14&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;S&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;u&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;m&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;A&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;l&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;l&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;p&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;l&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;y&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;B&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;y&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;U&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;=&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mstyle displaystyle=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:munderover&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;∑&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;T&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;=&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;1&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;M&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:munderover&gt;&lt;/mml:mstyle&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mstyle displaystyle=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:munderover&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;∑&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;=&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;1&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;N&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:munderover&gt;&lt;/mml:mstyle&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;N&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;o&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic&gt;R =&lt;/italic&gt; replies, &lt;italic&gt;T =&lt;/italic&gt; threads&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic&gt;NoRei&lt;/italic&gt; = number of replies created by user&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F15&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;pone.0215516.e015&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;graphic id=&quot;pone.0215516.e015g&quot; xlink:href=&quot;pone.0215516.e015&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M15&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;N&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;o&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;T&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;d&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;P&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;p&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;=&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mstyle displaystyle=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:munderover&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;∑&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;T&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;=&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;1&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;M&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:munderover&gt;&lt;/mml:mstyle&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mstyle displaystyle=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:munderover&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;∑&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;=&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;1&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;N&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:munderover&gt;&lt;/mml:mstyle&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;T&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;h&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;d&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;P&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic&gt;R =&lt;/italic&gt; replies, &lt;italic&gt;T =&lt;/italic&gt; threads&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic&gt;ThrdPrti&lt;/italic&gt; = the number of threads participated by each user.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F16&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;pone.0215516.e016&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;graphic id=&quot;pone.0215516.e016g&quot; xlink:href=&quot;pone.0215516.e016&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M16&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;A&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;=&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mfrac&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:msubsup&gt;&lt;mml:mo stretchy=&quot;false&quot;&gt;∑&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;U&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;=&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;1&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;n&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:msubsup&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;U&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;p&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;l&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;y&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;−&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:msubsup&gt;&lt;mml:mo stretchy=&quot;false&quot;&gt;∑&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;I&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;P&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;=&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;1&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;m&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:msubsup&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;U&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;I&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;P&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:msubsup&gt;&lt;mml:mo stretchy=&quot;false&quot;&gt;∑&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;=&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;1&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;k&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:msubsup&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;A&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;l&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;l&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;p&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;l&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;y&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mfrac&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic&gt;UsrRply&lt;/italic&gt; = number of replies by user in the threads.&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic&gt;UsrIP&lt;/italic&gt; = number of Initial-Posts by user in the threads.&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic&gt;AllRly&lt;/italic&gt; = number of all replies in the threads.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;4&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;D3&lt;break/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F17&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic&gt;TimToIpst = ReiTim–IPstTim&lt;/italic&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic&gt;ReiTim =&lt;/italic&gt; Reply Date&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic&gt;IPstTim =&lt;/italic&gt; Initial-Post date&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F18&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;pone.0215516.e017&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;graphic id=&quot;pone.0215516.e017g&quot; xlink:href=&quot;pone.0215516.e017&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M17&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;T&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;m&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;T&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;o&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;P&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;v&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;P&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;=&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;{&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mtable columnalign=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mtr&gt;&lt;mml:mtd&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;T&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;m&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;−&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;P&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;T&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;m&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mspace width=&quot;0.50em&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;P&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;≠&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;n&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;u&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;l&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;l&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mtd&gt;&lt;/mml:mtr&gt;&lt;mml:mtr&gt;&lt;mml:mtd&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;0&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;mml:mspace width=&quot;10.5em&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;o&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;h&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;w&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mtd&gt;&lt;/mml:mtr&gt;&lt;/mml:mtable&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic&gt;ReiTim =&lt;/italic&gt; Reply Date&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic&gt;PreReiTim&lt;/italic&gt; = previous reply date&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F19&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;pone.0215516.e018&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;graphic id=&quot;pone.0215516.e018g&quot; xlink:href=&quot;pone.0215516.e018&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M18&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;T&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;m&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;T&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;o&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;P&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;v&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;P&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;=&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;{&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mtable columnalign=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mtr&gt;&lt;mml:mtd&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;T&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;m&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;−&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;N&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;x&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;T&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;m&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mspace width=&quot;0.50em&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;N&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;x&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;≠&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;n&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;u&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;l&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;l&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mtd&gt;&lt;/mml:mtr&gt;&lt;mml:mtr&gt;&lt;mml:mtd&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;0&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;mml:mspace width=&quot;10.25em&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;o&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;h&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;w&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mtd&gt;&lt;/mml:mtr&gt;&lt;/mml:mtable&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic&gt;ReiTim =&lt;/italic&gt; Reply Date&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic&gt;NxtRei&lt;/italic&gt; = Next reply date&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F20&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;pone.0215516.e019&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;graphic id=&quot;pone.0215516.e019g&quot; xlink:href=&quot;pone.0215516.e019&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M19&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;P&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;o&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;o&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;n&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;=&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mfrac&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:msubsup&gt;&lt;mml:mo stretchy=&quot;false&quot;&gt;∑&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;=&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;1&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;n&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:msubsup&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;N&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;o&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mfrac&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic&gt;Rei =&lt;/italic&gt; Position of reply.&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic&gt;NoRei&lt;/italic&gt; = Number of replies in the thread.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;3&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;D4&lt;break/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F21&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;pone.0215516.e020&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;graphic id=&quot;pone.0215516.e020g&quot; xlink:href=&quot;pone.0215516.e020&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M20&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;W&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;h&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;Q&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;u&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;=&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;{&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mtable&gt;&lt;mml:mtr&gt;&lt;mml:mtd&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;1&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;mml:mspace width=&quot;2em&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;W&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;h&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;Q&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;∈&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mtd&gt;&lt;/mml:mtr&gt;&lt;mml:mtr&gt;&lt;mml:mtd&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;0&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;mml:mspace width=&quot;2em&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;o&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;h&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;w&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mtd&gt;&lt;/mml:mtr&gt;&lt;/mml:mtable&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic&gt;Rei =&lt;/italic&gt; reply &lt;italic&gt;i&lt;/italic&gt;&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic&gt;WhQ = 5WH-Q words (&lt;/italic&gt;what, where, when, why, who, how&lt;italic&gt;)&lt;/italic&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;pone.0215516.e021&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;graphic id=&quot;pone.0215516.e021g&quot; xlink:href=&quot;pone.0215516.e021&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M21&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;Q&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;u&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;M&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;a&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;k&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;=&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;{&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mtable columnalign=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mtr&gt;&lt;mml:mtd&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;1&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;mml:mspace width=&quot;2em&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;Q&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;u&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;M&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;a&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;k&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;∈&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mtd&gt;&lt;/mml:mtr&gt;&lt;mml:mtr&gt;&lt;mml:mtd&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;0&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;mml:mspace width=&quot;3.5em&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;o&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;h&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;w&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mtd&gt;&lt;/mml:mtr&gt;&lt;/mml:mtable&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic&gt;Rei =&lt;/italic&gt; reply i&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic&gt;QuMarks =&lt;/italic&gt; question mark (?)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F23&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;pone.0215516.e022&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;graphic id=&quot;pone.0215516.e022g&quot; xlink:href=&quot;pone.0215516.e022&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M22&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;E&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;x&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;M&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;a&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;k&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;=&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;{&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mtable columnalign=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mtr&gt;&lt;mml:mtd&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;1&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;mml:mspace width=&quot;2em&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;E&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;x&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;M&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;a&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;k&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;∈&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mtd&gt;&lt;/mml:mtr&gt;&lt;mml:mtr&gt;&lt;mml:mtd&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;0&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;mml:mspace width=&quot;3.5em&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;o&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;h&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;w&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mtd&gt;&lt;/mml:mtr&gt;&lt;/mml:mtable&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic&gt;Rei =&lt;/italic&gt; reply i&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic&gt;ExMarks =&lt;/italic&gt; exclamation marks (!)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;2&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;D5&lt;break/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F24&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;pone.0215516.e023&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;graphic id=&quot;pone.0215516.e023g&quot; xlink:href=&quot;pone.0215516.e023&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M23&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;P&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;o&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;W&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;d&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;=&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;{&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mtable columnalign=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mtr&gt;&lt;mml:mtd&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;1&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;mml:mspace width=&quot;2em&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;P&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;o&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;W&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;d&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;∈&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mtd&gt;&lt;/mml:mtr&gt;&lt;mml:mtr&gt;&lt;mml:mtd&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;0&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;mml:mspace width=&quot;4em&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;o&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;h&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;w&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mtd&gt;&lt;/mml:mtr&gt;&lt;/mml:mtable&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic&gt;Rei =&lt;/italic&gt; reply i&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic&gt;PosWrdRei =&lt;/italic&gt; positive feedback words&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F25&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;pone.0215516.e024&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;graphic id=&quot;pone.0215516.e024g&quot; xlink:href=&quot;pone.0215516.e024&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M24&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;N&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;g&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;W&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;d&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;=&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;{&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mtable columnalign=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mtr&gt;&lt;mml:mtd&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;1&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;mml:mspace width=&quot;2em&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;N&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;g&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;W&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;d&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;∈&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mtd&gt;&lt;/mml:mtr&gt;&lt;mml:mtr&gt;&lt;mml:mtd&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;0&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;mml:mspace width=&quot;4.5em&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;o&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;h&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;w&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mtd&gt;&lt;/mml:mtr&gt;&lt;/mml:mtable&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic&gt;Rei =&lt;/italic&gt; reply i&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic&gt;NegWrdRei&lt;/italic&gt; = negative feedback words&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;3&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;D6&lt;break/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F26&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;pone.0215516.e025&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;graphic id=&quot;pone.0215516.e025g&quot; xlink:href=&quot;pone.0215516.e025&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M25&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;N&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;o&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;W&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;d&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;=&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mstyle displaystyle=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:munderover&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;∑&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;w&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;=&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;1&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;n&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:munderover&gt;&lt;/mml:mstyle&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;W&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;d&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;T&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;x&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic&gt;w&lt;/italic&gt; = order of words in a reply&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic&gt;WrdTxt&lt;/italic&gt; = Number of words in a reply&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F27&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;pone.0215516.e026&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;graphic id=&quot;pone.0215516.e026g&quot; xlink:href=&quot;pone.0215516.e026&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M26&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;N&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;o&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;U&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;n&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;W&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;d&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;=&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mstyle displaystyle=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:munderover&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;∑&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;u&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;w&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;=&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;1&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;n&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:munderover&gt;&lt;/mml:mstyle&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;U&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;n&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;W&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;d&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;T&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;x&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic&gt;uw&lt;/italic&gt; = order of unique words in a reply&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic&gt;UnWrdTxt&lt;/italic&gt; = Number of unique words in a reply&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F28&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;pone.0215516.e027&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;graphic id=&quot;pone.0215516.e027g&quot; xlink:href=&quot;pone.0215516.e027&quot;/&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M27&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;N&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;o&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;S&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;n&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;=&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mstyle displaystyle=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:munderover&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;∑&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;=&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;1&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;n&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:munderover&gt;&lt;/mml:mstyle&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;S&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;n&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;T&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;x&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic&gt;se&lt;/italic&gt; = order of sentences in a reply&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic&gt;SentTxt&lt;/italic&gt; = Number of sentences in a reply.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
</infon><offset>24837</offset><text>QDs	Code	Formula	Description Symbols	 	D1	F1		Terms(TiThrd) = the words in the title of thread.Terms(Rei) = the words in reply i.	 	F2		Terms(IPst) = the words in Initial-Post.Terms(Rei) = the words in reply i	 	F3		Terms(TiThrd) = the words in the title of thread.Rei = reply i	 	F4		IPst = Initial-Post.Rei = reply i	 	F5		ReQu = words quoted by the replytermsPst = Posts words	 	F6		i = the order of replies, Rei = reply i	 	F7		Terms(PrRei) = the words in previous replies.Terms(Rei) = the words in reply i.	 	F8		Rei = reply iIPstCrtr = name of the Initial-Post creator	 	F9		RejMe = current reply jReiCrtr = name of creator reply i.	 	F10		URL = Website link in the reply	 	D2	F11		UrRei = reply i creates by user.iPstCrtr = name of users created Initial-Posts.	 	F12		UrRei = reply i creates by user.iPstCrtr = name of users created Initial-Posts.	 	F13		UrRei = reply creates by user.UrCrtr = name of users in the thread.	 	F14		R = replies, T = threadsNoRei = number of replies created by user	 	F15		R = replies, T = threadsThrdPrti = the number of threads participated by each user.	 	F16		UsrRply = number of replies by user in the threads.UsrIP = number of Initial-Posts by user in the threads.AllRly = number of all replies in the threads.	 	D3	F17	TimToIpst = ReiTim–IPstTim	ReiTim = Reply DateIPstTim = Initial-Post date	 	F18		ReiTim = Reply DatePreReiTim = previous reply date	 	F19		ReiTim = Reply DateNxtRei = Next reply date	 	F20		Rei = Position of reply.NoRei = Number of replies in the thread.	 	D4	F21		Rei = reply iWhQ = 5WH-Q words (what, where, when, why, who, how)	 	F22		Rei = reply iQuMarks = question mark (?)	 	F23		Rei = reply iExMarks = exclamation marks (!)	 	D5	F24		Rei = reply iPosWrdRei = positive feedback words	 	F25		Rei = reply iNegWrdRei = negative feedback words	 	D6	F26		w = order of words in a replyWrdTxt = Number of words in a reply	 	F27		uw = order of unique words in a replyUnWrdTxt = Number of unique words in a reply	 	F28		se = order of sentences in a replySentTxt = Number of sentences in a reply.	 	</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>26898</offset><text>The main motivation for using the QDs features for the IPR pairs was described in Table 1, in the following sub-sections.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>27020</offset><text>4.1 Relevancy dimension (D1)</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>27049</offset><text>This is a very important dimension, which builds the user perception about the relevancy of the reply given to an Initial-Post. The relevance of the reply reflects its suitability to the post. High-quality replies must have similarities and contain overlapping words to the Initial-Post. However, the irrelevant and off-topic replies show a low similarity score. Moreover, if the reply quotes the earlier replies or the username of the person posting the Initial-Post, it indicates that the reply is in direct response to the problems mentioned in the Initial-Post. In addition, replies with an URL are considered very relevant. Table 1 summarizes all quality features addressed by the relevancy dimension.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>27756</offset><text>4.2 Author activeness dimension (D2)</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>27793</offset><text>The contributions of many authors (participants) in the thread generate a significant source of new ideas, which can improve the quality of the content for all the user replies. The D2 features focus more on assessing the activities and the contribution of the authors in responding to the Initial-Post. An active author has a wide experience. When the author interacts with the person, who has posted the Initial-Post that would increase the trust between them. However, in the case the author interacting with other authors in the discussion thread, it has a negative effect because it often leads to deviation from the original topic in the Initial-Post and provokes a new discussion or a new topic unrelated to the inquiry (issue) raised in the Initial-Post. The activities of the authors indicate their involvement and commitment to the issue raised in the Initial-Post of each thread. Furthermore, the credibility of the authors is measured by assessing the amount of personal information provided by them. The authors are accountable to their replies and content that they created. Table 1 presents the features addressed by the author activeness dimension.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>28958</offset><text>4.3 Timeliness dimension (D3)</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>28988</offset><text>The D3 dimension quantifies the timeliness of the reply by assessing the reply age. The time between the IPR pairs indicates if the replies are still relevant and up-to-date. Furthermore, the temporal feature of the thread reflects the relevancy of the user replies to the Initial-Post based on its age. The timeliness is measured by the reply position in the thread compared to other user replies. These features determine the visibility of any reply (whether it is displayed on the first page of the discussion thread). Table 1 summarizes the features included in the timeliness dimension.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>29580</offset><text>4.4 Ease-of-understanding dimension (D4)</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>29621</offset><text>The D4 dimension evaluates if the contents of the reply to the Initial-Post can be understood easily. The features addressed by this dimension help in determining the types of the question and answer the replies. A higher number of replies containing the Wh-Qs or question marks show that the issue raised in the Initial-Post needs more clarification from the Initial-Post creator. This also indicates that the replier needs further details if the issue raised in the Initial-Post needs to be resolved completely. For example, “Do you want to stay in any particular part of Rochester? Downtown? Suburbs?” (https://www.tripadvisor.com.my/ShowTopic-g48503-i903-k1986305-Best_area_to_stay_for_nightlife-Rochester_Finger_Lakes_New_York.html). On receiving additional details, any user who has knowledge could provide a possible answer or valid response to this issue raised in the Initial-Post. It might suggest a solution and share his experience in the next reply. Hence, replies consisting of any one of the 5Wh-Qs are seen to be relevant and important for the Initial Post. All the features assessed by the ease-of-understanding dimension have been presented in Table 1.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>30796</offset><text>4.5 Politeness dimension (D5)</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>30826</offset><text>The D5 dimension measures the user politeness while expressing opinions, responding, and while addressing other replies. This feature helps in determining the words of appreciation or denial used in the user replies. For example, replies with words like &quot;This worked!&quot; or &quot;Thank you&quot; reflect the user politeness as they are appreciative. This would also help others to determine if the replies were relevant. Table 1 summarizes the features used by the politeness dimension.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>31301</offset><text>4.6 Amount-of-data dimension (D6)</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>31335</offset><text>The D6 dimension estimates the quantity of the information provided in the user replies. It measures the word count in the replies as it shows a degree of the user participation. It is also seen that replies with high word count provide a sufficient amount of knowledge and contain productive discussion matter, and were relevant to the Initial-Post. Table 1 presents the features addressed by the amount-of-data dimension.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>31759</offset><text>5.0 Human judgment</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>31778</offset><text>A classification of the user replies based on their response to the Initial-Posts could be helpful in the TFThs. In this study, the researchers have described the manner in which the reply classification information is used in the TFThs system. They have incorporated the class label information about the replies in the dataset for determining if it improved the TFThs system. Based on the human judgments, the replies are classified into three classes, i.e., to evaluate each reply in the thread, i.e., non-quality, low-quality, and high-quality replies. In Table 3, the authors have presented an example of the discussion thread containing an Initial-Post and replies with the class Labels, which were represented by the nominal values. The class labels display the information below:</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>32566</offset><text>The High-quality Replies were completely relevant and provide a good response to the Initial-Post. They were trustworthy, informative and fact-based.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>32716</offset><text>The Low-quality Replies were partially relevant and provided satisfactory responses to the Initial-Post. The replies were sensible and provided some information.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>32878</offset><text>The Non-quality Replies were completely irrelevant, subjective and uninformative and provided no useful knowledge in response to the Initial-Post.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>33025</offset><text>In Table 3 is mentioned below, Rows 1 and 2 consist of the title and Initial-Post and provide a context for the discussion thread. They were not a target class. The Table consists of a discussion thread (https://www.tripadvisor.com.my/ShowTopic-g60763-i5-k3128263-How_to_get_from_JFK_to_New_Rochelle-New_York_City_New_York.html) where every reply is labelled with a proper class label. The three classes were used for judging the quality of the user replies in the TFThs. The authors studied 100 threads, including the user replies for the 100 Initial-Posts along with their respective class labels.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">pone.0215516.t003.xml</infon><infon key="id">pone.0215516.t003</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_title_caption</infon><offset>33625</offset><text>An Example of the discussion thread containing class labels for the IPR pairs.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">pone.0215516.t003.xml</infon><infon key="id">pone.0215516.t003</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table</infon><infon key="xml">&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;table xmlns:xlink=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink&quot; frame=&quot;hsides&quot; rules=&quot;groups&quot;&gt;&lt;colgroup span=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; colspan=&quot;2&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Topic Title: &lt;italic&gt;How to get from JFK to New Rochelle&lt;/italic&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; colspan=&quot;2&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;Initial-Post:&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic&gt;Can someone please advise the best way to get from JFK to New Rochelle using public transport&lt;/italic&gt;? &lt;italic&gt;I know that by Taxi it is $80–85 USD which is quite expensive&lt;/italic&gt;.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;High-Quality Reply&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;Reply1:&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic&gt;Your combined cost of getting from JFK to &lt;ext-link ext-link-type=&quot;uri&quot; xlink:href=&quot;https://www.tripadvisor.com.my/Tourism-g48246-New_Rochelle_New_York-Vacations.html&quot;&gt;New Rochelle&lt;/ext-link&gt; and back to JFK—using the Airport Express Service bus and Metro North—will be $40–45 round-trip&lt;/italic&gt;, &lt;italic&gt;depending on whether you'll riding the Metro North train at times it deems to be peak or off-peak&lt;/italic&gt;.&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic&gt;The New Rochelle train station is only 1/2 mile from the Residence Inn&lt;/italic&gt;, &lt;italic&gt;and according to Metro North’s page re&lt;/italic&gt;: &lt;italic&gt;the New Rochelle station&lt;/italic&gt;, &lt;italic&gt;Bluebird Taxi has its office right at the train station&lt;/italic&gt;. &lt;italic&gt;Sounds easy peasy&lt;/italic&gt; :&lt;italic&gt;-)&lt;/italic&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;Low-Quality Reply&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;Reply2:&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic&gt;What are you going to do when you get to &lt;ext-link ext-link-type=&quot;uri&quot; xlink:href=&quot;https://www.tripadvisor.com.my/Tourism-g48246-New_Rochelle_New_York-Vacations.html&quot;&gt;New Rochelle&lt;/ext-link&gt;&lt;/italic&gt;? &lt;italic&gt;Since it is not in the city you will need transportation of some sort to get around&lt;/italic&gt;. &lt;italic&gt;In that case you may want to rent a car at JFK and drive&lt;/italic&gt;. &lt;italic&gt;The one day cost would be equal to the taxi fare and you will be in control&lt;/italic&gt;.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;Non-Quality Reply&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;Reply3:&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic&gt;One more thing&lt;/italic&gt;, &lt;italic&gt;would I have to be going up and down a lot of stairs&lt;/italic&gt;? &lt;italic&gt;I was thinking about my luggage&lt;/italic&gt; …&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
</infon><offset>33704</offset><text>Topic Title: How to get from JFK to New Rochelle	 	Initial-Post:Can someone please advise the best way to get from JFK to New Rochelle using public transport? I know that by Taxi it is $80–85 USD which is quite expensive.	 	High-Quality Reply	Reply1:Your combined cost of getting from JFK to New Rochelle and back to JFK—using the Airport Express Service bus and Metro North—will be $40–45 round-trip, depending on whether you'll riding the Metro North train at times it deems to be peak or off-peak.The New Rochelle train station is only 1/2 mile from the Residence Inn, and according to Metro North’s page re: the New Rochelle station, Bluebird Taxi has its office right at the train station. Sounds easy peasy :-)	 	Low-Quality Reply	Reply2:What are you going to do when you get to New Rochelle? Since it is not in the city you will need transportation of some sort to get around. In that case you may want to rent a car at JFK and drive. The one day cost would be equal to the taxi fare and you will be in control.	 	Non-Quality Reply	Reply3:One more thing, would I have to be going up and down a lot of stairs? I was thinking about my luggage …	 	</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>34869</offset><text>6.0 Experiments design</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>34892</offset><text>In this study, two datasets were used—the online TripAdvisor forum (https://www.tripadvisor.com.my/ShowForum-g28953-i4-New_York.html) for New York City (NYC) along with the online Ubuntu Linux distribution forum (http://ubuntuforums.org). The two datasets comprised of discussion threads, where every IPR pairs generated a thread. The statistics for both the datasets have been provided in Table 4 by.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">pone.0215516.t004.xml</infon><infon key="id">pone.0215516.t004</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_title_caption</infon><offset>35296</offset><text>Statistics for the trip advisor forum and the ubuntu linux distribution forum.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">pone.0215516.t004.xml</infon><infon key="id">pone.0215516.t004</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table</infon><infon key="xml">&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;table frame=&quot;hsides&quot; rules=&quot;groups&quot;&gt;&lt;colgroup span=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;NYC&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;Number of threads&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;83072&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;113277&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;Number of users&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;39454&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;103280&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;Number of replies&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;590021&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;590021&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
</infon><offset>35375</offset><text>	NYC	Ubuntu	 	Number of threads	83072	113277	 	Number of users	39454	103280	 	Number of replies	590021	590021	 	</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>35488</offset><text>The authors randomly chose 100 discussion threads from the NYC and the Ubuntu datasets, with 816 and 773 replies, respectively. As the judgment quality for the IPR pairs was unavailable, the authors conducted a survey on crowdsourcing platform community (https://www.crowdflower.com/) to judge the quality of each reply in the thread to initial post. This platform was used for assigning class labels to each posted reply, as mentioned in Section 5.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>35938</offset><text>In the case of the NYC dataset, the authors noted that 342 (42%) replies were of a high-quality, 303 (37%) replies were low-quality and 171 (21%) replies were non-quality. In the case of the Ubuntu dataset, 444 (57%) replies out of 773 replies were high-quality, 233 (30%) replies were low-quality while 96 (13%) replies were non-quality. Table 5 summarizes the distribution of the user replies in various classes for the two datasets.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">pone.0215516.t005.xml</infon><infon key="id">pone.0215516.t005</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_title_caption</infon><offset>36374</offset><text>A distribution of the user replies in various classes for the two datasets.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">pone.0215516.t005.xml</infon><infon key="id">pone.0215516.t005</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table</infon><infon key="xml">&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;table frame=&quot;hsides&quot; rules=&quot;groups&quot;&gt;&lt;colgroup span=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Reply Class&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; colspan=&quot;2&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;NYC&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; colspan=&quot;2&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Non-Quality&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;171&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;21%&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;96&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;13%&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Low-Quality&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;303&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;37%&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;233&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;30%&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;High-Quality&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;342&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;42%&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;444&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;57%&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Total&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;816&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;100%&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;773&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;100%&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
</infon><offset>36450</offset><text>Reply Class	NYC	Ubuntu	 	Non-Quality	171	21%	96	13%	 	Low-Quality	303	37%	233	30%	 	High-Quality	342	42%	444	57%	 	Total	816	100%	773	100%	 	</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>36592</offset><text>6.1 Classification algorithm</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>36621</offset><text>Due to the availability of texts in digital form and the increasing need to access them properly, the text classification was seen to be an important task, to find interesting information on the internet. It is very complicated and time-consuming to develop the text classifiers manually, hence, classifiers can be studied using samples. In order to classify the IPR pairs quality, the authors used many supervised machine learning algorithms like the Support Vector Machine (SVM), the Naïve Bayes (NB) and the Decision Tree (J48).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>37154</offset><text>6.1.1 Support vector machines (SVM)</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>37190</offset><text>There are more than 10,000 features that need to be looked at when learning about text classifiers. As support vector machines are not really dependent on the number of features, they are considered optimum to handle such large feature spaces. Thus, SVM is regarded to be helpful in text classification. The SVM is considered to be an effective supervised classification algorithm. SVMs employs the idea of drawing a line called as hyperplane which segments a dataset into classes in the best way. Support vectors can be defined as the data points closest to the hyperplane. If these points pertaining to a dataset be removed, it would also change the dividing hyperplane’s position. Therefore, they are referred to as the critical elements pertaining to a dataset. Intuitively, the greater the distance of these data points from the hyperplane, the better the chance they have been properly classified. Thus, when addition of new testing data is done, whichever side of the hyperplane it lands, it would define the assigned class subsequently. The margin can be defined as the distance between the hyperplane and the closest data point from either set. The key aim here is to select a hyperplane that has the highest possible margin between the hyperplane and any point inside the training set, which provides a higher chance of new data to be classified suitably. Inside the margin, there are no data points at any time. The SVM was initially developed for solving 2-class problems. However, many techniques were later developed that extended the SVM to the multi-class datasets.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>38774</offset><text>6.1.2 Naïve bayes (NB)</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>38798</offset><text>The NB classifier is a simple probabilistic classifier based on a common assumption that all features are independent of each other, given the class variable. NB classifier performs well especially for problems that are linearly separable and fairly well for problems that are nonlinearly separable. It is suitable for text classification as well as achieving good performance when dealing with high-dimensional feature spaces.. NB has the feature to learn the pattern of assessing a set of documents that have been already classified. Then, the contents are compared with the list of features that allows assigning the documents to their correct class. The NB classifier is based on theorem by Bayes and the theorem of total probability. For example, consider a probability in which a document d is represented by the vector X, X = {x1, x2,…xn}, wherein n refers to the number of features. The probability of the sample belonging to a specific class is calculated using the following formula:  </text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>39796</offset><text>Wherein, P(c|x) represents the probability of class, c; for a feature, x. Let P(c) be the probability of the class, while P(x) is the feature probability. P(x|c) refers to the probability that the feature belongs to a specific class.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>40030</offset><text>6.1.3 Decision trees (J48)</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>40057</offset><text>J48 algorithm is based on decision tree. The decision trees learning approach uses the structure of trees for classifying the samples. Decision trees starts with one node, which then branches into other possible results. The leaf node also refers to class labels. On the other hand, a branch indicates the feature conjunctions, while the nodes (or non-leaf nodes) represent the conditional tests on a feature.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>40467</offset><text>The classification results for three algorithms were obtained with the help of the 10-fold cross validation that is used for data mining. The classifier performance was studied based on the Precision (P), Recall (R) and the F-1 measure. The authors pre-processed the IPR pairs after removing the HTML tags and then stemming the words with Porter’s stemmer. Normal stop words in the English Language were used. For determining the best QDs features for classifying the replies to the Initial-Post, the feature selection methods (filter methods) are commonly used in text classification to reduce the numbers of text features and improve the efficiency and accuracy of classifiers. More details are presented in the next Section.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>41197</offset><text>6.2 Quality feature reduction</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>41227</offset><text>In a text classification process, the main issue that arises includes the feature space high dimensionality. Generally, a text domain consists of numerous features. These texts can be represented as the vector containing m elements, wherein m refers to the feature number, which are usually text words. A majority of the features are irrelevant and not helpful for the task classification process. A few of the features can significantly decrease the classification accuracy. Also, high feature number can slow the classification process, or make a few classifiers inapplicable. Here, the authors investigated the above-mentioned quality dimensions features. For decreasing the number of features and removing irrelevant features, the filters define a feature subset. This subset is vital for eliminating the noisy, irrelevant, non-valuable and redundant features and also helps in- (1) Improving the classification accuracy and runtime; (2) Reducing the feature space size and improving the quality of the classification method.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>42257</offset><text>In this study, the authors have applied the features selection techniques (filter methods) based on a statistical measure like the Information gain, Chi-square and the Gain Ratio for selecting the important features. These methods assign a score to every feature and rank all features, wherein all high-ranked features are chosen and applied to the classifier. The three filter methods are described below.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>42664</offset><text>6.2.1 Information gain (IG)</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>42692</offset><text>This method determines the decrease in the entropy by taking into account the presence or the absence of a specific feature in every user's reply in a thread. IG is used for selecting the test features in every class. IG aims to—(1) Select the features with several values; (2) Decide the feature order; (3) Identify the features in a specific set of training features which helps in TFThs classification.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>43100</offset><text>Furthermore, the IG estimates the gain between the ith feature fi and the class label, C, with the help of the Eq (3) as follows: </text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>43231</offset><text>Wherein H (fi) refers to the entropy of fi; while H(fi | C) refers to the entropy of fi after determining the C value. Hence, </text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>43358</offset><text>Eq (4) describes the uncertainty in the feature set which is selected. For a class label that is observed, the conditional entropy is determined as: </text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>43508</offset><text>This indicates that after observing C, class label, the uncertainty is decreased in the features that have to be selected.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>43631</offset><text>6.2.2 Chi-square (Chi2)</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>43655</offset><text>This method measures the absence of independence between the fi feature in Class ck. It is used as the (i) goodness-of-fit test which is used for a set of data and a specific statistical distribution, or (ii) A test of independence or relation between 2 variables or factors. For solving the feature selection issue in the text classification, the Chi-Square value helps in ranking the features based on their use and cannot determine the statistical dependence of the fi feature and ck class. By considering a 2-way contingency table for the fi feature and ck class, wherein A denotes the number of times the fi and ck co-occurred, while B denotes the number of times the fi occurred without the ck; C refers to the number of times the c occurred without fi; D refers to the number of times neither the ck nor the fi occurs, and N refers to the total number of thread replies. Thus, Chi-square value is determined as: </text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>44575</offset><text>6.2.3 Gain ratio (GR)</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>44597</offset><text>The GR is seen to improve the IG measure as it can offer a normalised score of the contribution of the feature to the optimal IG-based classification decisions. The GR is used as an iterative procedure, wherein small feature sets are selected in an incremental manner. These iterations are terminated when only a predetermined number of features are left. The GR is used as a disparity measure, and a high GR ratio indicates that the feature is useful for the classification process. Thus, GR can be computed as:  </text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>45112</offset><text>Where, K (a) can be calculated by splitting the training examples into v partitions, wherein v refers to the outcome of the test applied on the feature a; while | Pi | refers to the number of replies present in the tanning dataset, P.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>45347</offset><text>7.0 Results and discussion</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>45374</offset><text>In the subsequent subsections, descriptions regarding the classification result, reduction result and more discussions on the result via confusion matrix have been provided. Moreover, this work has been compared by the authors with a related work (baseline).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>45633</offset><text>7.1 Classification result</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>45659</offset><text>The results for the classification of the IPR pairs for the NYC and the Ubuntu datasets with the help of the SVM, NB and the J48 classifiers are presented in this section. The effects of the QDs features on the classification of the IPR pairs were investigated. All the classification experiments were conducted using a single QD features at a time as well as aggregating all QDs features.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>46049</offset><text>The classification results for the NYC dataset for every QD features are presented in Table 6 and Fig 3. According to the results, the three classifiers (SVM, NB, and J48) showed the best individual performance for the relevancy dimension features (D1) and the best among the three classifiers is J48 classifier based on its Precision (0.688), Recall (0.692) and the F-1 measure (0.684). The second best individual performance was achieved by the three classifiers as well for the amount-of-data dimension features (D6) and also the best classifier for this dimension is the J48 based on its Precision (0.647), Recall (0.651) and the F-1 measure (0.645). Furthermore, all the QDs features showed a better performance for the precision, recall and F-1 measure compared to the individual QD features using the SVM, NB and the J48 classifiers. The J48 classifier was seen to be the best classifier and showed high values for the precision (0.730), recall (0.723) and F-1 measure (0.716) for all the QDs features.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">pone.0215516.g003.jpg</infon><infon key="id">pone.0215516.g003</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_title_caption</infon><offset>47059</offset><text>A comparative analysis of the individual QD features using the three classifiers for the NYC.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">pone.0215516.t006.xml</infon><infon key="id">pone.0215516.t006</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_title_caption</infon><offset>47153</offset><text>Results for the SVM, NB and the J48 Classifiers for the NYC dataset.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">pone.0215516.t006.xml</infon><infon key="id">pone.0215516.t006</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table</infon><infon key="xml">&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;table frame=&quot;hsides&quot; rules=&quot;groups&quot;&gt;&lt;colgroup span=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;2&quot; style=&quot;background-color:#D9D9D9&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;QDs&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; colspan=&quot;3&quot; style=&quot;background-color:#D9D9D9&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;SVM Classifier&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; colspan=&quot;3&quot; style=&quot;background-color:#D9D9D9&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;NB Classifier&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; colspan=&quot;3&quot; style=&quot;background-color:#D9D9D9&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;J48 Classifier&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Avg-P&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Avg-R&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Avg-F&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Avg-P&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Avg-R&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Avg-F&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Avg-P&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Avg-R&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Avg-F&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;D1&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.618&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.62&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.606&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.642&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.625&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.596&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;0.688&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;0.692&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;0.684&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;D2&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.473&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.48&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.411&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.464&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.487&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.445&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.51&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.489&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.418&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;D3&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.333&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.433&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.367&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.443&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.466&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.434&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.407&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.438&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.366&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;D4&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.485&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.479&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.456&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.443&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.466&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.434&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.375&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.469&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.416&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;D5&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.176&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.419&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.248&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.249&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.403&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.307&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.176&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.419&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.248&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;D6&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.489&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.583&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.521&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.623&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.605&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.597&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.647&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.651&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.645&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;All QDs&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.709&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.706&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.704&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.666&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.656&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.651&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;0.730&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;0.723&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;0.716&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
</infon><offset>47222</offset><text>QDs	SVM Classifier	NB Classifier	J48 Classifier	 	Avg-P	Avg-R	Avg-F	Avg-P	Avg-R	Avg-F	Avg-P	Avg-R	Avg-F	 	D1	0.618	0.62	0.606	0.642	0.625	0.596	0.688	0.692	0.684	 	D2	0.473	0.48	0.411	0.464	0.487	0.445	0.51	0.489	0.418	 	D3	0.333	0.433	0.367	0.443	0.466	0.434	0.407	0.438	0.366	 	D4	0.485	0.479	0.456	0.443	0.466	0.434	0.375	0.469	0.416	 	D5	0.176	0.419	0.248	0.249	0.403	0.307	0.176	0.419	0.248	 	D6	0.489	0.583	0.521	0.623	0.605	0.597	0.647	0.651	0.645	 	All QDs	0.709	0.706	0.704	0.666	0.656	0.651	0.730	0.723	0.716	 	</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>47744</offset><text>Table 7 and Fig 4 show the classification results for the Ubuntu dataset for all the QD features. According to the results, the three classifiers achieved high performance for specific QDs features. SVM classifier showed the best individual performance for the relevancy dimension features (D1) based on its Precision (0.681), Recall (0.661) and the F-1 measure (0.606) compared to the other QDs for the same classifier. Comparatively, the SVM classifier is also the best among the three classifiers. Likewise, NB classifier showed the best individual performance for the relevancy dimension features (D1) based on its F-1 measure (0.568) compared to the other QDs for the same classifier. However, for the ease-of-understanding dimension features (D4), J48 classifier showed the best individual performance based on its Precision (0.535), Recall (0.614) and the F-1 measure (0.572) compared to the others QDs for the same classifier. Therefore, we observed there are no specific type of QDs features that achieve high performance across three classifiers based on its precision, recall and the F-1 measure. Furthermore, all the QDs features showed a better value for the precision, recall and the F-1 measure as compared to the individual QD features for all the classifiers. The SVM classifier showed the best values for the precision (0.754), recall (0.735) and the F-1 measure (0.712) for all the QDs features.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">pone.0215516.g004.jpg</infon><infon key="id">pone.0215516.g004</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_title_caption</infon><offset>49159</offset><text>A comparative analysis of the individual QD features using the three classifiers for the Ubuntu dataset.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">pone.0215516.t007.xml</infon><infon key="id">pone.0215516.t007</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_title_caption</infon><offset>49264</offset><text>Results for the SVM, NB and the J48 Classifiers for the Ubuntu dataset.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">pone.0215516.t007.xml</infon><infon key="id">pone.0215516.t007</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table</infon><infon key="xml">&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;table frame=&quot;hsides&quot; rules=&quot;groups&quot;&gt;&lt;colgroup span=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;2&quot; style=&quot;background-color:#D9D9D9&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;QDs&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; colspan=&quot;3&quot; style=&quot;background-color:#D9D9D9&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;SVM Classifier&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; colspan=&quot;3&quot; style=&quot;background-color:#D9D9D9&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;NB Classifier&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; colspan=&quot;3&quot; style=&quot;background-color:#D9D9D9&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;J48 Classifier&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Avg-P&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Avg-R&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Avg-F&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Avg-P&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Avg-R&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Avg-F&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Avg-P&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Avg-R&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Avg-F&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;D1&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;0.681&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;0.661&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;0.606&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.586&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.585&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.568&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.515&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.576&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.487&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;D2&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.575&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.605&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.541&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.539&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.578&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.547&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.468&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.577&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.482&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;D3&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.572&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.578&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.43&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.682&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.578&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.43&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.33&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.574&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.419&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;D4&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.539&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.617&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.575&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.514&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.598&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.543&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.535&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.614&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.572&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;D5&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.33&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.574&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.419&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.473&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.567&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.507&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.33&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.574&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.419&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;D6&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.632&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.576&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.422&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.697&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.583&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.478&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.403&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.587&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.477&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;All QDs&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;0.754&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;0.735&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;0.712&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.626&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.642&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.617&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.689&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.702&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.677&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
</infon><offset>49336</offset><text>QDs	SVM Classifier	NB Classifier	J48 Classifier	 	Avg-P	Avg-R	Avg-F	Avg-P	Avg-R	Avg-F	Avg-P	Avg-R	Avg-F	 	D1	0.681	0.661	0.606	0.586	0.585	0.568	0.515	0.576	0.487	 	D2	0.575	0.605	0.541	0.539	0.578	0.547	0.468	0.577	0.482	 	D3	0.572	0.578	0.43	0.682	0.578	0.43	0.33	0.574	0.419	 	D4	0.539	0.617	0.575	0.514	0.598	0.543	0.535	0.614	0.572	 	D5	0.33	0.574	0.419	0.473	0.567	0.507	0.33	0.574	0.419	 	D6	0.632	0.576	0.422	0.697	0.583	0.478	0.403	0.587	0.477	 	All QDs	0.754	0.735	0.712	0.626	0.642	0.617	0.689	0.702	0.677	 	</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>49856</offset><text>7.2 Reduction result</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>49877</offset><text>The result of the significance of every individual quality feature for the classification of the IPR pairs was also studied. Every quality feature was studied individually after calculating the IG, Chi2 and GR values for the class labels, and ranking the quality features based on their IG, Chi2 and GR values. The top 12 quality features used for classifying the IPR pairs for the NYC and the Ubuntu datasets is listed in Table 8, the lists do not include the Timeliness dimension features (D3) for the two datasets that were studied. Also, the lists do not include the Politeness dimension features (D5) for the NYC dataset. This means that these quality dimensions features are not important for the classification of the IPR pairs to identify relevant (quality) replies. Theses QDs achieved low scores and ranked at the bottom of the list wherein the lowly ranked features are irrelevant and unnecessary for these domains.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">pone.0215516.t008.xml</infon><infon key="id">pone.0215516.t008</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_title_caption</infon><offset>50804</offset><text>Top 12 quality features for the NYC and Ubuntu datasets that were ranked based on their IG, Chi2 and GR values.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">pone.0215516.t008.xml</infon><infon key="id">pone.0215516.t008</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table</infon><infon key="xml">&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;table frame=&quot;hsides&quot; rules=&quot;groups&quot;&gt;&lt;colgroup span=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; colspan=&quot;3&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;NYC Dataset&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; colspan=&quot;3&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Ubuntu Dataset&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;IG&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Chi2&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;GR&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;IG&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Chi2&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;GR&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F27&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F27&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F27&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F27&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F13&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F28&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F28&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F28&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F27&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F27&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F13&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F12&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F12&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F9&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F9&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F9&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F21&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F21&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F10&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F13&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F13&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F28&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F28&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F12&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;9&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F3&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F12&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F12&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F13&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F13&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F21&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F12&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F3&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F3&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F10&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F25&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F28&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F21&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F21&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F21&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F24&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F24&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F24&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;12&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F15&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F15&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F15&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F25&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F15&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;F25&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
</infon><offset>50916</offset><text>	NYC Dataset	Ubuntu Dataset	 		IG	Chi2	GR	IG	Chi2	GR	 	1	F27	F27	F27	F22	F27	F13	 	2	F28	F28	F28	F27	F22	F27	 	3	F4	F4	F4	F11	F4	F22	 	4	F1	F1	F11	F4	F11	F4	 	5	F11	F11	F1	F1	F1	F11	 	6	F2	F2	F13	F12	F12	F1	 	7	F9	F9	F9	F21	F21	F10	 	8	F13	F13	F2	F28	F28	F12	 	9	F3	F12	F12	F13	F13	F21	 	10	F12	F3	F3	F10	F25	F28	 	11	F21	F21	F21	F24	F24	F24	 	12	F15	F15	F15	F25	F15	F25	 	</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>51290</offset><text>Fig 5A and 5B present the classification results for the all QDs features and the best QDs features, and a summary of the results for the three classes using the best classifier for the NYC and the Ubuntu datasets, respectively, based on their precision, recall and F-1 measure. It was observed that for the two datasets, the majority of the replies were classified in the high-quality class rather than in the other classes. Also, a higher number of replies were classified in the low-quality class compared to the non-quality class. High values for the F-1 measure in the high-quality class indicated that the replies in this class contained the most significant information that was relevant to the Initial-Post. On comparing, results obtained via best QDs features were clearly seen to be better versus the results obtained via all QDs features by employing three measures. To conclude, the best results were obtained when the classification algorithms were combined with the features selection techniques.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">pone.0215516.g005.jpg</infon><infon key="id">pone.0215516.g005</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>52301</offset><text>(a) and (b) A comparative analysis between all quality features and best quality features for every class using the best classifier for two datasets.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>52451</offset><text>7.3 Measuring performance</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>52477</offset><text>In this section, assessing of the measures for classification algorithms with the features selection techniques in terms of performance measures was done.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>52632</offset><text>7.3.1 Confusion matrix</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>52655</offset><text>For each dataset, evaluation of the confusion matrix was done for best QDs features via the best classifier. Firstly, a confusion matrix can be defined as a specific table layout that enables visualising the algorithms’ performance. In this, the instances in an identified class are signified by each column of the matrix), while instances in an actual class are denoted by each row (or vice versa). The results pertaining to algorithm testing can be summarised through a confusion matrix for additional inspection as presented in Tables 9 and 10. In both tables, every class was represented by high-quality, low-quality and non-quality replies. The diagonal of the tables (highlighted in bold) contains all correct identifications, making visual inspection of the tables for identifying errors much easier, as these are denoted by the values outside the diagonal.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">pone.0215516.t009.xml</infon><infon key="id">pone.0215516.t009</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_title_caption</infon><offset>53522</offset><text>Confusion matrix for the best classifier for the NYC dataset.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">pone.0215516.t009.xml</infon><infon key="id">pone.0215516.t009</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table</infon><infon key="xml">&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;table frame=&quot;hsides&quot; rules=&quot;groups&quot;&gt;&lt;colgroup span=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; colspan=&quot;2&quot; rowspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;NYC Dataset&lt;break/&gt;(J48 Classifier)&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; colspan=&quot;3&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Predicted&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;High-Quality&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Low-Quality&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Non-Quality&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;3&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;Model&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;High-Quality&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;288&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;41&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;13&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;Low-Quality&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;41&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;225&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;37&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;Non-Quality&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;21&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;36&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;114&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
</infon><offset>53584</offset><text>NYC Dataset(J48 Classifier)	Predicted	 	High-Quality	Low-Quality	Non-Quality	 	Model	High-Quality	288	41	13	 	Low-Quality	41	225	37	 	Non-Quality	21	36	114	 	</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">pone.0215516.t010.xml</infon><infon key="id">pone.0215516.t010</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_title_caption</infon><offset>53743</offset><text>Confusion matrix for the best classifier for the Ubuntu dataset.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">pone.0215516.t010.xml</infon><infon key="id">pone.0215516.t010</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table</infon><infon key="xml">&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;table frame=&quot;hsides&quot; rules=&quot;groups&quot;&gt;&lt;colgroup span=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; colspan=&quot;2&quot; rowspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;Ubuntu Dataset&lt;break/&gt;(SVM Classifier)&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; colspan=&quot;3&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Predicted&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;High-Quality&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Low-Quality&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Non-Quality&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;3&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;Model&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;High-Quality&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;410&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;28&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;Low-Quality&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;58&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;166&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;9&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;Non-Quality&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;45&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;41&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
</infon><offset>53808</offset><text>Ubuntu Dataset(SVM Classifier)	Predicted	 	High-Quality	Low-Quality	Non-Quality	 	Model	High-Quality	410	28	6	 	Low-Quality	58	166	9	 	Non-Quality	45	10	41	 	</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>53967</offset><text>The actual classes for the two datasets were defined in Section 6 in Table 5. The confusion matrix for the NYC dataset shown in Table 9 is discussed as follows: First of all, the model demonstrated that for the 342 actual high-quality classes, the majority of the replies are 288 actually belonging to the high-quality class, and were correctly classified (84.21%). Based on the model, 41 replies were inaccurately identified as low-quality (11.99%) and 13 replies (3.80%) were inaccurately classified as those belonging to the non-quality class, even though they were able to provide information that was totally relevant to the final user. Second, for 303 actual low-quality class, the model depicted the majority of the replies were 225 actually belonging to the low-quality class, and were correctly classified (74.26%). However, 41 actually belonged to low-quality replies and were inaccurately classified as those belonging to the high-quality class (13.53%), while 37 belonging to low-quality replies were inaccurately classified as non-quality replies (12.28%). These results showed that although the replies possessed characteristics similar to the high-quality and non-quality class, respectively, they could only provide information that was partially relevant to the final user. Lastly, for 171 actual non-quality class, the model indicated that most replies 114 actually belonging to the non-quality class were correctly classified (66.67%), 21 replies (12.28%) of the non-quality replies were incorrectly classified as high-quality replies, while 36 replies (21.05%) were incorrectly classified as low-quality replies. These results showed that although the replies had some characteristics that were similar to the low-quality rather than high-quality replies, they provided no relevant information to the final user. Based on the confusion matrix pertaining to the diagonal values, the model was seen to be capable in identifying the three classes well.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>55937</offset><text>Similarly, in the case of the Ubuntu dataset in Table 10, the model was as follows: First, for the 444 actual high-quality class, the model showed that the majority of replies, 410 which actually belonged to the high-quality replies class were correctly classified as being of high-quality (92.34%) as they could provide information that was totally relevant to the final user. Meanwhile, 28 replies (6.31%) and 6 replies (1.35%) were inaccurately classified as those belonging to the low-quality and non-quality class, respectively, even though they could provide information that was totally relevant to the final user. They possessed characteristics that were similar to the low-quality and non-quality classes, respectively. Second, for 233 actual low-quality class, the model indicated the majority of replies 166 actually belonged to low quality class, and were appropriately classified (71.25%) as being of low-quality, while 58 actual replies (24.89%) of the low-quality were incorrectly classified as high-quality, while 9 actual replies (3.86%) of the low-quality replies were incorrectly classified as non-quality replies. These results showed that although the replies possessed characteristics that were similar to the high-quality instead of the non-quality replies, they could only provide information that was partially relevant to the final user. Lastly, the model demonstrated that for the 96 actual non-quality class, the 41 replies (42.7%) were classified correctly as non-quality since they offered irrelevant information for the final user. Meanwhile, the classifier incorrectly classified 45 replies (46.88%) of the non-quality replies as high-quality ones. Based on the confusion matrix, the authors could observe that the model in question faced difficulty in differentiating low-quality replies as being high-quality replies. Ten replies (10.42%) of the non-quality replies were inaccurately classified as those belonging to the low-quality class. This was due to the fact that these replies possessed similarities to the high-quality replies rather than to the non-quality replies, and were erroneously considered as being relevant to the Initial-Post by the classifier. Subsequently, the model was found to be better in distinguishing high-quality and low-quality replies versus non-quality replies.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>58265</offset><text>7.3.2 Comparison with related models</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>58302</offset><text>A comparison was made by the authors between two baseline and the work provided by the authors to evaluate the performance of the put forward model. The two datasets were employed to assess the three models. A comparison was done for these and the put forward classified quality Initial-Post replies pairs. Frist, in the case of the rule-based model, it was assumed by the authors that the Initial-Post in a thread is considered as a question while all replies in the same thread were branded as solutions. Second, in the BoW model, lexical characteristics pertaining to the text between IPR pairs that had to be classified were captured by the authors. For the purpose of classification, frequency of words in IPR pairs was employed as features by the authors. For a range of text classification works, BoW-based classifiers are commonly employed. Last comes the role pertaining to the user posts model. The authors employed a range of features such as structural features, content-based features, sentiment-based features and user features to segment initial post replies pairs into eight classes that follow initial post as question and replies in the form of repeat question, clarification, further details, solution, positive feedback, negative feedback, and junk.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>59572</offset><text>For each dataset, the results pertaining to all QDs features as well as the best QDs features with the baselines were compared by the authors. Table 11 presents the classification results for the IPR pairs carried out with the help of the quality model classifiers and the baseline classifiers (Rule based, BoW) as well as the Role of user posts. In terms of best QDs features pertaining to the NYC dataset, the results showed an overall classification accuracy of 76.83%, along with the value of precision (0.767), recall (0.768) and F1-measure (0.768). Likewise, in the Ubuntu dataset, the result showed a classification accuracy of 79.82%, along with the values of precision (0.795), recall (0.798) and F1-measure (0.788). For the three measures, the results pertaining to all QDs features were listed in Tables 6 and 7.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">pone.0215516.t011.xml</infon><infon key="id">pone.0215516.t011</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_title_caption</infon><offset>60396</offset><text>Classification results for the rule-based, bag-of-words, role of individual user messages, all quality features and the proposed classification approaches.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">pone.0215516.t011.xml</infon><infon key="id">pone.0215516.t011</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table</infon><infon key="xml">&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;table frame=&quot;hsides&quot; rules=&quot;groups&quot;&gt;&lt;colgroup span=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; colspan=&quot;6&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;NYC Dataset&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;Metrics&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;Rule based&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;Bag of words (BoW)&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;Role of user posts&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;All QDs features&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;Best QDs features&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;break/&gt;&lt;bold&gt;(Proposed approach)&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;Accuracy&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;61.88%&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;60.98%&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;75.11%&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;72.30%&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;76.83%&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;Precision&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.441&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.596&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.726&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.730&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.767&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;F1-measue&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.499&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.529&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.724&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.716&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.768&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; colspan=&quot;6&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;Ubuntu Dataset&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;Metrics&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;Rule based&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;Bag of words (BoW)&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;Role of user posts&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;All QDs features&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;Best QDs features&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;break/&gt;&lt;bold&gt;(Proposed approach)&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;Accuracy&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;58.03%&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;57.66%&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;72.69%&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;73.48%&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;79.82%&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;Precision&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.442&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.503&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.705&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.754&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.795&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;F1-measue&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.471&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.473&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.712&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.712&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.788&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
</infon><offset>60552</offset><text>NYC Dataset	 	Metrics	Rule based	Bag of words (BoW)	Role of user posts	All QDs features	Best QDs features(Proposed approach)	 	Accuracy	61.88%	60.98%	75.11%	72.30%	76.83%	 	Precision	0.441	0.596	0.726	0.730	0.767	 	F1-measue	0.499	0.529	0.724	0.716	0.768	 	Ubuntu Dataset	 	Metrics	Rule based	Bag of words (BoW)	Role of user posts	All QDs features	Best QDs features(Proposed approach)	 	Accuracy	58.03%	57.66%	72.69%	73.48%	79.82%	 	Precision	0.442	0.503	0.705	0.754	0.795	 	F1-measue	0.471	0.473	0.712	0.712	0.788	 	</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>61070</offset><text>Thus, the use of the suggested quality features set yielded different results for the two datasets due to the nature of each dataset. Note that the NYC dataset is a general discussion forum while the Ubuntu dataset is a specific domain discussion forum. Furthermore, the proposed classifier was able to significantly outperform the baseline classifiers for the three metrics that were studied. Here the Initial-Posts were considered as a query and the replies as the documents for determining the relevant (high-quality), less relevant (low-quality), and irrelevant (non-quality) replies to the Initial-Post in order to identify the relevant replies (high-quality) of the IPR pairs. On the other hand, based on the results mentioned in Tables 6, 7, 8 and 11, that the proposed quality dimensions features displayed differing performances based on the forum types and contents. The QDs could show different selecting effects for different algorithms and two forums domains. Therefore, based on our finding, it is found that the J48 classifier showed the best result in NYC dataset. However, the SVM classifier showed the best result in the Ubuntu dataset, while the NB classifier showed the least result in the two datasets (NYC and Ubuntu). As discussed previously, assessment of feature selection techniques was done; to achieve the best QDs features, analysis of all QDs features was done. Thus, the best result was obtained when the classification algorithm was combined with the features selection techniques. It was important to recognise such accurate replies in order to successfully apply in text forum thread summarization, question-answer pair detection, forum search, etc.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>62754</offset><text>8.0 Conclusions and future work</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>62786</offset><text>In this study, human judgment and the quality dimensions features for identifying the best quality features were exploited to detect the relevant user replies to the Initial-Posts in a discussion thread (IPR pairs) to help in detecting the quality of the user replies in the TFThs. Six QDs features were studied using the discussion thread structure for assessing the user reply quality, which included the relevancy, author activeness, timeliness, ease-of-understanding, amount-of-data, and politeness dimension features. Thereafter, the values of the quality features for every reply were estimated. Human judgment was also used to classify the replies as high-quality, low-quality or non-quality. The SVM, NB and J48 classifiers were applied to classify the replies in any one out of the three groups mentioned above. Additionally, the features selection techniques of Information Gain, Chi-square and Gain Ratio were used as these were better indicators for identifying the quality of the replies along with the best quality dimensions features. According to these experiments, the model was able to identify the appropriate quality features from the six QDs features for the TFThs, thereby improving the extraction of high-quality replies from the thread. Furthermore, this model also possessed a good classification ability which helped in identifying the high-quality users. It is believed that this proposed model will be able to support content filtering and specific forum searches. In future, this work can be further expanded to include text forum threads summarization.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">title</infon><offset>64369</offset><text>References</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">055</infon><infon key="issue">1</infon><infon key="lpage">62</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:ALBAHAM;given-names:AT</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:SA LIM;given-names:N</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Journal of Theoretical and Applied Information Technology</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">38</infon><infon key="year">2012</infon><offset>64380</offset><text>QUALITY-BIASED RETRIEVAL IN ONLINE FORUMS</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">117</infon><infon key="issue">1</infon><infon key="lpage">23</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Heydari;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Tavakoli;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Ismail;given-names:Z</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Salim;given-names:N</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">World Academy of Science, Engineering and Technology, International Journal of Computer, Electrical, Automation, Control and Information Engineering</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">10</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>64422</offset><text>Leveraging Quality Metrics in Voting Model Based Thread Retrieval</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">377</infon><infon key="lpage">84</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Chen;given-names:Z</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Zhang;given-names:L</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Wang;given-names:W</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Information Retrieval Technology</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2008</infon><offset>64488</offset></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>64489</offset><text>Agichtein E, Castillo C, Donato D, Gionis A, Mishne G, editors. Finding high-quality content in social media. Proceedings of the 2008 international conference on web search and data mining; 2008: ACM.</text></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Chai;given-names:KEK</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">A machine learning-based approach for automated quality assessment of user generated content in web forums</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2011</infon><offset>64690</offset></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>64691</offset><text>Weimer M, Gurevych I, Mühlhäuser M, editors. Automatically assessing the post quality in online discussions on software. Proceedings of the 45th Annual Meeting of the ACL on Interactive Poster and Demonstration Sessions; 2007: Association for Computational Linguistics.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>64963</offset><text>Albaham AT, Salim N, Adekunle OI, editors. Leveraging post level quality indicators in online forum thread retrieval. Proceedings of the First International Conference on Advanced Data and Information Engineering (DaEng-2013); 2014: Springer.</text></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Biyani;given-names:P</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Majumdar;given-names:D</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Rambachan;given-names:SAK</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Visweswariah;given-names:K</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Google Patents</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>65206</offset><text>Online thread retrieval using thread structure and query subjectivity</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1</infon><infon key="issue">1</infon><infon key="lpage">163</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Hoogeveen;given-names:D</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Wang;given-names:L</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Baldwin;given-names:T</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Verspoor;given-names:KM</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Foundations and Trends® in Information Retrieval</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">12</infon><infon key="year">2018</infon><offset>65276</offset><text>Web Forum Retrieval and Text Analytics: A Survey</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">31</infon><infon key="issue">1</infon><infon key="lpage">44</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Osman;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Salim;given-names:N</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Saeed;given-names:F</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">International Journal of Soft Computing</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">12</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>65325</offset><text>Quality-Based Text Web Forum Summarization-A Review</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">613</infon><infon key="issue">11</infon><infon key="lpage">20</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Salton;given-names:G</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Wong;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Yang;given-names:C-S</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Communications of the ACM</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">18</infon><infon key="year">1975</infon><offset>65377</offset><text>A vector space model for automatic indexing</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">513</infon><infon key="issue">5</infon><infon key="lpage">23</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Salton;given-names:G</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Buckley;given-names:C</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Information processing &amp; management</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">24</infon><infon key="year">1988</infon><offset>65421</offset><text>Term-weighting approaches in automatic text retrieval</text></passage><passage><infon key="issue">32</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Obasa;given-names:AI</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Salim;given-names:N</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Khan;given-names:A</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Indian Journal of Science and Technology</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">8</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>65475</offset><text>Hybridization of Bag-of-Words and Forum Metadata for Web Forum Question Post Detection</text></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Zhou;given-names:TC</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Lin;given-names:C-Y</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:King;given-names:I</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Lyu;given-names:MR</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Song;given-names:Y-I</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Cao;given-names:Y</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Learning to Suggest Questions in Online Forums</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2011</infon><offset>65562</offset></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">66</infon><infon key="lpage">85</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Abdi;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Shamsuddin;given-names:SM</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Hasan;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Piran;given-names:J</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Expert Systems with Applications</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">109</infon><infon key="year">2018</infon><offset>65563</offset><text>Machine learning-based multi-documents sentiment-oriented summarization using linguistic treatment</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">23</infon><infon key="lpage">49</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Piskorski;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Yangarber;given-names:R</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Multi-source, multilingual information extraction and summarization</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2013</infon><offset>65662</offset></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">276</infon><infon key="issue">2</infon><infon key="lpage">88</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Bhatia;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Biyani;given-names:P</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Mitra;given-names:P</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Journal of the Association for Information Science and Technology</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">67</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>65663</offset><text>Identifying the role of individual user messages in an online discussion and its use in thread retrieval</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>65768</offset><text>Biyani P, Bhatia S, Caragea C, Mitra P, editors. Using Subjectivity Analysis to Improve Thread Retrieval in Online Forums. European Conference on Information Retrieval; 2015: Springer.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>65953</offset><text>Albaham AT, Salim N, editors. Quality biased thread retrieval using the voting model. Proceedings of the 18th Australasian Document Computing Symposium; 2013: ACM.</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">29</infon><infon key="lpage">34</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Liu;given-names:B</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Feng;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Liu;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Hu;given-names:H</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Wang;given-names:X</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Pattern Recognition Letters</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">58</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>66117</offset><text>Predicting the quality of user-generated answers using co-training in community-based question answering portals</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>66230</offset><text>Obasa AI, Salim N, Khan A, editors. Enhanced lexicon based model for web forum answer detection. Digital Information Processing and Communications (ICDIPC), 2015 Fifth International Conference on; 2015: IEEE.</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">61</infon><infon key="issue">1</infon><infon key="lpage">5</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Tavakoli;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Heydari;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Salim;given-names:N</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">World Academy of Science, Engineering and Technology, International Journal of Computer, Electrical, Automation, Control and Information Engineering</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">10</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>66439</offset><text>A Framework for Review Spam Detection Research</text></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Liu;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Cao;given-names:Y</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Lin;given-names:C-Y</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Huang;given-names:Y</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Zhou;given-names:M</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">EMNLP-CoNLL</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2007</infon><offset>66486</offset><text>Low-Quality Product Review Detection in Opinion Summarization</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>66548</offset><text>Almahy I, Salim N, editors. Web Discussion Summarization: Study Review. Proceedings of the First International Conference on Advanced Data and Information Engineering (DaEng-2013); 2014: Springer.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>66745</offset><text>Osman A, Salim N, Saeed F, Abdelhamid I, editors. Quality Features for Summarizing Text Forum Threads by Selecting Quality Replies. International Conference of Reliable Information and Communication Technology; 2018: Springer.</text></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Bhatia;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Biyani;given-names:P</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Mitra;given-names:P</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">EMNLP</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2014</infon><offset>66972</offset><text>Summarizing Online Forum Discussions-Can Dialog Acts of Individual Messages Help?</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>67054</offset><text>Altantawy M, Rafea A, Aly S, editors. Summarizing online discussions by filtering posts. Information Reuse &amp; Integration, 2009 IRI'09 IEEE International Conference on; 2009: IEEE.</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1</infon><infon key="issue">3</infon><infon key="lpage">130</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Carenini;given-names:G</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Murray;given-names:G</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Ng;given-names:R</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Synthesis Lectures on Data Management</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">3</infon><infon key="year">2011</infon><offset>67234</offset><text>Methods for mining and summarizing text conversations</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">5</infon><infon key="issue">4</infon><infon key="lpage">33</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Wang;given-names:RY</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Strong;given-names:DM</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Journal of management information systems</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">12</infon><infon key="year">1996</infon><offset>67288</offset><text>Beyond accuracy: What data quality means to data consumers</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>67347</offset><text>Chai K, Wu C, Potdar V, Hayati P, editors. Automatically measuring the quality of user generated content in forums. Australasian Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence; 2011: Springer.</text></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Bhatia;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Mitra;given-names:P</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Adopting Inference Networks for Online Thread Retrieval</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2010</infon><offset>67537</offset></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Zhang;given-names:X</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Effective search in online knowledge communities: A genetic algorithm approach</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2009</infon><offset>67538</offset></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Wang;given-names:G</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Liu;given-names:X</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Fan;given-names:W</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">A knowledge adoption model based framework for finding helpful user-generated contents in online communities</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2011</infon><offset>67539</offset></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>67540</offset><text>Lui M, Baldwin T, editors. Classifying user forum participants: Separating the gurus from the hacks, and other tales of the internet. Australasian Language Technology Association Workshop 2010; 2010.</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">67</infon><infon key="lpage">76</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Sun;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Gao;given-names:H</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Yang;given-names:X</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Web Information Systems and Mining</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2010</infon><offset>67740</offset></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>67741</offset><text>Chen Y, Cheng X-Q, Huang Y-L, editors. A wavelet-based model to recognize high-quality topics on web forum. Proceedings of the 2008 IEEE/WIC/ACM International Conference on Web Intelligence and Intelligent Agent Technology-Volume 01; 2008: IEEE Computer Society.</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">346</infon><infon key="issue">4</infon><infon key="lpage">59</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Brinton;given-names:CG</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Chiang;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Jain;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Lam;given-names:H</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Liu;given-names:Z</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Wong;given-names:FMF</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">IEEE transactions on Learning Technologies</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">7</infon><infon key="year">2014</infon><offset>68004</offset><text>Learning about social learning in MOOCs: From statistical analysis to generative model</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>68091</offset><text>Squire M, editor &quot; Should We Move to Stack Overflow?&quot; Measuring the Utility of Social Media for Developer Support. Software Engineering (ICSE), 2015 IEEE/ACM 37th IEEE International Conference on; 2015: IEEE.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>68300</offset><text>Wanas N, El-Saban M, Ashour H, Ammar W, editors. Automatic scoring of online discussion posts. Proceedings of the 2Nd ACM Workshop on Information Credibility on the Web; 2008: ACM.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>68481</offset><text>Weimer M, Gurevych I, editors. Predicting the perceived quality of web forum posts. Proceedings of the Conference on Recent Advances in Natural Language Processing (RANLP); 2007.</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">134</infon><infon key="lpage">45</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Raiber;given-names:F</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Kurland;given-names:O</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Advances in Information Retrieval</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2013</infon><offset>68660</offset></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">569</infon><infon key="issue">3</infon><infon key="lpage">86</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Ferguson;given-names:P</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Smeaton;given-names:AF</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Information Processing &amp; Management</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">48</infon><infon key="year">2012</infon><offset>68661</offset><text>Index ordering by query-independent measures</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>68706</offset><text>Yamamoto Y, Tanaka K, editors. Enhancing credibility judgment of web search results. Proceedings of the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems; 2011: ACM.</text></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Jiao;given-names:J</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">A framework for finding and summarizing product defects, and ranking helpful threads from online customer forums through machine learning</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2013</infon><offset>68878</offset></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">131</infon><infon key="lpage">46</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Subha;given-names:R</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Palaniswami;given-names:S</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Advances in Computing, Communication, and Control</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2013</infon><offset>68879</offset></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>68880</offset><text>Duan H, Zhai C, editors. Exploiting thread structures to improve smoothing of language models for forum post retrieval. European Conference on Information Retrieval; 2011: Springer.</text></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Huang;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Zhou;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Yang;given-names:D</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Extracting Chatbot Knowledge from Online Discussion Forums</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2007</infon><offset>69062</offset></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>69063</offset><text>Hong L, Davison BD, editors. A classification-based approach to question answering in discussion boards. Proceedings of the 32nd international ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in information retrieval; 2009: ACM.</text></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Brand;given-names:DJ</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Automatic Prediction of Comment Quality</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>69292</offset></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>69293</offset><text>Ismail Z, Salim N, Huspi SH, editors. Understanding human quality judgment in assessing online forum contents for thread retrieval purpose. AIP Conference Proceedings; 2017: AIP Publishing.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>69483</offset><text>Ren Z, Ma J, Wang S, Liu Y, editors. Summarizing web forum threads based on a latent topic propagation process. Proceedings of the 20th ACM international conference on Information and knowledge management; 2011: ACM.</text></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Klaas;given-names:M</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">UBC CS TR-2005</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">4</infon><infon key="year">2005</infon><offset>69700</offset><text>Toward indicative discussion fora summarization</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>69748</offset><text>Farrell R, Fairweather PG, Snyder K, editors. Summarization of discussion groups. Proceedings of the tenth international conference on Information and knowledge management; 2001: ACM.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>69932</offset><text>Zhou L, Hovy EH, editors. On the Summarization of Dynamically Introduced Information: Online Discussions and Blogs. AAAI Spring Symposium: Computational Approaches to Analyzing Weblogs; 2006.</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">170</infon><infon key="lpage">8</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Biyani;given-names:P</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Bhatia;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Caragea;given-names:C</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Mitra;given-names:P</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Knowledge-Based Systems</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">69</infon><infon key="year">2014</infon><offset>70124</offset><text>Using non-lexical features for identifying factual and opinionative threads in online forums</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>70217</offset><text>Verberne S, van den Bosch A, Wubben S, Krahmer E, editors. Automatic summarization of domain-specific forum threads: collecting reference data. Proceedings of the 2017 Conference on Conference Human Information Interaction and Retrieval; 2017: ACM.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>70466</offset><text>Grozin VA, Gusarova NF, Dobrenko NV, editors. Feature selection for language independent text forum summarization. International Conference on Knowledge Engineering and the Semantic Web; 2015: Springer.</text></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Manning;given-names:CD</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Raghavan;given-names:P</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Schütze;given-names:H</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Introduction to information retrieval</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2008</infon><offset>70669</offset></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Chai;given-names:KEK</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">A machine learning-based approach for automated quality assessment of user generated content in web forums</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2011</infon><offset>70670</offset></passage><passage><infon key="issue">1</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:OBASA;given-names:AI</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:SALIM;given-names:N</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Journal of Theoretical &amp; Applied Information Technology</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">63</infon><infon key="year">2014</infon><offset>70671</offset><text>MINING FAQ FROM FORUM THREADS: THEORETICAL FRAMEWORK</text></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Fan;given-names:W</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">A genetic algorithm approach</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2009</infon><offset>70724</offset></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">514</infon><infon key="lpage">29</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Burel;given-names:G</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:He;given-names:Y</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Alani;given-names:H</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">The Semantic Web: Research and Applications</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2012</infon><offset>70725</offset></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Ismail;given-names:Z</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Heydari;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Tavakoli;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Salim;given-names:N</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">INCORPORATING AUTHOR’S ACTIVENESS IN ONLINE DISCUSSION IN THREAD RETRIEVAL MODEL</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>70726</offset></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">690</infon><infon key="lpage">5</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Kargar;given-names:MJ</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Azimzadeh;given-names:F</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">World Academy of Science, Engineering and Technology</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">56</infon><infon key="year">2009</infon><offset>70727</offset><text>A framework for ranking quality of information on weblog</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">120</infon><infon key="issue">1</infon><infon key="lpage">45</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Waheed;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Kaur;given-names:K</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Qazi;given-names:A</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Internet Research</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">26</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>70784</offset><text>Students’ perspective on knowledge quality in eLearning context: a qualitative assessment</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>70876</offset><text>Onyeabor GA, Ta’a A, editors. A Model for Addressing Quality Issues in Big Data. International Conference of Reliable Information and Communication Technology; 2018: Springer.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>71054</offset><text>Kim J, Chern G, Feng D, Shaw E, Hovy E, editors. Mining and assessing discussions on the web through speech act analysis. Proceedings of the Workshop on Web Content Mining with Human Language Technologies at the 5th International Semantic Web Conference; 2006.</text></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Watson;given-names:C</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Wilson;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Drew;given-names:V</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Thompson;given-names:TL</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.iheduc.2016.07.005</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">The Internet and Higher Education</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>71315</offset><text>Criticality and the exercise of politeness in online spaces for professional learning</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">159</infon><infon key="issue">5</infon><infon key="lpage">72</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Knight S-a;given-names:Burn JM</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Informing Science: International Journal of an Emerging Transdiscipline</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">8</infon><infon key="year">2005</infon><offset>71401</offset><text>Developing a framework for assessing information quality on the World Wide Web</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>71480</offset><text>Weimer M, Gurevych I, editors. Predicting the perceived quality of web forum posts. Proceedings of the conference on recent advances in natural language processing; 2007.</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">4276</infon><infon key="issue">11</infon><infon key="lpage">95</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Faisal;given-names:CMS</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Daud;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Imran;given-names:F</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Rho;given-names:S</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">The Journal of Supercomputing</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">72</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>71651</offset><text>A novel framework for social web forums’ thread ranking based on semantics and post quality features</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">5432</infon><infon key="issue">3</infon><infon key="lpage">5</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Chen;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Huang;given-names:H</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Tian;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Qu;given-names:Y</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Expert Systems with Applications</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">36</infon><infon key="year">2009</infon><offset>71754</offset><text>Feature selection for text classification with Naïve Bayes</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>71814</offset><text>Joachims T, editor Text categorization with support vector machines: Learning with many relevant features. European conference on machine learning; 1998: Springer.</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1</infon><infon key="issue">1</infon><infon key="lpage">37</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Wu;given-names:X</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Kumar;given-names:V</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Ross Quinlan;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Ghosh;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Yang;given-names:Q</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Motoda;given-names:H</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Knowledge and information systems</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">14</infon><infon key="year">2008</infon><offset>71978</offset><text>Top 10 algorithms in data mining</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">231</infon><infon key="lpage">47</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Shmilovici;given-names:A</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Data Mining and Knowledge Discovery Handbook</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2010</infon><offset>72011</offset><text>Support vector machines</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">159</infon><infon key="issue">3</infon><infon key="lpage">90</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Kotsiantis;given-names:SB</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Zaharakis;given-names:ID</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Pintelas;given-names:PE</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Artificial Intelligence Review</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">26</infon><infon key="year">2006</infon><offset>72035</offset><text>Machine learning: a review of classification and combining techniques</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">371</infon><infon key="lpage">6</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Shirsat;given-names:VS</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Jagdale;given-names:RS</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Deshmukh;given-names:SN</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Computing, Communication and Signal Processing</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2019</infon><offset>72105</offset></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">37</infon><infon key="issue">3</infon><infon key="lpage">46</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Ting;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Ip;given-names:W</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Tsang;given-names:AH</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">International Journal of Software Engineering and Its Applications</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">5</infon><infon key="year">2011</infon><offset>72106</offset><text>Is Naive Bayes a good classifier for document classification?</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>72168</offset><text>Rish I, editor An empirical study of the naive Bayes classifier. IJCAI 2001 workshop on empirical methods in artificial intelligence; 2001: IBM New York.</text></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Kharde;given-names:V</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Sonawane;given-names:P</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">arXiv preprint arXiv:160106971</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>72322</offset><text>Sentiment analysis of twitter data: a survey of techniques</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">48</infon><infon key="issue">1</infon><infon key="lpage">59</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Xu;given-names:S</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Journal of Information Science</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">44</infon><infon key="year">2018</infon><offset>72381</offset><text>Bayesian Naïve Bayes classifiers to text classification</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">256</infon><infon key="issue">2</infon><infon key="lpage">61</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Patil;given-names:TR</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Sherekar;given-names:S</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">International journal of computer science and applications</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">6</infon><infon key="year">2013</infon><offset>72438</offset><text>Performance analysis of Naive Bayes and J48 classification algorithm for data classification</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">130</infon><infon key="issue">3</infon><infon key="lpage">7</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Porter;given-names:MF</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Program</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">14</infon><infon key="year">1980</infon><offset>72531</offset><text>An algorithm for suffix stripping</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">16</infon><infon key="issue">1</infon><infon key="lpage">28</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Chandrashekar;given-names:G</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Sahin;given-names:F</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Computers &amp; Electrical Engineering</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">40</infon><infon key="year">2014</infon><offset>72565</offset><text>A survey on feature selection methods</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>72603</offset><text>Parlar T, Özel SA, editors. A new feature selection method for sentiment analysis of Turkish reviews. INnovations in Intelligent SysTems and Applications (INISTA), 2016 International Symposium on; 2016: IEEE.</text></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Kolchyna;given-names:O</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Souza;given-names:TT</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Treleaven;given-names:P</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Aste;given-names:T</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">arXiv preprint arXiv:150700955</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>72813</offset><text>Twitter sentiment analysis: Lexicon method, machine learning method and their combination</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>72903</offset><text>Hall MA, Smith LA, editors. Practical feature subset selection for machine learning. Computer science’98 proceedings of the 21st Australasian computer science conference ACSC; 1998.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>73087</offset><text>Meesad P, Boonrawd P, Nuipian V, editors. A chi-square-test for word importance differentiation in text classification. Proceedings of International Conference on Information and Electronics Engineering; 2011.</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">15</infon><infon key="lpage">20</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Sharma;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Dey;given-names:S</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">IJCA Special Issue on Advanced Computing and Communication Technologies for HPC Applications</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">3</infon><infon key="year">2012</infon><offset>73297</offset><text>Performance investigation of feature selection methods and sentiment lexicons for sentiment analysis</text></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Al-Harbi;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Almuhareb;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Al-Thubaity;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Khorsheed;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Al-Rajeh;given-names:A</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Automatic Arabic text classification</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2008</infon><offset>73398</offset></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Powers;given-names:DM</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Evaluation: from precision, recall and F-measure to ROC, informedness, markedness and correlation</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2011</infon><offset>73399</offset></passage></document></collection>
