<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd">
<collection><source>PMC</source><date>20201220</date><key>pmc.key</key><document><id>6620884</id><infon key="license">CC BY</infon><passage><infon key="article-id_doi">10.2196/14950</infon><infon key="article-id_pmc">6620884</infon><infon key="article-id_pmid">31250828</infon><infon key="article-id_publisher-id">v21i6e14950</infon><infon key="elocation-id">e14950</infon><infon key="issue">6</infon><infon key="license">This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License (https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/), which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original work, first published in the Journal of Medical Internet Research, is properly cited. The complete bibliographic information, a link to the original publication on http://www.jmir.org/, as well as this copyright and license information must be included.</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Washington;given-names:Peter</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Kalantarian;given-names:Haik</infon><infon key="name_10">surname:Paskov;given-names:Kelley</infon><infon key="name_11">surname:Voss;given-names:Catalin</infon><infon key="name_12">surname:Haber;given-names:Nick</infon><infon key="name_13">surname:Wall;given-names:Dennis Paul</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Tariq;given-names:Qandeel</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Schwartz;given-names:Jessey</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Dunlap;given-names:Kaitlyn</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Chrisman;given-names:Brianna</infon><infon key="name_6">surname:Varma;given-names:Maya</infon><infon key="name_7">surname:Ning;given-names:Michael</infon><infon key="name_8">surname:Kline;given-names:Aaron</infon><infon key="name_9">surname:Stockham;given-names:Nathaniel</infon><infon key="section_type">TITLE</infon><infon key="type">front</infon><infon key="volume">21</infon><infon key="year">2019</infon><offset>0</offset><text>Addendum to the Acknowledgements: Validity of Online Screening for Autism: Crowdsourcing Study Comparing Paid and Unpaid Diagnostic Tasks</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>138</offset><text>The authors of “Validity of Online Screening for Autism: Crowdsourcing Study Comparing Paid and Unpaid Diagnostic Tasks” (J Med Internet Res 2019;21(5):e13668) missed an important source of funding in the Acknowledgments section — Wu Tsai Neurosciences Institute Neuroscience: Translate Program. The revised Acknowledgments section now appears as follows:</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>500</offset><text>We thank all the crowd workers and citizen scientists who participated in the studies. These studies were supported by awards to DW by the National Institutes of Health (1R21HD091500-01 and 1R01EB025025-01). Additionally, we acknowledge the support of grants to DW from The Hartwell Foundation, the David and Lucile Packard Foundation Special Projects Grant, Beckman Center for Molecular and Genetic Medicine, Coulter Endowment Translational Research Grant, Berry Fellowship, Spectrum Pilot Program, Stanford’s Precision Health and Integrated Diagnostics Center (PHIND), Wu Tsai Neurosciences Institute Neuroscience: Translate Program, and Stanford’s Institute of Human Centered Artificial Intelligence as well as philanthropic support from Mr. Peter Sullivan. HK would like to acknowledge support from the Thrasher Research Fund and Stanford NLM Clinical Data Science program (T-15LM007033-35).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>1400</offset><text>The correction will appear in the online version of the paper on the JMIR website on June 27, 2019, together with the publication of this correction notice. Because this was made after submission to PubMed, PubMed Central, and other full-text repositories, the corrected article also has been resubmitted to those repositories.</text></passage></document></collection>
