<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd">
<collection><source>PMC</source><date>20201224</date><key>pmc.key</key><document><id>6913768</id><infon key="license">CC BY</infon><passage><infon key="article-id_doi">10.2196/13027</infon><infon key="article-id_pmc">6913768</infon><infon key="article-id_pmid">31596245</infon><infon key="article-id_publisher-id">v5i4e13027</infon><infon key="elocation-id">e13027</infon><infon key="issue">4</infon><infon key="kwd">gay-friendly doctors social media crowdsourcing prototype evaluation men who have sex with men China</infon><infon key="license">This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License (https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/), which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original work, first published in JMIR Public Health and Surveillance, is properly cited. The complete bibliographic information, a link to the original publication on http://publichealth.jmir.org, as well as this copyright and license information must be included.</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Eysenbach;given-names:Gunther</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Davoudi;given-names:Anis</infon><infon key="name_10">surname:Stoneking;given-names:Shelby</infon><infon key="name_11">surname:Tang;given-names:Weiming</infon><infon key="name_12">surname:Luo;given-names:Zhenzhou</infon><infon key="name_13">surname:Wei;given-names:Chongyi</infon><infon key="name_14">surname:Tucker;given-names:Joseph</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Cheng;given-names:Qijin</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Kwan;given-names:Tsz Ho</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Wu;given-names:Dan</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Huang;given-names:Wenting</infon><infon key="name_6">surname:Zhao;given-names:Peipei</infon><infon key="name_7">surname:Li;given-names:Chunyan</infon><infon key="name_8">surname:Cao;given-names:Bolin</infon><infon key="name_9">surname:Wang;given-names:Yifan</infon><infon key="section_type">TITLE</infon><infon key="type">front</infon><infon key="volume">5</infon><infon key="year">2019</infon><offset>0</offset><text>A Crowdsourced Physician Finder Prototype Platform for Men Who Have Sex with Men in China: Qualitative Study of Acceptability and Feasibility</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract_title_1</infon><offset>142</offset><text>Background</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>153</offset><text>Men who have sex with men (MSM), including both gay and bisexual men, have a high prevalence of HIV and sexually transmitted infections (STIs) in China. However, healthcare seeking behaviors and engagement in clinical services among MSM are often suboptimal. Global evidence shows that embedding online HIV or sexual health services into gay social networking applications holds promise for facilitating higher rates of healthcare utilization among MSM. We developed a prototype of a gay-friendly health services platform, designed for integration within a popular gay social networking app (Blued) in China.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract_title_1</infon><offset>762</offset><text>Objective</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>772</offset><text>The purpose of this study was to evaluate the acceptability of the platform and ask for user feedback through focus group interviews with young MSM in Guangzhou and Shenzhen, cities in Southern China.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract_title_1</infon><offset>973</offset><text>Methods</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>981</offset><text>The prototype was developed through an open, national crowdsourcing contest. Open crowdsourcing contests solicit community input on a topic in order to identify potential improvements and implement creative solutions. The prototype included a local, gay-friendly, STI physician finder tool and online psychological consulting services. Semistructured focus group discussions were conducted with MSM to ask for their feedback on the platform, and a short survey was administered following discussions. Thematic analysis was used to analyze the data in NVivo, and we developed a codebook based on the first interview. Double coding was conducted, and discrepancies were discussed with a third individual until consensus was reached. We then carried out descriptive analysis of the survey data.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract_title_1</infon><offset>1773</offset><text>Results</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>1781</offset><text>A total of 34 participants attended four focus group discussions. The mean age was 27.3 years old (SD 4.6). A total of 32 (94%) participants obtained at least university education, and 29 (85%) men had seen a doctor at least once before. Our survey results showed that 24 (71%) participants had interest in using the online health services platform and 25 (74%) thought that the system was easy to use. Qualitative data also revealed that there was a high demand for gay-friendly healthcare services which could help with care seeking. Men felt that the platform could bridge gaps in the existing HIV or STI service delivery system, specifically by identifying local gay-friendly physicians and counselors, providing access to online physician consultation and psychological counseling services, creating space for peer support, and distributing pre-exposure prophylaxis and sexual health education.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract_title_1</infon><offset>2681</offset><text>Conclusions</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>2693</offset><text>Crowdsourcing can help develop a community-centered online platform linking MSM to local gay-friendly HIV or STI services. Further research on developing social media–based platforms for MSM and evaluating the effectiveness of such platforms may be useful for improving sexual health outcomes.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>2989</offset><text>Introduction</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>3002</offset><text>HIV prevalence has steadily increased among men who have sex with men (MSM) in China. According to a national estimate, the prevalence increased from 1.2% in 2003 to 7.8% in 2016. However, healthcare seeking behaviors and engagement in clinical services among MSM are often suboptimal. Many MSM living with HIV in China have poor retention along the HIV care continuum. Limited knowledge of HIV and HIV care, stigma against people living with HIV and against nonheterosexual practices, and lack of navigation guidance in the health system are commonly identified factors that contribute to attrition along the HIV care cascade. A Chinese study also revealed men’s concerns about inadvertent disclosure of their sexual orientation.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>3735</offset><text>Electronic health technologies (ie, electronic Health [eHealth]) have become a common platform for behavioral interventions because of their wide coverage, convenience, and low cost. eHealth programs use an electronic device or information technologies to provide their services. Among MSM, eHealth interventions may be even more appealing because of the anonymity and the protection of their confidentiality.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>4145</offset><text>Many MSM in China use the internet to find sexual partners, creating an opportunity for online sexual health promotion. Several studies suggest that MSM are interested in using eHealth tools for HIV prevention or sexual health promotion and would be willing to share personal information on the use of such apps. A cross-sectional survey of MSM in the United States in 2015 found that over 80% of the participants had an interest in embedding tools for finding lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, and queer (LGBTQ)-friendly doctors, and for directly consulting with physicians, into their social apps. Lists of LGBTQ-friendly physicians are now available in the United States and several other high-income countries. However, there has not been as much research done on the development of eHealth interventions that help men find gay-friendly physicians in middle-income countries.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>5028</offset><text>Given the need for improving MSM’s linkage to services, we developed a prototype of a platform designed to be embedded within a popular gay social app (Blued) in China. The goal of the platform was to facilitate higher rates of healthcare utilization among MSM by identifying local gay-friendly health services. The platform presents Blued users with a list of gay-friendly doctors endorsed by community members who have used their services. The platform allows users to seek online counseling or schedule in-person appointments. The purpose of this study was to evaluate the acceptability of the platform and ask for user feedback through focus group discussions with young MSM in two major cities in Southern China.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>5748</offset><text>Methods</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>5756</offset><text>Participant Recruitment</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>5780</offset><text>Both convenience and purposive sampling strategies were used to recruit men who were willing to share their experiences and perspectives. By using a qualitative approach, we did not aim to generalize the study results to the wider community but instead to have a better understanding of some key issues. In focus group discussions, group interactions and dynamics facilitate rich information generation, which can help establish a range of perceptions on a topic of interest. Thus, we conducted a total of four focus groups, each made up of 8-10 MSM, to evaluate the platform. Two focus groups were conducted in Shenzhen and two were conducted in Guangzhou, both cities in Southern China's Guangdong Province. Men were recruited through local community-based organizations (CBOs) that work with MSM in Shenzhen and Guangzhou. Recruitment was conducted both on-site and via an announcement on WeChat, an instant messaging mobile app which has a widespread posting function like Twitter. Participants were considered eligible for the study if they met the following criteria: (1) aged 18 years or older; (2) born biologically male; (3) have had sex with a man at least once; and (4) currently residing in Guangzhou or Shenzhen, China. Other purposive sampling criteria included whether they disclosed their sexual orientation to others (yes/no), whether they had ever been tested for HIV before (yes/no), and past experiences of seeing a physician (within 1 year, 1-2 years, 2-5 years, and never saw a physician before).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>7299</offset><text>Platform Development</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>7320</offset><text>The prototype of the health-seeking mobile platform was developed based on submissions to an open crowdsourcing contest, which was held from March 1, 2018 to March 25, 2018. Open crowdsourcing contests ask for community input on a topic to identify potential improvements and implement creative solutions. The contest was promoted through social media announcements on WeChat. We solicited submissions about the function, content, and design of the platform, but specifically, we collected ideas for the name, logo, slogan, and features of the platform. Figure 1 shows the start page of the prototype, which includes the name, logo, and slogan. Submissions were voted on by the public through social media and then evaluated by a panel consisting of public health researchers, a representative from a local LGBT CBO, and a Blued developer. Using the winning name, slogan, logo, and function content, we created a prototype for a health seeking platform tailored for MSM. Please see Multimedia Appendix 1 for details on the contest.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>8352</offset><text>The mobile platform, as the most exceptional design product of the contest, had the following main functions: (1) it could identify local sexually transmitted infections (STI) physician services; (2) it provided online psychological consulting services; and (3) it created a network for peer communication and support. The local physician finder connected users to nearby gay-friendly physicians, and users could sort and view physician profiles by specialty (HIV and other STIs), user recommendations, and distance from their location. For the consulting feature, users could choose different forms of service delivery, including online, via phone call, and via an in-person appointment. The psychological consulting service feature aimed to provide support and mental health care for MSM navigating life as a sexual minority in China (eg, psychologists might provide advice on methods for disclosing sexual orientation to friends and family). Peer communication and support aimed to facilitate peer-led online communications within the platform, and users could anonymously ask and answer questions about sexual health, coming out, health services, and so on.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">publichealth_v5i4e13027_fig1.jpg</infon><infon key="id">figure1</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>9514</offset><text>Start page of the prototype.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>9543</offset><text>Focus Group Discussion</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>9566</offset><text>The focus group discussions were conducted in a private conference room and facilitated by two researchers experienced in qualitative research. Each interview lasted between one and two hours. Snacks and drinks were provided to ease participant burden and build rapport. We explained the purpose of the study and stressed confidentiality to participants, and written consent was obtained before the focus group discussion began. Then, we played a video showing the features of the online healthcare seeking platform and asked the men to share their reactions (see Multimedia Appendix 2). The focus group discussions focused on evaluating the acceptability and feasibility of the early product of the crowdsourcing contest rather than the contest method. A topic guide was used to guide the overall structure of the interview, but discussions were kept relatively open, and participants were invited to provide any feedback they thought might be relevant for improving the platform. A short survey on the acceptability and usability (perceived ease of use) of the platform was collected following the focus group discussions. Perceived ease-of-use is an important construct of usability and positively affects user acceptability of information technology. The survey was used to triangulate the qualitive findings as an approach to enhance validity. Each participant received a small monetary award of ¥50 (7.50 United States Dollars) for their participation. We ceased focus group discussions once we reached thematic saturation.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>11097</offset><text>Data Analysis</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>11111</offset><text>The focus group discussions were audio-recorded and transcribed, then a thematic analysis of the transcripts was conducted. We developed an initial code framework based on the interview guide and applied this code to the first interview. In addition to predetermined codes, during the first coding process we also used an inductive coding approach to allow unexpected codes to emerge from the raw data. The revised codebook, consisting of predefined and inductive-derived codes, was then applied to the remaining transcripts. All transcripts were double coded by DW and PZ, and discrepancies were discussed with a third independent individual (WH). We then read and organized the coded text to find themes and subthemes, and selected relevant quotes were then translated into English. Nvivo 12 software (QSR International, Melbourne) was used to carry out all qualitative data analysis. Descriptive analysis was conducted to analyze survey data using SPSS version 25 (IBM, New York).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>12095</offset><text>Ethical Statement</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>12113</offset><text>This study received approval from institutional review boards at the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill and Southern Medical University Dermatology Hospital.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>12280</offset><text>Results</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>12288</offset><text>Participant Characteristics</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>12316</offset><text>A total of 34 participants attended four focus group discussions. Table 1 shows the participants characteristics. The mean age was 27.3 years old (SD 4.6). At the time of the focus group discussions 18 (53%) men were living in Guangzhou and 16 (47%) men were living in Shenzhen. A total of 33 (97%) individuals self-identified as male and one self-identified as female. In addition, 32 (94%) had obtained at least a university education, 7 (21%) men were students, and 20 (59%) earned an annual salary of $14,052 or less. Overall, 27 (79%) men took at least one HIV test in the past 12 months, and 29 (85%) men had seen a doctor at least once before. Among them, 18/29 (62%) had never disclosed their sexual orientation to health professionals and 15/29 (52%) were satisfied with their last physician encounter.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">table1.xml</infon><infon key="id">table1</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_caption</infon><offset>13128</offset><text>Demographic characteristics of focus group discussion participants in China, 2018 (N=34).</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">table1.xml</infon><infon key="id">table1</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table</infon><infon key="xml">&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;table frame=&quot;hsides&quot; rules=&quot;groups&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; cellpadding=&quot;5&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; border=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;col width=&quot;30&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col width=&quot;570&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col width=&quot;400&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Characteristics&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Value&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Age in years (mean, SD)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;27.3 (4.6)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt;City, n (%)&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;break/&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;break/&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Guangzhou&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;18 (53)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;break/&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Shenzhen&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;16 (47)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt;Gender identity, n (%)&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;break/&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;break/&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Male&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;33 (97)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;break/&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Female&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1 (3)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt;Sexual orientation, n (%)&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;break/&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;break/&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Men who only have sex with men&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;32 (94)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;break/&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Bisexual&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1 (3)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;break/&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Not sure&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1 (3)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt;Highest education, n (%)&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;break/&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;break/&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;High school&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;2 (6)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;break/&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;University&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;27 (79)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;break/&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Postgraduate&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;5 (15)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt;Annual income (USD), n (%)&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;break/&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;break/&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;3516&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;6 (18)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;break/&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;3516-8784&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;7 (21)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;break/&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;8784-14052&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;7 (21)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;break/&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;14052&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;14 (41)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt;Employment status, n (%)&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;break/&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;break/&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Student&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;7 (21)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;break/&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Employed&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;26 (77)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;break/&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Unemployed&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1 (3)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt;Ethnicity, n (%)&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;break/&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;break/&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Han&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;32 (94)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;break/&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Non-Han&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;2 (6)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt;Number of HIV tests done in past 12 months, n (%)&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;break/&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;break/&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;7 (21)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;break/&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;10 (29)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;break/&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;11 (32)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;break/&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;4 or above&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;6 (18)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt;Last time saw a physician, n (%)&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;break/&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;break/&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Within 1 year&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;25 (74)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;break/&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1-2 years&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;3 (9)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;break/&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;2-5 years&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1 (3)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;break/&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Never&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;5 (15)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt;Sexual orientation disclosure to your physician (N=29), n (%)&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;break/&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;break/&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;11 (38)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;break/&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;18 (62)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt;Degree of satisfaction with last experience of seeing a doctor time (N=29), n (%)&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;break/&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;break/&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Very satisfied&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;5 (17)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;break/&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Satisfied&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;10 (35)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;break/&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Neutral&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;14 (48)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
</infon><offset>13218</offset><text>Characteristics	Value	 	Age in years (mean, SD)	27.3 (4.6)	 	City, n (%)		 		Guangzhou	18 (53)	 		Shenzhen	16 (47)	 	Gender identity, n (%)		 		Male	33 (97)	 		Female	1 (3)	 	Sexual orientation, n (%)		 		Men who only have sex with men	32 (94)	 		Bisexual	1 (3)	 		Not sure	1 (3)	 	Highest education, n (%)		 		High school	2 (6)	 		University	27 (79)	 		Postgraduate	5 (15)	 	Annual income (USD), n (%)		 		&lt;3516	6 (18)	 		3516-8784	7 (21)	 		8784-14052	7 (21)	 		&gt;14052	14 (41)	 	Employment status, n (%)		 		Student	7 (21)	 		Employed	26 (77)	 		Unemployed	1 (3)	 	Ethnicity, n (%)		 		Han	32 (94)	 		Non-Han	2 (6)	 	Number of HIV tests done in past 12 months, n (%)		 		0	7 (21)	 		1	10 (29)	 		2	11 (32)	 		4 or above	6 (18)	 	Last time saw a physician, n (%)		 		Within 1 year	25 (74)	 		1-2 years	3 (9)	 		2-5 years	1 (3)	 		Never	5 (15)	 	Sexual orientation disclosure to your physician (N=29), n (%)		 		Yes	11 (38)	 		No	18 (62)	 	Degree of satisfaction with last experience of seeing a doctor time (N=29), n (%)		 		Very satisfied	5 (17)	 		Satisfied	10 (35)	 		Neutral	14 (48)	 	</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>14309</offset><text>Acceptability</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>14323</offset><text>Table 2 shows participants’ responses to the survey questions. We found that 24/34 (71%) participants showed interest in using an online health services platform, and the prototype of the platform we presented was highly acceptable to our participants. Qualitative interviews revealed that there was a high demand for gay-friendly healthcare services, and men commented that a platform linking online and offline gay-friendly healthcare services would encourage healthcare seeking behaviors.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>14817</offset><text>Further, privacy and confidentiality were considered to be well protected by the security measures of the platform. For example, participant 2 from group one in Shenzhen commented that the:</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>15007</offset><text>two most important features of this platform are privacy protection and gay-friendly services.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>15102</offset><text>Allowing a user to seek health information securely and anonymously with this online platform was particularly helpful to alleviate fears of being discriminated or judged (see Multimedia Appendix 3, Box 1, Quote 1).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>15318</offset><text>Participants expected that such a platform would help expand men’s access to in-person health services. One man said that:</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>15443</offset><text>This platform is meaningful because if I know that there are gay-friendly services in other hospitals, I don’t have to confine my access in one specific hospital.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>15608</offset><text>Another participant from the same group mentioned that such a platform was a necessity for those who had already developed relevant STI symptoms and felt anxious about finding out the cause (see Multimedia Appendix 3, Box 1, Quote 2).</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">table2.xml</infon><infon key="id">table2</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_caption</infon><offset>15843</offset><text>Acceptability and perceived usability of the online health care seeking prototype platform by MSMa in China, 2018 (N=34). All values are given as n (%).</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">table2.xml</infon><infon key="id">table2</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table</infon><infon key="xml">&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;table frame=&quot;hsides&quot; rules=&quot;groups&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; cellpadding=&quot;5&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; border=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;col width=&quot;410&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col width=&quot;140&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col width=&quot;100&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col width=&quot;100&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col width=&quot;100&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col width=&quot;150&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Acceptability and perceived usability items&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Strongly agree&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Agree&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Neutral&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Disagree&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Strongly disagree&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;I am willing to use this platform frequently&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;7 (21)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;17 (50)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;7 (21)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;3 (9)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0 (0)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;I think this platform is unnecessarily complicated&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;3 (9)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;5 (15)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;10 (29)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;15 (44)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1(3)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;I think this platform is easy to use&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;6 (18)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;19 (56)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;8 (24)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0 (0)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0 (0)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;I think that I would need the support of a technical person to be able to use this system&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1 (3)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0 (0)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;2 (6)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;16 (47)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;15 (44)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;I find the various functions in this system are well integrated&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;6 (18)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;11 (32)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;16 (47)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1 (3)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0 (0)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;I think there is too much inconsistency in the system&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;3 (9)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;2 (6)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;11 (32)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;17 (50)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1 (3)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;I would imagine that most people would learn to use this system very quickly&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;10 (29)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;18 (53)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;4 (12)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;2 (6)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0 (0)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;I find the system very cumbersome to use&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0 (0)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0 (0)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;2 (6)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;22 (65)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;10 (29)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;I feel very confident using the system&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;12 (35)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;16 (47)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;4 (12)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1 (3)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0 (0.0)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;I think I need to learn a lot of things before I can get going with this system&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1 (3)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;2 (6)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;4 (12)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;17 (50)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;9 (27)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
</infon><offset>15996</offset><text>Acceptability and perceived usability items	Strongly agree	Agree	Neutral	Disagree	Strongly disagree	 	I am willing to use this platform frequently	7 (21)	17 (50)	7 (21)	3 (9)	0 (0)	 	I think this platform is unnecessarily complicated	3 (9)	5 (15)	10 (29)	15 (44)	1(3)	 	I think this platform is easy to use	6 (18)	19 (56)	8 (24)	0 (0)	0 (0)	 	I think that I would need the support of a technical person to be able to use this system	1 (3)	0 (0)	2 (6)	16 (47)	15 (44)	 	I find the various functions in this system are well integrated	6 (18)	11 (32)	16 (47)	1 (3)	0 (0)	 	I think there is too much inconsistency in the system	3 (9)	2 (6)	11 (32)	17 (50)	1 (3)	 	I would imagine that most people would learn to use this system very quickly	10 (29)	18 (53)	4 (12)	2 (6)	0 (0)	 	I find the system very cumbersome to use	0 (0)	0 (0)	2 (6)	22 (65)	10 (29)	 	I feel very confident using the system	12 (35)	16 (47)	4 (12)	1 (3)	0 (0.0)	 	I think I need to learn a lot of things before I can get going with this system	1 (3)	2 (6)	4 (12)	17 (50)	9 (27)	 	</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">table2.xml</infon><infon key="id">table2</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_footnote</infon><offset>17042</offset><text>aMSM: men who have sex with men.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>17075</offset><text>Perceived Usability</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>17095</offset><text>About three quarters (25/34, 74%) of men thought that the system was easy to use and only one (3%) commented that he would need technical support to be able to use it. Half of them regarded the various functions of the platform as well integrated. Most men (28/34, 82%) felt confident about using it.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>17396</offset><text>Specific Functions of the Platform</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>17431</offset><text>We asked for participants’ views towards the functions of the prototype, specifically about physician consultation services, psychological support and consulting services, and peer communication and support. Participants tended to view peer communication and support as a part of psychological counselling services. Additionally, we found that men were interested in pre-exposure prophylaxis (PrEP) services and sexual health education.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>17870</offset><text>Physician Consultation Services</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>17902</offset><text>Participants discussed the various forms and timing of service delivery, quality of services, and desirable types of health services. Many men showed preferences for audio or video consultations compared to text-image consultations, as the former was thought to be more efficient (Multimedia Appendix 3, Box 2, Quotes 1 and 2). Others felt a combination of all forms would be most acceptable (Multimedia Appendix 3, Box 2, Quote 3). Participants expressed concerns about delayed service delivery via the platform due to the demands of a physicians’ schedule (Multimedia Appendix 3, Box 2, Quote 4). Appointment services may mitigate such concerns and would be important for ensuring prompt service delivery (Multimedia Appendix 3, Box 2, Quote 5). In terms of quality of services, the qualifications of physicians and recognition by a public medical authority were the most essential considerations for participants (Multimedia Appendix 3, Box 2, Quotes 6 and 7).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>18868</offset><text>Men expressed a desire for services relevant to sexual health and homosexual practices from the platform. Several particular services were preferred, including HIV or STI testing and treatment, anorectal services, urology, and relevant dermatological services (Multimedia Appendix 3, Box 2, Quote 8). One group in Shenzhen described that long-term, follow-up services were especially necessary for elderly patients and those living with chronic conditions, such as people living with HIV (Multimedia Appendix 3, Box 2, Quote 9 and 10).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>19404</offset><text>Psychological Support and Consultations</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>19444</offset><text>To facilitate a more comprehensive analysis, we divided this issue of psychological services into peer support and professional consultations. Participants acknowledged that there is a great need for mental health care, but that gay-friendly psychological services were lacking (Multimedia Appendix 3, Box 3, Quotes 1 and 2). Some attributed nondisclosure of sexual orientation to the health professions’ lack of capacity to deal with mental health issues (Multimedia Appendix 3, Box 3, Quote 3). A man from group 1 in Guangzhou said that:</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>19986</offset><text>You can provide peer counselling first, then move to professionals.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>20054</offset><text>According to the same participant, peer counselling was “free and easier to find”, while “professional consultation services are more expensive”. Another participant from group 1 responded:</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>20252</offset><text>They (professionals) are standing in a high position and looking down, and we would feel pressure or even be subject to discrimination, which makes it worse.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>20410</offset><text>However, other men from group 2 in Guangzhou disagreed, saying that “peers are far from professional” (Participant 1). Professional psychological consultations were considered to be most useful as a resource for the coming out process and for treating mental disorders such as depression (Multimedia Appendix 3, Box 3, Quotes 4 and 5).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>20750</offset><text>Pre-Exposure Prophylaxis</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>20775</offset><text>Additionally, although not an aspect of the prototype design, men mentioned the necessity of providing both educational information and accessibility for PrEP. Group 1 in Guangzhou mentioned that “both PrEP and PEP services should be strengthened” and this platform could be a good channel for promotion and education. However, risk compensation, like having more condomless sex, was also recognized by our participants (group 1 in Guangzhou).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>21223</offset><text>Sexual Health Education</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>21247</offset><text>Health education about HIV and sexual health was thought to be an important platform function. This function is particularly important for those who have recently identified as gay and have limited knowledge about safe sex practices. Men suggested that such a feature include information about HIV, methods of HIV prevention, and other safe sex practices (Multimedia Appendix 3, Box 4, Quotes 1 and 2). Providing educational information about HIV might generate interest in using the platform because of its relevance to potential users’ daily lives (Multimedia Appendix 3, Box 4, Quote 3). They also showed interest in information about coping with HIV infection and navigating life either as, or with, a partner living with HIV (Multimedia Appendix 3, Box 4, Quote 4).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>22020</offset><text>Discussion</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>22031</offset><text>Principal Results</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>22049</offset><text>Many MSM delay seeking necessary healthcare and have difficulty finding gay-friendly physician services, and few interventions focus on linking MSM to local health services in low-and-middle income countries. We collected qualitative and survey data to evaluate men’s acceptability and usability of a crowdsourced social media–based eHealth intervention tailored to MSM. This study extends the literature by evaluating men’s acceptability of an online health service prototype that aims to link MSM to local health services in China.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>22589</offset><text>We found that an online healthcare platform which links online to offline services was highly acceptable among our participants. This is consistent with previous research in China and the United States. We identified three main reasons for strong interest in the platform. First, as an online platform tailored to MSM, it provided a channel for anonymously seeking sexual health services, which may have mitigated some of the hesitation about using facility-based services, as men are fearful of health professional discrimination in traditional clinics. Second, a platform where men can comfortably disclose their sexual history holds promise for reducing such fears and facilitating help seeking. Third, the crowdsourced platform provided a mechanism to compile all local, gay-friendly, sexual, and psychological health services into a single platform. This simplified the process of finding a gay-friendly doctor.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>23506</offset><text>We also found that most men felt the platform was easy to use and were confident in their ability to use it, which is like findings from previous literature on eHealth platforms supporting HIV patient self-management. Levels of ease-of-use in health information technology significantly affect a customer’s intention to engage, and it is important for MSM to continue using a health app over time. We developed the prototype platform based on our previous crowdsourcing contests. Crowdsourcing is an effective approach to improve community engagement in sexual health promotion and HIV prevention programs. This community-centered platform design approach may contribute to a user-friendly health information product; however, another reason may be that our participants were young adults who were well educated and skilled at using complicated products. The usability of the prototype platform among elderly groups, those with poor health literacy, or those with little experience with using mobile phones is still unknown.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>24533</offset><text>Men in our study desired help in finding physicians and services related to PrEP. This is consistent with earlier findings of high demand for PrEP among MSM in China. PrEP services are not currently approved by the China Food and Drug Administration and are largely unavailable in the country, but several pilot programs in developed cities suggest that there is growing demand. Strong evidence has confirmed the efficacy of PrEP in preventing HIV acquisition in key populations, and the World Health Organization recommends PrEP for use in MSM. Thus, incorporating information about PrEP into eHealth platforms may be useful.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>25160</offset><text>Limitations</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>25172</offset><text>Our study has several limitations. First, we evaluated men’s acceptability and perceived usability by describing the platform, showing a short video, and providing a PowerPoint presentation. Men were not able to download the platform within the Blued environment, however, acceptance of various platforms was found, in earlier research, to be correlated to actual eHealth use. Second, a qualitative study design has limited generalizability. Quantitative evaluations are needed to further determine community acceptance. Additionally, our focus group discussions only recruited men from two Chinese cities. Our subjects were mainly young, had higher education, and had a higher income. Thus, the results may not reflect views of MSM with different sociodemographic backgrounds and in other social contexts. Finally, we assessed one major construct of usability and did not evaluate other aspects such as learnability, operability, and understandability. Usability should be more comprehensively evaluated when the platform becomes available for men to use.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>26231</offset><text>Implications</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>26244</offset><text>More research is called for to help develop eHealth programs to meet MSM’s needs for sexual health services. Linking local, gay-friendly health services to MSM via social media platforms may be a promising approach to encourage necessary healthcare seeking. Further developing the platform, monitoring actual use by MSM, and refining the platform are also worthy of exploration. In addition, PrEP services are an important strategy to prevent HIV spread and the men in our study showed a great interest in PrEP, which both indicates a need to introduce it into China’s healthcare system and the establishment of supportive policies. Preparing men for PrEP by incorporating relevant information and services into the platform is also worthy of consideration. Meanwhile, integrating a gay-friendly physician finder with an MSM social networking app may introduce ethical concerns, as approval from the Chinese Food and Drug Administration is necessary for online health service provision. In summary, developing platforms that can be embedded into social media apps for MSM may be useful for improving the HIV care cascade and sexual health.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">footnote</infon><offset>27388</offset><text>Authors' Contributions: JDT led the project. BC, PZ and YW led the design and development of the prototype platform. DW, WH, PZ, SS, ZL and WT collected data. DW, WH, and PZ analyzed data. DW, CL and WH wrote and revised this manuscript. Other authors provided constructive comments and edited the manuscript, and all authors approved the final version.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">footnote</infon><offset>27742</offset><text>Conflicts of Interest: None declared.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">APPENDIX</infon><infon key="type">title</infon><offset>27780</offset><text>Appendix</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABBR</infon><infon key="type">title</infon><offset>27789</offset><text>Abbreviations</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABBR</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>27803</offset><text>CBO</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABBR</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>27807</offset><text>community-based organization</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABBR</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>27836</offset><text>eHealth</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABBR</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>27844</offset><text>electronic health</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABBR</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>27862</offset><text>LGBTQ</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABBR</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>27868</offset><text>lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, and queer</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABBR</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>27915</offset><text>MSM</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABBR</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>27919</offset><text>men who have sex with men</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABBR</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>27945</offset><text>PrEP</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABBR</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>27950</offset><text>pre-exposure prophylaxis</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABBR</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>27975</offset><text>STIs</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABBR</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>27980</offset><text>sexually transmitted infections</text></passage><passage><infon key="comment">2015 China AIDS Response Progress Reporthttp://www.unaids.org/sites/default/files/country/documents/CHN_narrative_report_2015.pdf</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">National Health and Family Planning Commission of the People’s Republic of China</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>28012</offset></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">701</infon><infon key="issue">3</infon><infon key="lpage">710</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Wong;given-names:NS</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Mao;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Cheng;given-names:W</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Tang;given-names:W</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Cohen;given-names:MS</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Tucker;given-names:JD</infon><infon key="name_6">surname:Xu;given-names:H</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1007/s10461-017-1893-4</infon><infon key="pub-id_medline">28849284</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">AIDS Behav</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">22</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>28013</offset><text>HIV Linkage to Care and Retention in Care Rate Among MSM in Guangzhou, China</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">372</infon><infon key="issue">3</infon><infon key="lpage">378</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Wei;given-names:C</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Yan;given-names:H</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Yang;given-names:C</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Raymond;given-names:HF</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Li;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Yang;given-names:H</infon><infon key="name_6">surname:Zhao;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_7">surname:Huan;given-names:X</infon><infon key="name_8">surname:Stall;given-names:R</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1080/09540121.2013.824538</infon><infon key="pub-id_medline">23909807</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">23909807</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">AIDS Care</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">26</infon><infon key="year">2013</infon><offset>28090</offset><text>Accessing HIV testing and treatment among men who have sex with men in China: A qualitative study</text></passage><passage><infon key="issue">1</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Xu;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Ming;given-names:Z</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Zhang;given-names:Y</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Wang;given-names:P</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Jing;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Cheng;given-names:F</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1186/s40249-017-0364-5</infon><infon key="pub-id_medline">29157301</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Infect Dis Poverty</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">6</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>28188</offset><text>Family support, discrimination, and quality of life among ART-treated HIV-infected patients: a two-year study in China</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1118</infon><infon key="issue">9</infon><infon key="lpage">1121</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Zhang;given-names:D</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Li;given-names:C</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Meng;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Qi;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Fu;given-names:X</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Sun;given-names:J</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1080/09540121.2014.902420</infon><infon key="pub-id_medline">24684294</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">24684294</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">AIDS Care</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">26</infon><infon key="year">2014</infon><offset>28307</offset><text>Attrition of MSM with HIV/AIDS along the continuum of care from screening to CD4 testing in China</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">221</infon><infon key="issue">3</infon><infon key="lpage">8</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Zhang;given-names:Y</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Fan;given-names:Y</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Dai;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Li;given-names:B</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Xu;given-names:W</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Hu;given-names:L</infon><infon key="name_6">surname:Liu;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_7">surname:Su;given-names:H</infon><infon key="name_8">surname:Ye;given-names:D</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1111/ijn.12254</infon><infon key="pub-id_medline">24621391</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">24621391</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Int J Nurs Pract</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">21</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>28405</offset><text>HIV/AIDS stigma among older PLWHA in south rural China</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">70</infon><infon key="issue">2</infon><infon key="lpage">7</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Liu;given-names:Y</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Osborn;given-names:CY</infon><infon key="name_10">surname:Amico;given-names:KR</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Qian;given-names:H</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Yin;given-names:L</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Xiao;given-names:D</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Ruan;given-names:Y</infon><infon key="name_6">surname:Simoni;given-names:JM</infon><infon key="name_7">surname:Zhang;given-names:X</infon><infon key="name_8">surname:Shao;given-names:Y</infon><infon key="name_9">surname:Vermund;given-names:SH</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1089/apc.2015.0296</infon><infon key="pub-id_medline">26784360</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">26784360</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">AIDS Patient Care STDS</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">30</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>28460</offset><text>Barriers and Facilitators of Linkage to and Engagement in HIV Care Among HIV-Positive Men Who Have Sex with Men in China: A Qualitative Study</text></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Noar;given-names:SM</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Harrington;given-names:NG</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">eHealth Applications: Promising Strategies for Behavior Change</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2012</infon><offset>28602</offset><text>Building an evidence base for eHealth applications: Research Questions and Practice Implications</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">244</infon><infon key="issue">2</infon><infon key="lpage">51</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Blaya;given-names:JA</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Fraser;given-names:HS</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Holt;given-names:B</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1377/hlthaff.2009.0894</infon><infon key="pub-id_medline">20348068</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">20348068</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Health Aff (Millwood)</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">29</infon><infon key="year">2010</infon><offset>28699</offset><text>E-health technologies show promise in developing countries</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">885</infon><infon key="issue">4</infon><infon key="lpage">894</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Zou;given-names:H</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Fan;given-names:S</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1007/s10508-016-0709-3</infon><infon key="pub-id_medline">27043837</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">27043837</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Arch Sex Behav</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">46</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>28758</offset><text>Characteristics of Men Who Have Sex With Men Who Use Smartphone Geosocial Networking Applications and Implications for HIV Interventions: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">926</infon><infon key="issue">7</infon><infon key="lpage">30</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Nehl;given-names:EJ</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:He;given-names:N</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Wang;given-names:X</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Lin;given-names:L</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Wong;given-names:FY</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Yu;given-names:F</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1080/09540121.2012.726344</infon><infon key="pub-id_medline">23061806</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">23061806</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">AIDS Care</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">25</infon><infon key="year">2013</infon><offset>28934</offset><text>Feasibility and willingness of using e-technologies for HIV prevention and research targeting Chinese MSM</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">e100</infon><infon key="issue">4</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Muessig;given-names:KE</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Bien;given-names:CH</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Wei;given-names:C</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Lo;given-names:EJ</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Yang;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Tucker;given-names:JD</infon><infon key="name_6">surname:Yang;given-names:L</infon><infon key="name_7">surname:Meng;given-names:G</infon><infon key="name_8">surname:Hightow-Weidman;given-names:LB</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.2196/jmir.3370</infon><infon key="pub-id_medline">25900881</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">25900881</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Med Internet Res</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">17</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>29040</offset><text>A mixed-methods study on the acceptability of using eHealth for HIV prevention and sexual health care among men who have sex with men in China</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">3384</infon><infon key="issue">10</infon><infon key="lpage">3394</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Ventuneac;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:John;given-names:SA</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Whitfield;given-names:THF</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Mustanski;given-names:B</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Parsons;given-names:JT</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1007/s10461-018-2171-9</infon><infon key="pub-id_medline">29948335</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">29948335</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">AIDS Behav</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">22</infon><infon key="year">2018</infon><offset>29183</offset><text>Preferences for Sexual Health Smartphone App Features Among Gay and Bisexual Men</text></passage><passage><infon key="comment">Health Professionals Advancing LGBTQ Equalityhttp://www.glma.org/index.cfm?fuseaction=Page.viewPage&amp;pageId=532</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">GLMA</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2019</infon><offset>29264</offset></passage><passage><infon key="comment">Supporting LGBTIQ health and well-beinghttps://www.glhv.org.au/</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Rainbow Health Victoria</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2019</infon><offset>29265</offset></passage><passage><infon key="comment">Trans Friendly Doctors and GP’s Registerhttps://transfigurations.org.uk/trans-friendly-doctors/</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Transfigurations</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2019</infon><offset>29266</offset></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">299</infon><infon key="issue">7000</infon><infon key="lpage">302</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Kitzinger;given-names:J</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1136/bmj.311.7000.299</infon><infon key="pub-id_medline">7633241</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">7633241</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">BMJ</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">311</infon><infon key="year">1995</infon><offset>29267</offset><text>Qualitative research. Introducing focus groups</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">e113</infon><infon key="issue">3</infon><infon key="lpage">e115</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Tucker;given-names:JD</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Fenton;given-names:KA</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/S2352-3018(18)30027-4</infon><infon key="pub-id_medline">29519613</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">29519613</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Lancet HIV</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">5</infon><infon key="year">2018</infon><offset>29314</offset><text>Innovation challenge contests to enhance HIV responses</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Crowdsourcing in health and health research: a practical guide</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2018</infon><offset>29369</offset></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">319</infon><infon key="issue">3</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Davis;given-names:FD</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.2307/249008</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">MIS Quarterly</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">13</infon><infon key="year">1989</infon><offset>29370</offset><text>Perceived Usefulness, Perceived Ease of Use, and User Acceptance of Information Technology</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">77</infon><infon key="issue">2</infon><infon key="lpage">101</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Braun;given-names:V</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Clarke;given-names:V</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1191/1478088706qp063oa</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Qualitative Research in Psychology</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">3</infon><infon key="year">2006</infon><offset>29461</offset><text>Using thematic analysis in psychology</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">389</infon><infon key="issue">4</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Rosengren;given-names:AL</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Huang;given-names:E</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Daniels;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Young;given-names:SD</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Marlin;given-names:RW</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Klausner;given-names:JD</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1071/sh15236</infon><infon key="pub-id_medline">27209076</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Sex. Health</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">13</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>29499</offset><text>Feasibility of using GrindrTM to distribute HIV self-test kits to men who have sex with men in Los Angeles, California</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">S98</infon><infon key="lpage">S103</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Feng;given-names:Y</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Wu;given-names:Z</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Detels;given-names:R</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1097/qai.0b013e3181c7df71</infon><infon key="pub-id_medline">20104118</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">20104118</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">JAIDS Journal of Acquired Immune Deficiency Syndromes</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">53</infon><infon key="year">2010</infon><offset>29618</offset><text>Evolution of Men Who Have Sex With Men Community and Experienced Stigma Among Men Who Have Sex With Men in Chengdu, China</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">527</infon><infon key="issue">8</infon><infon key="lpage">533</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Watson;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Tang;given-names:W</infon><infon key="name_10">surname:Tucker;given-names:JD</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Pan;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Wu;given-names:D</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Zhao;given-names:P</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Cao;given-names:B</infon><infon key="name_6">surname:Liu;given-names:C</infon><infon key="name_7">surname:Bien;given-names:C</infon><infon key="name_8">surname:Huang;given-names:W</infon><infon key="name_9">surname:Luo;given-names:Z</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1097/OLQ.0000000000000808</infon><infon key="pub-id_medline">29465638</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">29465638</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Sex Transm Dis</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">45</infon><infon key="year">2018</infon><offset>29740</offset><text>Out of the Closet, Into the Clinic: Opportunities for Expanding Men Who Have Sex With Men-Competent Services in China</text></passage><passage><infon key="issue">4</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Swendeman;given-names:Dallas</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Farmer;given-names:Shu</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Mindry;given-names:Deborah</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Lee;given-names:Sung-Jae</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Medich;given-names:Melissa</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.16966/2380-5536.127</infon><infon key="pub-id_medline">28066820</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J HIV AIDS</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">2</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>29858</offset><text>HIV Care Providers' Attitudes regarding Mobile Phone Applications and Web-Based Dashboards to support Patient Self-Management and Care Coordination: Results from a Qualitative Feasibility Study</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">e133</infon><infon key="issue">5</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Kim;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Park;given-names:H</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.2196/jmir.2143</infon><infon key="pub-id_medline">23026508</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">23026508</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Med Internet Res</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">14</infon><infon key="year">2012</infon><offset>30052</offset><text>Development of a health information technology acceptance model using consumers' health behavior intention</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">e128</infon><infon key="issue">4</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Mitchell;given-names:JW</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Torres;given-names:MB</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Joe;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Danh;given-names:T</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Gass;given-names:B</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Horvath;given-names:KJ</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.2196/mhealth.6178</infon><infon key="pub-id_medline">27852558</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">27852558</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">JMIR Mhealth Uhealth</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">4</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>30159</offset><text>Formative Work to Develop a Tailored HIV Testing Smartphone App for Diverse, At-Risk, HIV-Negative Men Who Have Sex With Men: A Focus Group Study</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1436</infon><infon key="issue">11</infon><infon key="lpage">1442</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Tang;given-names:W</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Han;given-names:L</infon><infon key="name_10">surname:Galler;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_11">surname:Yang;given-names:L</infon><infon key="name_12">surname:Peeling;given-names:R</infon><infon key="name_13">surname:Volberding;given-names:P</infon><infon key="name_14">surname:Ma;given-names:B</infon><infon key="name_15">surname:Xu;given-names:H</infon><infon key="name_16">surname:Yang;given-names:B</infon><infon key="name_17">surname:Huang;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_18">surname:Fenton;given-names:K</infon><infon key="name_19">surname:Wei;given-names:C</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Best;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_20">surname:Tucker;given-names:JD</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Zhang;given-names:Y</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Mollan;given-names:K</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Kim;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_6">surname:Liu;given-names:F</infon><infon key="name_7">surname:Hudgens;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_8">surname:Bayus;given-names:B</infon><infon key="name_9">surname:Terris-Prestholt;given-names:F</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1093/cid/ciw171</infon><infon key="pub-id_medline">27129465</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">27129465</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Clin Infect Dis</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">62</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>30305</offset><text>Crowdsourcing HIV Test Promotion Videos: A Noninferiority Randomized Controlled Trial in China</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">227</infon><infon key="issue">4</infon><infon key="lpage">237</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Pan;given-names:SW</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Stein;given-names:G</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Bayus;given-names:B</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Tang;given-names:W</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Mathews;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Wang;given-names:C</infon><infon key="name_6">surname:Wei;given-names:C</infon><infon key="name_7">surname:Tucker;given-names:JD</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1136/bmjinnov-2017-000203</infon><infon key="pub-id_medline">29576873</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">BMJ Innov</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">3</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>30400</offset><text>Systematic review of innovation design contests for health: spurring innovation and mass engagement</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">166</infon><infon key="issue">2</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Holt;given-names:M</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1071/sh13060</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">23866853</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Sex. Health</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">11</infon><infon key="year">2014</infon><offset>30500</offset><text>HIV pre-exposure prophylaxis and treatment as prevention: a review of awareness and acceptability among men who have sex with men in the Asia-Pacific region and the Americas</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">2904</infon><infon key="issue">16</infon><infon key="lpage">2889</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Mou;given-names:Y</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Xu;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Ma;given-names:Y</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Modern Preventive Medicine</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">44</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>30674</offset><text>Cohort retention in HIV pre-exposure prophylaxis clinical trial among men who have sex with men</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">53</infon><infon key="issue">10013</infon><infon key="lpage">60</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:McCormack;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Dunn;given-names:DT</infon><infon key="name_10">surname:Mackie;given-names:N</infon><infon key="name_11">surname:Bowman;given-names:C</infon><infon key="name_12">surname:Lacey;given-names:CJ</infon><infon key="name_13">surname:Apea;given-names:V</infon><infon key="name_14">surname:Brady;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_15">surname:Fox;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_16">surname:Taylor;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_17">surname:Antonucci;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_18">surname:Khoo;given-names:SH</infon><infon key="name_19">surname:Rooney;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Desai;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_20">surname:Nardone;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_21">surname:Fisher;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_22">surname:McOwan;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_23">surname:Phillips;given-names:AN</infon><infon key="name_24">surname:Johnson;given-names:AM</infon><infon key="name_25">surname:Gazzard;given-names:B</infon><infon key="name_26">surname:Gill;given-names:ON</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Dolling;given-names:DI</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Gafos;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Gilson;given-names:R</infon><infon key="name_6">surname:Sullivan;given-names:AK</infon><infon key="name_7">surname:Clarke;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_8">surname:Reeves;given-names:I</infon><infon key="name_9">surname:Schembri;given-names:G</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/s0140-6736(15)00056-2</infon><infon key="pub-id_medline">26364263</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">The Lancet</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">387</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>30770</offset><text>Pre-exposure prophylaxis to prevent the acquisition of HIV-1 infection (PROUD): effectiveness results from the pilot phase of a pragmatic open-label randomised trial</text></passage><passage><infon key="comment">Consolidated guidelines on the use of antiretroviral drugs for treating and preventing HIV infection: Recommendations for a public health approach-Second editionhttps://www.who.int/hiv/pub/arv/arv-2016/en/</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">World Health Organization</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>30936</offset></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">A</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Mburu;given-names:S</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1109/AFRCON.2017.8095535</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">IEEE</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>30937</offset><text>A predictive model for optimizing acceptance and use of mHealth interventions in low-resource settings: A case of Mamacare prototype</text></passage></document></collection>
