<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd">
<collection><source>PMC</source><date>20220218</date><key>pmc.key</key><document><id>7333788</id><infon key="license">NO-CC CODE</infon><passage><infon key="article-id_doi">10.1007/s12553-020-00456-z</infon><infon key="article-id_pmc">7333788</infon><infon key="article-id_pmid">32837807</infon><infon key="article-id_publisher-id">456</infon><infon key="fpage">1115</infon><infon key="issue">5</infon><infon key="kwd">Disease outbreaks Communicable diseases Crowdsourcing Mobile applications</infon><infon key="license">This article is made available via the PMC Open Access Subset for unrestricted research re-use and secondary analysis in any form or by any means with acknowledgement of the original source. These permissions are granted for the duration of the World Health Organization (WHO) declaration of COVID-19 as a global pandemic.</infon><infon key="lpage">1127</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Khedo;given-names:Kavi</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Baichoo;given-names:Shakuntala</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Nagowah;given-names:Soulakshmee Devi</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Mungloo-Dilmohamud;given-names:Zahra</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Cadersaib;given-names:Zarine</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Cheerkoot-Jalim;given-names:Sudha</infon><infon key="name_6">surname:Nagowah;given-names:Leckraj</infon><infon key="name_7">surname:Sookha;given-names:Lownish</infon><infon key="section_type">TITLE</infon><infon key="title">Keywords</infon><infon key="type">front</infon><infon key="volume">10</infon><infon key="year">2020</infon><offset>0</offset><text>DOT: a crowdsourcing Mobile application for disease outbreak detection and surveillance in Mauritius</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>101</offset><text>Early detection of disease outbreaks is crucial and even small improvements in detection can significantly impact on a country’s public health. In this work, we investigate the use of a crowdsourcing application and a real-time disease outbreak surveillance system for five diseases; Influenza, Gastroenteritis, Upper Respiratory Tract Infection (URTI), Scabies and Conjunctivitis, that are closely monitored in Mauritius. We also analyze and correlate the collected data with past statistics. A crowdsourcing mobile application known as Disease Outbreak Tracker (DOT) was implemented and made public. A real-time disease surveillance system using the Early Aberration Reporting System algorithm (EARS) for analysis of the collected data was also implemented. The collected data were correlated to historical data for 2017. Data were successfully collected and plotted on a daily basis. The results show that a few cases of Flu and Scabies were reported in some districts. The EARS methods C1, C2 and C3 also depicted spikes above the set threshold on some days. The study covers data collected over a period of one month. Once symptoms data were collected using DOT, probabilistic methods were used to find the disease or diseases that the user was suffering from. The data were further processed to find the extent of the disease outbreak district-wise, per disease. These data were represented graphically for a rapid understanding of the situation in each district. Our findings concur with existing data for the same period for previous years showing that the crowdsourcing application can aid in the detection of disease outbreaks.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>1741</offset><text>Introduction</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>1754</offset><text>Despite breakthroughs in the field of medicine to prevent and cure different types of diseases, the fear of outbreaks is ever present. This is due to several factors such as the dynamic and volatile nature of viruses and bacteria or the harsh and abrupt changes in weather. To be able to detect or fight these diseases, surveillance is of utmost importance. Disease surveillance is the ongoing scrutiny and monitoring of clinical syndromes that have a significant impact on medical resource allocation and health policy. Disease surveillance ensures that prompt intervention is done for the control of diseases in order to contain the outbreak and minimize any potential harm. It comprises the continuous methodical collection, organization, analysis and interpretation of disease data and often involves big data. With the COVID-19 pandemic affecting most countries around the world, disease surveillance systems are gaining momentum. Such systems aim at rapidly identifying possible cases of infectious diseases, which can help health practitioners and authorities to take timely decisions. Now more than ever, simple and easily accessible disease surveillance systems are required which can also reach countries with high resource constraints.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>3001</offset><text>Surveillance systems can be categorized into disease-specific surveillance systems, syndromic surveillance systems and event-based surveillance systems. The traditional surveillance systems are disease-specific. Data standardization is required for such systems. Reporting from traditional systems is normally not open to the public due to the fact that individuals might not be able to correctly identify the disease they are suffering from. Syndromic surveillance, on the other hand, is more real-time than the traditional surveillance and requires no laboratory confirmation. Reporting from syndromic surveillance systems can be deployed at large and certain methods can be used to correlate the syndromes to a corresponding disease. Event-based surveillance consists of “the real-time or near-real time scanning, collection, and analysis of unstructured information from diverse Internet sources (such as news or online discussion platforms) for detecting potential or confirmed health hazards occurring worldwide from reports and rumours”.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>4050</offset><text>With the recent technological advances leading to a decrease in the cost of mobile phones and easy access to social media, event-based surveillance systems are on the rise. People are increasingly using social networks such as Twitter, Facebook and LinkedIn amongst others to share their experiences and opinions on a variety of different things, including healthcare-related topics like health conditions, symptoms, treatments and side-effects. Social media is thus producing massive amounts of data at an unparalleled scale and this is an attractive resource for obtaining interesting healthcare insights and health hazards information. When one’s family member is suffering from a specific disease or in the case of an outbreak, a person tends to search or write about the disease as well as the related symptoms on her/his favorite social network. The analysis of structured and unstructured data from these social networks is referred to as social media analytics. After the advent of Web 2.0 in the early 2000s, social media analytics has emerged with data centric nature being a key characteristic.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>5158</offset><text>Social media analytics spread over several disciplines such as psychology, sociology, anthropology, computer science, mathematics, physics, and economics and even politics. Data can be analyzed using online and offline services. Systems such as DEFENDER and ORBiT make use of social network data such as Twitter. Ramanathan et al. examined the use of the diagnostic data to reveal spatial and temporal patterns of how the 2009 H1N1 pandemic affected the USA. ORBiT was used to identify, quantify and describe spatial and temporal patterns of the 2009–2010 pandemic H1N1 flu within the United States. It was observed that the integration of heterogeneous data sources, including publicly accessible sources, could provide timely and novel information regarding influenza pandemic. As reported by Boulos et al., “in Cambodia, the Ministry of Health uses GeoChat for disease reporting and to send staff alerts and rapidly escalate response to potential outbreaks, while in Thailand, more than 900 facilities within the Hospital Network exchange information and get alerts to monitor influenza outbreaks in real-time from facilities across the country.”</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>6314</offset><text>However, there are several challenges regarding the analysis of social media data. Twitter, for example, poses several challenges, since streams contain large amounts of meaningless messages, polluted content and rumors, which negatively affect the detection performance. Moreover, traditional text mining techniques are less suitable for Twitter, because of the short length of the tweets, the large number of spelling and grammatical errors as well as the frequent use of informal, irregular and abbreviated words, and the use of improper sentence structure and mixed language. Moreover, in the context of Big Data Analytics (BDA) from social networks, several issues are raised. Some of these include advances in scale-out systems, data models and high-level abstractions, incremental processing, scalability, resource sharing and classification of social networks. Real-time data analytics poses a number of challenges due to the fact that the resulting actions are usually based on the current and previous situations. In other words, the system needs to react instantly based on what is happening in terms of data being updated. The main challenges are transfer of data events in real-time, incomplete data, analysis of the large volume of data, scalability and infrastructural issues, visualization of the results, and the decision-making. The data events can be transferred from the social networks as raw events or as filtered or aggregated events. Real-time analytical services need to deploy fast algorithms that provide alternative options within a bounded time. For effective visualization, data can be grouped together instead of plotting points on a graph, which may be difficult when dealing with extremely large amounts of information or a variety of categories of information. As far as the decision-making process is concerned, it may be automated or not depending on the type of application, for example, for the disease surveillance it will require some level of human inputs. In fact, in most clinical systems, advanced real time analytics has not been incorporated.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>8403</offset><text>Crowdsourcing is an online and distributed sourcing model in which individuals or organizations use contributions from Internet users to obtain needed services or ideas. It allows large-scale and flexible invocation of human input for data gathering and analysis, which introduces a new paradigm of data mining process. Crisis map is a crowdsourcing platform, designed to do information collection, analysis of mass data and display in a straightforward way in real time during a crisis. A few examples of crowdsourcing platforms include: CrowdSource, Figure Eight (formerly CrowdFlower), CrowdForge, CrowdWeaver, the Amazon Mechanical Turk (MTurk) and Crowdbreaks. The types of data mining tasks that can be accomplished using crowdsourcing are classification, clustering, semi-supervised learning and association-rule mining. In the context of healthcare applications, some mobile crowdsourcing applications include HealthMap’s Outbreaks Near Me, Sickweather, Flu Near You, UH-BigDataSys, Stop Corona! and Mo-Buzz.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>9422</offset><text>A good way to complement a surveillance system is to allow patients to input their medical condition to a centralized system, which is capable of keeping an eye over the country. A very practical way to allow this is to implement a mobile application accessible to all for sending the data. With the prevailing use of smartphones, it is now easy for anyone to use a mobile application to upload their medical condition to the system. Sensing application domains using mobile phone is being used in healthcare. Schwind et al. present a local media surveillance, which might be related to possible outbreak situations. Google Trends can be used in a similar way such that specific terms associated to the diseases are monitored in a localized region. This data source can complement disease outbreak detection. A script is run to capture the search interest of the respective terms throughout a time period and saved in a MySQL database. This can be combined with data from official sources.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>10412</offset><text>Objectives</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>10423</offset><text>Despite the small size of Mauritius, it takes time to collect and process data, and there is usually a few weeks’ time lag before the actual data becomes available. Furthermore, the diseases’ estimates are not updated on a regular basis. Early detection of a pandemic is critical because it allows faster communication between policy makers and the public and provides more time to prepare in case of an outbreak. In 2005–2006, the Chikungunya infected a large number of people in Mauritius, causing the death of a few. The country was faced with a major outbreak in February/March 2006 following a minor outbreak in April/May 2005. Since August 2006, the country has not registered any other Chikungunya outbreak. Similarly, the A/H1N1 flu pandemic caused at least 69 infections and 8 deaths on the island in 2009.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>11245</offset><text>Currently, there is no integrated Health Information System (HIS) in Mauritius, thus the data of daily visits and interventions are not stored electronically on a centralized system anywhere. Hence, in the case of any infectious disease outbreak, pandemic situation is detected when it has already infected many people. News about a high number of cases registered for Flu, Gastroenteritis or Conjunctivitis, for example, are reported in the press only when the Ministry of Health has already registered around a few thousands of such cases and it is already quite late to contain the disease. To date, there is no automated surveillance system for any infectious disease being used in Mauritius although social media is extensively used in Mauritius.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>11997</offset><text>The aim of this paper is therefore to present the features of a real-time disease outbreak surveillance system based on a crowdsourcing mobile application. A mobile application has been developed based on some major infectious diseases monitored by the health authorities (identified through the stakeholders’ workshop), namely Influenza, Gastroenteritis, Scabies, URTI and Conjunctivitis. The methodology, design principles, implementation details and results are discussed in subsequent sections. The system provides a real-time visual analysis, which can guide the authorities (Communicable Diseases Control Unit) to take prompt decision and provide the necessary healthcare service and advice to the public in general, thus help in the prevention of an outbreak situation.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>12776</offset><text>It should be noted that the data collected through the mobile crowdsourcing application are unconfirmed cases and will be used solely to provide an indication of a possible disease outbreak as is the case with rumor-based and event-based disease outbreak surveillance system. Data from the real-time disease outbreak surveillance system will have to be correlated with the notifiable disease registers that contain confirmed cases being notified by qualified health professionals. Indeed, the system will be beneficial to the Communicable Diseases Control Unit as a complementary tool to track disease outbreak.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>13388</offset><text>Methodology</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>13400</offset><text>Literature Review: An extensive literature review was conducted to explore the various data analytics techniques used for disease outbreak surveillance, with a focus on event-based surveillance and social media analytics. Related works on healthcare-related crowdsourcing applications have also been reviewed. Existing crowdsourcing platforms and applications designed for disease outbreak surveillance have been investigated.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>13827</offset><text>Requirements Gathering: To have a better understanding of the current methods used for disease monitoring in Mauritius, a stakeholders’ workshop was carried out. Participants included representatives from various departments of the Ministry of Health and Quality of Life and the Pharmaceutical Division, WHO representatives, as well as representatives from public and private hospitals. The aim of the workshop was to identify the sources of information used for disease monitoring, the types of analysis carried out and the involvement of medical and pharmaceutical institutions. The workshop was also helpful to finalize the list of diseases to be monitored for a possible outbreak.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>14514</offset><text>Analysis and Mapping of Symptoms: The crowdsourcing application to be developed will monitor the shortlisted diseases, namely Influenza, Gastroenteritis, URTI, Scabies and Conjunctivitis. However, members of the public contributing to the application may not appropriately know the disease they are suffering from. They will therefore be required to only report their symptoms. The mapping between symptoms and diseases is done by the application. Since some people might not suffer from all symptoms of a particular disease, a probabilistic approach was devised for the correlation. To limit the discrepancies of the symptoms to disease mapping, only submissions with an accuracy of 70% and above were considered.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>15229</offset><text>Mobile Application Design: A user-friendly crowdsourcing mobile application has been designed to allow users to select and submit the different symptoms they are suffering from. Users also have to enter their location upon their first use to easily localize cases of outbreaks, if any. The submissions are clustered into localized regions according to the location of users and the data are analyzed. To avoid duplication of data, a daily restriction of one submission per user is imposed by the application. The extent of the disease outbreak can be visualized district-wise for each of the diseases using the Early Aberration Reporting System (EARS) algorithm. Feature scaling was used to standardize the data to a particular scale to allow better interpretation of the recorded data.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>16016</offset><text>Application Deployment: The mobile application is deployed on the Android platform. It is named DOT (Disease Outbreak Tracker) and an appropriate, comprehensive logo has been designed for it. The authentication and database services are offered by Firebase, which is an open-source cloud storage service.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>16321</offset><text>Application Promotion: As a pilot phase, DOT was mainly advertised to University students through emails, on the university website and on social media and was hosted on Google Play Store. Following feedback received from the first release, a second release was deployed after addressing the issues encountered by users. There were 94 installs with 167 set of symptoms being reported for the period May 2018 to December 2018.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>16747</offset><text>In order to develop the real-time disease outbreak surveillance system, the following methodology has been adopted.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>16863</offset><text>DOT crowdsourcing Mobile application</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>16900</offset><text>The primary purpose of the DOT crowdsourcing mobile application is to enable the general public to report diseases in real time. Since the public might be ignorant of the actual nature of a disease, the application does not include a list of diseases but a list of symptoms for a set of diseases. As mentioned in the previous section, the stakeholders advised that the application focuses on Influenza, Gastroenteritis, URTI, Scabies and Conjunctivitis. Consequently, the mobile application lists a set of symptoms for these diseases. The mobile application was initially tested among the members of the research group and was then published on Google PlayStore to be made available to the general public.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">12553_2020_456_Fig1_HTML.jpg</infon><infon key="id">Fig1</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>17606</offset><text>Main Screen</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">12553_2020_456_Fig2_HTML.jpg</infon><infon key="id">Fig2</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>17618</offset><text>About Us</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>17627</offset><text>The main screen of the DOT mobile application (Fig.1) provides a Sign-in feature, a short description of the mobile application and a link to the About Us page (Fig. 2).</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">12553_2020_456_Fig3_HTML.jpg</infon><infon key="id">Fig3</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>17798</offset><text>Google Sign-in</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">12553_2020_456_Fig4_HTML.jpg</infon><infon key="id">Fig4</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>17813</offset><text>Report Symptoms</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>17829</offset><text>Google Sign-in (Fig. 3) has been integrated in the DOT mobile application and it allows users to authenticate with the Firebase database by using their Google Accounts. The users can select one of the many Google accounts set up on the mobile device or may also proceed by creating a new account. During registration, users also have to select the location (district) they are from. The reporting screen is shown in Fig. 4. It displays the symptoms for the most common infectious diseases in Mauritius: Conjunctivitis, URTI, Scabies and Gastro-Enteritis together with some general regular sickness symptoms. A brief description of the symptoms are also provided to help people in reporting the most appropriate symptoms.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">12553_2020_456_Fig5_HTML.jpg</infon><infon key="id">Fig5</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>18552</offset><text>Firebase Database</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>18570</offset><text>Though the philosophy behind crowdsourcing applications is that users would honestly contribute with accurate data, such applications are, however, always prone to malicious users submitting fabricated data or launching various sorts of attacks. As a means to limit the submission of inaccurate data, only one submission per user is allowed per day. The data are stored on the Firebase database in the format shown in Fig. 5.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>18997</offset><text>All the reported symptoms are saved on the path “Individual Report”. Under this path, the data are categorized based on the submission date and then on the location of the user which the latter chose upon registration. Under a specific location, the Firebase’s unique Id is saved and finally all the submitted symptoms are saved at the end of the tree. This tree enables the application to know whether a submission has already been made for a specific user.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>19462</offset><text>To be able to analyze the submitted information, the data generated from the mobile application is migrated to a MySQL database for easier processing. Every submission is then evaluated to determine the probability of the closest disease. Every disease has its own set of symptoms Ri, with cardinality ri where 1 ≤ i ≤ 5. The reported symptoms form a separate set, say R. R is then intersected with each Ri. Considering the cardinality of each intersected set to be xi, the probability x that the reportee is suffering from any of the diseases is computed as:</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">12553_2020_456_Fig6_HTML.jpg</infon><infon key="id">Fig6</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>20034</offset><text>Extracted Disease with Probabilities</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>20071</offset><text>Based on the submitted symptoms, the disease having the highest probability is then considered. The data, excluding the symptoms, are then saved in a new table (Fig. 6) along with the corresponding disease. This data in this table is hence ready for applying the surveillance algorithms as shown in the next section.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>20389</offset><text>Disease outbreak analysis methods</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>20423</offset><text>EARS is an outbreak detection model which analyses the standard deviation of the data recorded on a daily basis. This model has two key factors, which play an important role in the system. It requires a baseline, which demarcates the situation as an outbreak or not. The baseline is decided upon aspects such as population and risk factors. The second factor is the flow of data. The model requires data from at least the last 7 consecutive days for the computation. Lack of any such data will result in impairment of detecting an outbreak. The criteria for an outbreak is when the current data exceed the baseline. In EARS, there are three detection methods, which are differentiated by their level of rigidity. The three methods are described as follows.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>21180</offset><text>C1-Mild provides the least rigid algorithm among the 3 methods. C1 method requires the data of the last 7 consecutive days to determine if this foresees any possible outbreak given the current situation. An alarm is triggered when the current data exceeds three sample deviations from the sample mean, that is, C1(t) &gt; 3.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>21506</offset><text>C2-Medium works in a similar way as C1, except that it leaves a 2-days gap before considering the 7 days required for computational purposes. This gap decreases the possibility of any biasing of the data from the last 2 days. The 7 days taken are more likely to be an “outbreak-free” observed count. An alarm is again triggered when the current count exceeds three sample deviations from the sample mean.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>21918</offset><text>C3-Ultra is the method with the most rigidity and is more likely to detect an outbreak first, in comparison to the previous 2 methods. C3 is a combination of historical and current data. It requires the current observed count as well as the C2 values of the previous 2 days. In this case, a possible outbreak is detected when C3 &gt; 2. A limitation of this method is that there cannot be any gap while the data are being collected. In case (for some reasons), data were not recorded for a particular day, the observed count is considered to be zero, but this will highly affect the detection. A way to counter this is to neglect such days in the timeline and maintain a non-zero continuity.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>22612</offset><text>The EARS method has been used for the analysis of the crowdsourcing data obtained from mobile application for the five diseases being monitored.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>22757</offset><text>Results and discussions</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">12553_2020_456_Fig7_HTML.jpg</infon><infon key="id">Fig7</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>22781</offset><text>The symptoms reported in May 2018</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">12553_2020_456_Fig8_HTML.jpg</infon><infon key="id">Fig8</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>22815</offset><text>The highest number of reporting was for Flu</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">12553_2020_456_Fig9_HTML.jpg</infon><infon key="id">Fig9</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>22859</offset><text>Disease Reported by Districts</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">12553_2020_456_Fig10_HTML.jpg</infon><infon key="id">Fig10</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>22889</offset><text>Data visualization for the flu data collected using the mobile application, based on the EARS methods</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>22991</offset><text>Data were collected using the DOT crowdsourcing mobile application in May 2018 and were plotted on a daily basis over the said period, as shown in Figs. 7, 8, 9 and 10. A total of 208 users had subscribed to the system.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>23212</offset><text>Figure 7 shows the symptoms reported by users. It can be observed that the most common symptoms reported during this period were cough, fever, running nose and sore throat. From Fig. 8, it was observed that 100 users reported Flu symptoms, which amounts to about 50% of the users. Given that these data represent reporting done during the period of May when there is a change in climate (summer to winter), with a higher incidence of Flu like symptoms, this correlation is further supported with the results in Fig. 8.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>23732</offset><text>Most of the reporting for all the districts were Flu as shown in Fig. 9. However, in one of the districts, a number of cases were reported for Scabies as well. Due to the number of cases reported being quite low as well as the duration of the reporting, no conclusion can be drawn in this case. It is expected that as more users will register on the system there will be more reported number of cases for each of the diseases and therefore better disease outbreak analysis can be performed.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>24223</offset><text>Figure 10 depicts the EARS computation for Flu, using data from 5th May to 20th May 2018. The threshold for plausible outbreak is set at 3 for C1 and C2 method, while C3 method has its threshold at 2. On 7th May, all three methods faced a spike, due to a sudden high number of submissions. Since C1 is the method with least rigidity, it was the first one whose alert waved off on 9th May. The alert was waved off one day later for the other two methods.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>24677</offset><text>Another period where the rigidity can be evaluated is during 14th May to 16th May. C1 was the only method, which did not detect any outbreak. C3, being the most rigid method, signaled an alert earlier than C2 and lasted for a longer duration. Determining the proper method for surveillance depends on the necessity to get an alert for the observed disease as well as on how reliable the mobile crowdsourcing data are. The characteristics of the disease can also play a part in choosing the correct method as a contagious disease has the ability to spread out at an exponential rate, and hence, needs to be detected and contained at the first sign of plausible outbreak.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>25347</offset><text>The initial trial of the crowdsourcing mobile application shows the potential for early detection and prediction of seasonal disease outbreaks. The resulting insights are expected to reduce the response time in case of a pandemic, as well as help in tracking the spread of an infectious disease in Mauritius. Since the system will be completely automated and the output of analysis will be updated in near real time, it is expected to detect disease outbreaks significantly faster than the traditional disease surveillance system that collects public health data from sentinel medical practices.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">12553_2020_456_Fig11_HTML.jpg</infon><infon key="id">Fig11</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>25943</offset><text>URTI Records for January 2017 to December 2017</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>25990</offset><text>Historical data were also obtained from the Communicable Diseases Control Unit (CDCU), Ministry of Health, for 2017. Figure 11 provides a snapshot of the number of reported cases for URTI, starting from January 2017 to December 2017.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>26224</offset><text>If we compare the number of cases reported as possible flu cases in May 2018 compared with the cases of URTI in May 2017, it is clear that there is a correlation. Around that period, there is a change in temperature from warm to slightly colder, hence a rise in flu-related diseases and URTI. According to, seasonal exposure to cold air causes an increase in the incidence of URTI due to cooling of the nasal airway.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>26641</offset><text>The close correlation between the crowdsourcing data and the historical data from the Ministry shows the reliability of the real-time disease outbreak surveillance system. It is expected that as more users register on the system there will be more submissions of reported diseases cases and the system will provide more accurate results. As future works, other sources of information such as pharmacy sales for specific drugs related to the diseases being monitored and absenteeism in schools and workplace will be integrated in the real-time disease outbreak surveillance system for better detection of disease outbreak.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>27263</offset><text>The proposed real-time disease outbreak surveillance system is intended to be used by the Communicable Diseases Control Unit as a complementary tool to track disease outbreak in Mauritius. Analytical data from the system will only be used as an indication of a possible outbreak and will allow the health authorities to have advance notice of outbreaks that may eventually be correlated with daily confirmed cases of specific diseases.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">Tab1.xml</infon><infon key="id">Tab1</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_caption</infon><offset>27699</offset><text>Comparative Evaluation</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">Tab1.xml</infon><infon key="id">Tab1</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table</infon><infon key="xml">&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;table frame=&quot;hsides&quot; rules=&quot;groups&quot;&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;Application&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;Domain&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;Data Collection and type&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;Analytics/&lt;break/&gt;Methods/&lt;break/&gt;Algorithms&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;Results/ Visualization&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Crowdbreaks &lt;xref ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot; rid=&quot;CR33&quot;&gt;33&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Health trends, flu or other infectious diseases&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Tweets from Twitter using a list of vaccine-related keywords collected between July 2018 and January 2019&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;FastText classifier for sentiment analysis&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Real-time predictions of vaccine sentiments, sentiment trends over time&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;HealthMap’s Outbreaks Near Me &lt;xref ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot; rid=&quot;CR34&quot;&gt;34&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;H1N1, typhoid, Swine Flu, Cholera, COVID-19 and other food-borne bacterial outbreaks&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Health-related reports from a multitude of web based sources: GoogleNews, ProMed-Mail, World health organization reports, Geo Sentinel, OIE (the World organization for animal health), EuroSurvillence, Baidu News, Soso info and the Wildlife Data Integration Network&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Uses Bayesian methods to classify News into breaking News, context, warning, old News and non-disease News&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;GIS map of hotspots - Regional Disease Map View&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;SickWeather &lt;xref ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot; rid=&quot;CR35&quot;&gt;35&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Flu, Norovirus, Pink Eye, Whooping Cough, and 20 other illnesses&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Social media monitoring (Facebook, Twitter) and user reporting (symptoms, illness, location)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Machine learning models are used to measure the rate of real-time input compared to an extensive archived data to predict the rate of illnesses&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;The application tracks all the illnesses on a map and provides alerts of sickness that may be present in a specific region (sick zone) along with forecasts. Users are able to get alerts about nearby sicknesses and daily forecasts on active illness.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Flu Near You (FNY) &lt;xref ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot; rid=&quot;CR36&quot;&gt;36&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Influenza-like illness (ILI), H1N1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Participants report health information (their symptoms and that of their household members) weekly via website, Facebook or mobile application &lt;xref ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot; rid=&quot;CR46&quot;&gt;46&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;ILI rates are computed by dividing the number of weekly participants by the total number of FNY participant reports in that same week at each spatial resolution &lt;xref ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot; rid=&quot;CR47&quot;&gt;47&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reports are generated and mapped to allow one to be aware when the flu is around.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;GIS Map is used to provide regional disease Map view.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;UH-BigDataSys &lt;xref ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot; rid=&quot;CR37&quot;&gt;37&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Health advices for respiratory disease, sleep quality control and outdoor travel&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Air quality data collection through: meteorological site data, mobile device crowdsourced data and IoT sensing data. Real-time physiological indicator (collected through wearable devices)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Spring framework for BDA&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Dashboard for trend analysis (Air Quality Index and Physiological Status). On mobile: Air Condition Data, Physiological Data and Healthcare Guidance through GIS&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Stop Corona! &lt;xref ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot; rid=&quot;CR38&quot;&gt;38&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;COVID-19&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Participant information such as gender, age, location, whether person has travelled abroad, whether person has been in contact with another person suffering from COVID-19 and whether person is suffering from disease or not.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;System aggregates all information to show on a map of the world&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Heatmap of disease hotspots&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Mo-Buzz &lt;xref ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot; rid=&quot;CR39&quot;&gt;39&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Dengue&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Participant information (symptoms, mosquito bites, breeding sites) is reported through interactive forms and social media (twitter). Other sources include weather data and human and vector population.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Predictive surveillance based on a computer simulation. GPS-based location sensor to track location.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Information is disseminated in the form of hotspot maps to health officials and the public. Health alerts and personalized messages are sent to people living in specific geographic zones.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Disease Outbreak Tracker (DOT)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;Influenza, Conjunctivitis, URTI, Scabies and&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gastro-Enteritis&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data are recorded through crowdsourcing applications (symptoms)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;and via submissions from clinic (admissions data)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;EARS methods (C1,C2,C3)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Dashboard showing: Spatial visualization of hotspots in Mauritius and trends with respect to number of infections over time and per district&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
</infon><offset>27722</offset><text>Application	Domain	Data Collection and type	Analytics/Methods/Algorithms	Results/ Visualization	 	Crowdbreaks 	Health trends, flu or other infectious diseases	Tweets from Twitter using a list of vaccine-related keywords collected between July 2018 and January 2019	FastText classifier for sentiment analysis	Real-time predictions of vaccine sentiments, sentiment trends over time	 	HealthMap’s Outbreaks Near Me 	H1N1, typhoid, Swine Flu, Cholera, COVID-19 and other food-borne bacterial outbreaks	Health-related reports from a multitude of web based sources: GoogleNews, ProMed-Mail, World health organization reports, Geo Sentinel, OIE (the World organization for animal health), EuroSurvillence, Baidu News, Soso info and the Wildlife Data Integration Network	Uses Bayesian methods to classify News into breaking News, context, warning, old News and non-disease News	GIS map of hotspots - Regional Disease Map View	 	SickWeather 	Flu, Norovirus, Pink Eye, Whooping Cough, and 20 other illnesses	Social media monitoring (Facebook, Twitter) and user reporting (symptoms, illness, location)	Machine learning models are used to measure the rate of real-time input compared to an extensive archived data to predict the rate of illnesses	The application tracks all the illnesses on a map and provides alerts of sickness that may be present in a specific region (sick zone) along with forecasts. Users are able to get alerts about nearby sicknesses and daily forecasts on active illness.	 	Flu Near You (FNY) 	Influenza-like illness (ILI), H1N1	Participants report health information (their symptoms and that of their household members) weekly via website, Facebook or mobile application 	ILI rates are computed by dividing the number of weekly participants by the total number of FNY participant reports in that same week at each spatial resolution 	Reports are generated and mapped to allow one to be aware when the flu is around.GIS Map is used to provide regional disease Map view.	 	UH-BigDataSys 	Health advices for respiratory disease, sleep quality control and outdoor travel	Air quality data collection through: meteorological site data, mobile device crowdsourced data and IoT sensing data. Real-time physiological indicator (collected through wearable devices)	Spring framework for BDA	Dashboard for trend analysis (Air Quality Index and Physiological Status). On mobile: Air Condition Data, Physiological Data and Healthcare Guidance through GIS	 	Stop Corona! 	COVID-19	Participant information such as gender, age, location, whether person has travelled abroad, whether person has been in contact with another person suffering from COVID-19 and whether person is suffering from disease or not.	System aggregates all information to show on a map of the world	Heatmap of disease hotspots	 	Mo-Buzz 	Dengue	Participant information (symptoms, mosquito bites, breeding sites) is reported through interactive forms and social media (twitter). Other sources include weather data and human and vector population.	Predictive surveillance based on a computer simulation. GPS-based location sensor to track location.	Information is disseminated in the form of hotspot maps to health officials and the public. Health alerts and personalized messages are sent to people living in specific geographic zones.	 	Disease Outbreak Tracker (DOT)	Influenza, Conjunctivitis, URTI, Scabies andGastro-Enteritis	Data are recorded through crowdsourcing applications (symptoms)and via submissions from clinic (admissions data)	EARS methods (C1,C2,C3)	Dashboard showing: Spatial visualization of hotspots in Mauritius and trends with respect to number of infections over time and per district	 	</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>31402</offset><text>A comparative evaluation was carried out with respect to existing health-related surveillance systems identified in the section 1 based on different criteria as highlighted in Table 1.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>31587</offset><text>From Table 1, it can be observed that applications like Mo-Buzz and Stop Corona! restricted their surveillance to only one type of disease, namely Dengue and COVID-19 respectively as compared to DOT. Like Stop Corona!, DOT provides the user with a list of different symptoms to choose from when reporting health status while in Sickweather and Crowdbreaks, the main source of information is social media data with more emphasis on Twitter. However, in Mauritius there is limited health-related information being shared on Twitter with only few active users on. The main source of information in DOT is a crowdsourcing application, which is more suited to the context of Mauritius. In terms of visualizations, DOT limits itself to hotspots in Mauritius while FNY, Stop Corona! and Outbreaks Near Me built on HealthMap show a worldwide view of hotspots for specific diseases, with different colors indicating different outbreak status. Compared to DOT, UH-BigDataSys makes use of IoT sensing and focuses on diseases related to air quality only.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>32630</offset><text>As future enhancements, real-time physiological indicator, as captured in UH-BigDataSys, could be considered as potential new sources of data for DOT. Additionally, like in Mo-Buzz, the posting of health alerts and personalized messages to people living in specific geographical zones, based on the identified hotspots can be considered. Similar to Outbreaks Near Me, DOT can be enhanced to advise users based on their current locations and be platform independent. Furthermore, DOT can be extended to include symptoms for COVID-19 and other diseases. The ability of DOT to integrate admissions data from healthcare institutions can considerably improve the reliability of disease surveillance. None of the applications analyzed considered such sources of data.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>33392</offset><text>Conclusion</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>33403</offset><text>The aim of this work is to develop a crowdsourcing mobile application for Disease Outbreak Surveillance for Mauritius since our background study has shown that there exists no such application in the country. The application is intended to monitor the number of cases reported for chosen communicable diseases across the island as well as in specific districts. To gain a better understanding of the disease outbreak surveillance in Mauritius, a stakeholders’ meeting was held with representatives of various health institutions of Mauritius. This exercise provided insight into the analysis currently being performed for outbreak detection as well as which diseases required monitoring in Mauritius. The communicable diseases that were chosen are Influenza, Gastroenteritis, URTI, Scabies and Conjunctivitis. Next, the list of symptoms associated to these diseases had to be created as people might not know which disease they are suffering from but are aware of the symptoms they have. This list was included in the application and users had to select all symptoms that apply. DOT was successfully implemented, tested amongst a small group of people and then was deployed on Google Play Store. All the data collected were anonymized.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>34641</offset><text>Once symptoms data were collected using DOT, probabilistic methods were used to find the disease or diseases that the user might be suffering from. The data were further processed using the EARS algorithm to find the extent of the disease outbreak district-wise, per disease. These data were represented graphically for a rapid understanding of the situation in each district. Our findings concur with existing data for the same period for the previous years showing that the crowd-sourcing application can aid with disease outbreak detection. One major issue of the project was the low-adoption rate of the application. However, in a real-life scenario if the application is deployed on behalf of decision-makers and is promoted on a more massive scale, adoption rate will be higher and the application can only be more efficient at detecting disease outbreak as early as possible. In the future, DOT can be extended to include symptoms for COVID-19 and other diseases. Other data sources such as pharmacy sales for specific drugs related to the diseases being monitored and absenteeism in schools and workplace can also be integrated.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">footnote</infon><offset>35778</offset><text>Publisher’s note</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">footnote</infon><offset>35797</offset><text>Springer Nature remains neutral with regard to jurisdictional claims in published maps and institutional affiliations.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ACK_FUND</infon><infon key="type">title</infon><offset>35916</offset><text>Funding information</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ACK_FUND</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>35936</offset><text>This work was supported by the Mauritius Research Council [MRC/HPCRIG-A03].</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ACK_FUND</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>36012</offset><text>The content is solely the responsibility of the authors and does not necessarily represent the official views of the MRC.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ACK_FUND</infon><infon key="type">title</infon><offset>36134</offset><text>Compliance with ethical standards</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">COMP_INT</infon><infon key="type">title</infon><offset>36168</offset><text>Disclosure of interest</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">COMP_INT</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>36191</offset><text>The author(s) declared no potential conflicts of interest with respect to the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">COMP_INT</infon><infon key="type">title</infon><offset>36327</offset><text>Ethics compliance</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">COMP_INT</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>36345</offset><text>Consent was obtained from all users of the application upon registration on the DOT application and prior to using the application. All data collected were anonymous and no personal data of users were saved.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">COMP_INT</infon><infon key="type">title</infon><offset>36553</offset><text>Conflict of interest</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">COMP_INT</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>36574</offset><text>The authors declare that they have no competing of interests.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">title</infon><offset>36636</offset><text>References</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">365</infon><infon key="lpage">375</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Semenza;given-names:JC</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Menne;given-names:B</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/S1473-3099(09)70104-5</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">19467476</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Lancet Infect Dis</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">9</infon><infon key="year">2009</infon><offset>36647</offset><text>Climate change and infectious diseases in Europe</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">e0005212</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Abat;given-names:C</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Colson;given-names:P</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Chaudet;given-names:H</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Rolain;given-names:JM</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Bassene;given-names:H</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Diallo;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_6">surname:Mediannikov;given-names:O</infon><infon key="name_7">surname:Fenollar;given-names:F</infon><infon key="name_8">surname:Raoult;given-names:D</infon><infon key="name_9">surname:Sokhna;given-names:C</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1371/journal.pntd.0005212</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">27926917</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">PLoS Negl Trop Dis</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">10</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>36696</offset><text>Implementation of syndromic surveillance systems in two rural villages in Senegal</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">161</infon><infon key="lpage">168</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Isere;given-names:EE</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Fatiregun;given-names:AA</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Ajayi;given-names:IO</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.4103/0300-1652.160347</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">26229222</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Niger Med J</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">56</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>36778</offset><text>An overview of disease surveillance and notification system in Nigeria and the roles of clinicians in disease outbreak prevention and control</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>36920</offset><text>Manogaran G, Lopez D. Disease surveillance system for big climate data processing and dengue transmission. In: Management Association IR (ed) Web services: concepts, methodologies, tools, and applications. IGI Global; 2019; pp 490–509.</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1238</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Choi;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Cho;given-names:Y</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Shim;given-names:E</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Woo;given-names:H</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1186/s12889-016-3893-0</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">27931204</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">BMC Public Health</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">16</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>37158</offset><text>Web-based infectious disease surveillance systems and public health perspectives: a systematic review</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">3</infon><infon key="lpage">6</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Fung;given-names:IC-H</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Tse;given-names:ZTH</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Fu;given-names:K-W</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.5365/WPSAR.2015.6.1.019</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Western Pac Surveill Response J</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">6</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>37260</offset><text>The use of social media in public health surveillance</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">137</infon><infon key="lpage">144</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Gandomi;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Haider;given-names:M</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.ijinfomgt.2014.10.007</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Int J Inf Manag</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">35</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>37314</offset><text>Beyond the hype: big data concepts, methods, and analytics</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">156</infon><infon key="lpage">168</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Stieglitz;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Mirbabaie;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Ross;given-names:B</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Neuberger;given-names:C</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.ijinfomgt.2017.12.002</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Int J Inf Manag</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">39</infon><infon key="year">2018</infon><offset>37373</offset><text>Social media analytics – challenges in topic discovery, data collection, and data preparation</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">89</infon><infon key="lpage">116</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Batrinca;given-names:B</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Treleaven;given-names:PC</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1007/s00146-014-0549-4</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">AI Soc</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">30</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>37469</offset><text>Social media analytics: a survey of techniques, tools and platforms</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>37537</offset><text>Chae J, Thom D, Bosch H, et al. Spatiotemporal social media analytics for abnormal event detection and examination using seasonal-trend decomposition. 2012 IEEE Conference on Visual Analytics Science and Technology (VAST). IEEE; 2012; pp 143–152.</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">74</infon><infon key="lpage">81</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Fan;given-names:W</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Gordon;given-names:MD</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1145/2602574</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Commun ACM</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">57</infon><infon key="year">2014</infon><offset>37786</offset><text>The power of social media analytics</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">328</infon><infon key="lpage">331</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Ribarsky;given-names:W</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Xiaoyu Wang;given-names:D</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Dou;given-names:W</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.cag.2013.11.003</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Comput Graph</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">38</infon><infon key="year">2014</infon><offset>37822</offset><text>Social media analytics for competitive advantage</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1277</infon><infon key="lpage">1291</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Stieglitz;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Dang-Xuan;given-names:L</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1007/s13278-012-0079-3</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Soc Netw Anal Min</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">3</infon><infon key="year">2013</infon><offset>37871</offset><text>Social media and political communication: a social media analytics framework</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">13</infon><infon key="lpage">16</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Zeng;given-names:D</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Chen;given-names:H</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Lusch;given-names:R</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Li;given-names:S-H</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1109/MIS.2010.151</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">IEEE Intell Syst</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">25</infon><infon key="year">2010</infon><offset>37948</offset><text>Social media analytics and intelligence</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>37988</offset><text>Lutu PEN. Data analytics to support social media marketing : challenges and opportunities. 2016.</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">e0155417</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Thapen;given-names:N</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Simmie;given-names:D</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Hankin;given-names:C</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Gillard;given-names:J</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0155417</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">27192059</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">PLoS One</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">11</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>38085</offset><text>DEFENDER: detecting and forecasting epidemics using novel data-analytics for enhanced response</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>38180</offset><text>Ramanathan A, Pullum LL, Hobson TC, et al. ORBiT: Oak Ridge biosurveillance toolkit for public health dynamics. BMC Bioinformatics 16 Suppl. 2015; 17:S4. doi: 10.1186/1471-2105-16-S17-S4</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">67</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Kamel Boulos;given-names:MN</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Resch;given-names:B</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Crowley;given-names:DN</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Breslin;given-names:JG</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Sohn;given-names:G</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Burtner;given-names:R</infon><infon key="name_6">surname:Pike;given-names:WA</infon><infon key="name_7">surname:Jezierski;given-names:E</infon><infon key="name_8">surname:Chuang;given-names:KY</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1186/1476-072X-10-67</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">22188675</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Int J Health Geogr</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">10</infon><infon key="year">2011</infon><offset>38367</offset><text>Crowdsourcing, citizen sensing and sensor web technologies for public and environmental health surveillance and crisis management: trends, OGC standards and application examples</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>38545</offset><text>Louis A. Natural language processing for social MediaAtefeh Farzindar and Diana Inkpen (NLP technologies Inc., Université de Montréal; and University of Ottawa)Morgan &amp; Claypool (synthesis lectures on human language technologies, edited by Graeme Hirst, volume 30), 2015, xix+146 pp; paperbound, ISBN 978-1-62705-388-4; ebook, ISBN 978-1-62705-389-1; doi 10.2200/S00659ED1V01Y201508HLT030, $55.00 Computational Linguistics 2016; 42:833–836. doi: 10.1162/COLI_r_00270.</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">62</infon><infon key="lpage">69</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Tan;given-names:W</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Blake;given-names:MB</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Saleh;given-names:I</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Dustdar;given-names:S</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1109/MIC.2013.100</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">IEEE Internet Comput</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">17</infon><infon key="year">2013</infon><offset>39017</offset><text>Social-network-sourced big data analytics</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>39059</offset><text>Eklund JM, McGregor C. Real-time online health analytics for interplanetary space missions. 2014 IEEE Aerospace Conference. IEEE. 2014; pp 1–10.</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1</infon><infon key="lpage">10</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Jirkovsky;given-names:V</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Obitko;given-names:M</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">ITAT</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">1214</infon><infon key="year">2014</infon><offset>39206</offset><text>Semantic heterogeneity reduction for big data in industrial automation</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>39277</offset><text>Khan M, Wu X, Xu X, Dou W. Big data challenges and opportunities in the hype of Industry 4.0. 2017 IEEE International Conference on Communications (ICC). IEEE. 2017; pp 1–6.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>39453</offset><text>Van Sinderen M, Oude Luttighuis P, Folmer E, Bosems S. Enterprise Interoperability: 5th International IFIP Working Conference, IWEI 2013, Enschede, the Netherlands, march 27–28, 2013. Proceedings. doi: 10.1007/978-3-642-36796-0.</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">8</infon><infon key="lpage">17</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Carrière;given-names:R</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:MacDonald;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Chan;given-names:Y</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.12927/cjnl.2016.24556</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">27122085</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Nurs Leadersh (Tor Ont)</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">28</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>39684</offset><text>Past, present and future: the outlook from mid-career nurse Informaticians</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>39759</offset><text>Brabham DC. Crowdsourcing as a model for problem solving: an introduction and cases. Convergence: The International Journal of Research into New Media Technologies 2008; 14:75–90. doi: 10.1177/1354856507084420.</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">7987</infon><infon key="lpage">7994</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Xintong;given-names:G</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Hongzhi;given-names:W</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Song;given-names:Y</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Hong;given-names:G</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.eswa.2014.06.044</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Expert Syst Appl</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">41</infon><infon key="year">2014</infon><offset>39972</offset><text>Brief survey of crowdsourcing for data mining</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>40018</offset><text>CrowdSource. https://www.crowdsource.com/. Accessed 3 Sep 2019.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>40082</offset><text>CrowdFlower. https://www.figure-eight.com/. Accessed 3 Sep 2019.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>40147</offset><text>Kittur A, Smus B, Khamkar S, Kraut RE. Crowd Forge. Proceedings of the 24th annual ACM symposium on User interface software and technology - UIST' ' ‘11. ACM Press, New York, New York, USA, 2011; p 43.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>40351</offset><text>Kittur A, Khamkar S, André P, Kraut R. Crowd Weaver: Visually managing complex crowd work. Proceedings of the ACM 2012 conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work - CSCW' ' ‘12. ACM Press, New York, New York, USA, 2012; p 1033.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>40588</offset><text>Amazon Mechanical Turk. https://www.mturk.com/. Accessed 3 Sep 2019.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>40657</offset><text>Müller MM, Salathé M. Crowdbreaks: tracking health trends using public social media data and crowdsourcing. Front Public Health. 2019;7.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>40796</offset><text>Outbreaks Near Me. HealthMap, https://www.healthmap.org/outbreaksnearme/. Accessed 21 May 2020.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>40892</offset><text>Sickweather. http://www.sickweather.com/. Accessed 17 May 2020.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>40956</offset><text>Flu Near You. https://flunearyou.org/ Accessed 21 May 2020.</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">14</infon><infon key="issue">11</infon><infon key="lpage">20</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Chen;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Yang;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Hu;given-names:L</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Hossain;given-names:MS</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Muhammad;given-names:G</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1109/MCOM.2018.1700571</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">IEEE Commun Mag</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">56</infon><infon key="year">2018</infon><offset>41016</offset><text>Urban healthcare big data system based on crowdsourced and cloud-based air quality indicators</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>41110</offset><text>Stop Corona!. https://stopcorona.app/. Accessed: 21 May 2020.</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">100</infon><infon key="lpage">107</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Lwin;given-names:MO</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Vijaykumar;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Fernando</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.actatropica.2013.09.021</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">24161879</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Acta Trop</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">130</infon><infon key="year">2014</infon><offset>41172</offset><text>A 21st century approach to tackling dengue: Crowdsourced surveillance, predictive mapping and tailored communication</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">e110236</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Schwind;given-names:JS</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Wolking;given-names:DJ</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Brownstein;given-names:JS</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Mazet;given-names:JAK</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Smith;given-names:WA</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0110236</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">25333618</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">PLoS One</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">9</infon><infon key="year">2014</infon><offset>41289</offset><text>Evaluation of local media surveillance for improved disease recognition and monitoring in global hotspot regions</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">e328</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Ghamy;given-names:AB</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Goorah;given-names:SSD</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Caussy;given-names:BS</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Cheeneebash;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Ramchurn;given-names:SK</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.ijid.2008.05.878</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Int J Infect Dis</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">12</infon><infon key="year">2008</infon><offset>41402</offset><text>Clinical complications of chikungunya in Mauritius</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>41453</offset><text>(2009) ECDC RISK ASSESSMENT Pandemic H1N1 2009. 1–23.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>41509</offset><text>Jha KK. Impact of Social Networking Sites on the Mauritian Youth : A Study of their Life Styles and its Effectiveness in Nation Building. 2016; 114–124.</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">98</infon><infon key="lpage">105</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Ren;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Zhang;given-names:Y</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Zhang;given-names:K</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Shen;given-names:X</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1109/MCOM.2015.7060488</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">IEEE Commun Mag</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">53</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>41664</offset><text>Exploiting mobile crowdsourcing for pervasive cloud services: challenges and solutions</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">183</infon><infon key="lpage">191</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Eccles;given-names:R</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1080/00016480252814207</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">11936911</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Acta Otolaryngol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">122</infon><infon key="year">2002</infon><offset>41751</offset><text>An explanation for the seasonality of acute upper respiratory tract viral infections</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">2124</infon><infon key="issue">10</infon><infon key="lpage">2130</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Smolinski;given-names:MS</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Crawley;given-names:AW</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Baltrusaitis;given-names:K</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Chunara;given-names:R</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Olsen;given-names:JM</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Wójcik;given-names:O</infon><infon key="name_6">surname:Santillana;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_7">surname:Nguyen;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_8">surname:Brownstein;given-names:JS</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.2105/AJPH.2015.302696</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">26270299</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Am J Public Health</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">105</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>41836</offset><text>Flu near you: crowdsourced symptom reporting spanning 2 influenza seasons</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">403</infon><infon key="issue">1</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Baltrusaitis;given-names:K</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Brownstein;given-names:JS</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Scarpino;given-names:SV</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Bakota;given-names:E</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Crawley;given-names:AW</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Conidi;given-names:G</infon><infon key="name_6">surname:Gunn;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_7">surname:Gray;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_8">surname:Zink;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_9">surname:Santillana;given-names:M</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1186/s12879-018-3322-3</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">30111305</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">BMC Infect Dis</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">18</infon><infon key="year">2018</infon><offset>41910</offset><text>Comparison of crowd-sourced, electronic health records based, and traditional health-care based influenza-tracking systems at multiple spatial resolutions in the United States of America</text></passage></document></collection>
