<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd">
<collection><source>PMC</source><date>20210202</date><key>pmc.key</key><document><id>7840485</id><infon key="license">CC BY</infon><passage><infon key="alt-title">Yeung et al. OI in Medicine and Pharmacology</infon><infon key="article-id_doi">10.3389/fphar.2020.587526</infon><infon key="article-id_pmc">7840485</infon><infon key="article-id_pmid">33519448</infon><infon key="article-id_publisher-id">587526</infon><infon key="elocation-id">587526</infon><infon key="kwd">public-private partnership pharmaceutical industry drug discovery patient-centered innovation intellectual property crowdsourcing knowledge management open innovation</infon><infon key="license">This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License (CC BY). The use, distribution or reproduction in other forums is permitted, provided the original author(s) and the copyright owner(s) are credited and that the original publication in this journal is cited, in accordance with accepted academic practice. No use, distribution or reproduction is permitted which does not comply with these terms.</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Yeung;given-names:Andy Wai Kan</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Atanasov;given-names:Atanas G.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Sheridan;given-names:Helen</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Klager;given-names:Elisabeth</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Eibensteiner;given-names:Fabian</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Völkl-Kernsock;given-names:Sabine</infon><infon key="name_6">surname:Kletecka-Pulker;given-names:Maria</infon><infon key="name_7">surname:Willschke;given-names:Harald</infon><infon key="name_8">surname:Schaden;given-names:Eva</infon><infon key="section_type">TITLE</infon><infon key="type">front</infon><infon key="volume">11</infon><infon key="year">2020</infon><offset>0</offset><text>Open Innovation in Medical and Pharmaceutical Research: A Literature Landscape Analysis</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>88</offset><text>Open innovation in medical and pharmaceutical research has grown steadily over the last decade. However, the performance of the published literature in terms of the scientific impact and gaining social media attention remains largely unexplored. The scientific literature of open innovation was examined by means of bibliometric analyses to identify the most prolific authors, organizations, countries, journals, research areas, and recurring terms. By accessing the Web of Science Core Collection and Altmetric electronic databases, citation-related and Altmetric data were evaluated. Public-private partnerships and a selection of newly introduced potential novel drugs in the analyzed publications were identified. North America and Europe were the major literature contributors. Research outputs were mainly published in journals focused on business and economics, pharmacology and pharmacy, and engineering. Many pharmaceutical and biotechnological companies contributed to the analyzed publications, with higher mean citation counts and social media attention (Altmetric score) than nonindustry articles. Public-private partnerships fostered financial support, sharing of expertise and intellectual property, and research collaborations. In summary, open innovation might serve as a powerful strategy to both benefit the involved industry entities and accelerate the development of solutions and products for the betterment of human health.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>1535</offset><text>Introduction</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>1548</offset><text>Companies rely on innovation in order to develop and stay competitive in the face of dynamically evolving scientific, technological, and societal conditions. Traditionally, the industry's approach has been to generate innovation internally within specialized research and development departments. However, the shortcomings of this approach are that, on the one hand, there is always a lot of potentially valuable innovation generated in parallel outside of companies and, on the other hand, internally generated innovation cannot always be translated into commercial products or services benefiting the company. Therefore, in recent times, there has been a paradigm shift toward open innovation, a model that does not exclude the traditional internal innovation but is open to also incorporate externally generated innovation. Open innovation, as defined by, is “a distributed innovation process based on purposively managed knowledge flows across organizational boundaries, using pecuniary and nonpecuniary mechanisms in line with the organization's business model.” The innovation derived from external sources can include ideas, technologies, and research and development. In open innovation, companies have moved from the pursuit of intellectual property protection to engaging in cross industry-academia and industry-public collaboration and engagement. Early adopters of the open innovation concept have been the so-called “high-technology” industries in the area of information technology, computers, and pharmaceuticals. Beyond these early adopters, other industrial areas with medical significance that shortly followed embracing the open innovation concept include industries from the areas of medical devices, chemicals, and bioscience tools and services. Depending on the direction of movement of new knowledge, three different types of open innovation processes have been distinguished. The outside-in (inbound) process involves the integration of internal knowledge of an organization with knowledge derived from external sources; the inside-out (outbound) process involves generating profits for the organization by transferring internally generated knowledge or intellectual property to external entities; and the third, “coupled,” process involves a combination of both inbound and outbound processes by the formation of alliances with complementary external entities. Analysis of the literature on open innovation in healthcare revealed that open inbound innovation was the most widely applied approach in this sector.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>4097</offset><text>In pharmaceutical companies, open innovation differs according to partnerships, incentives, and goals. placed open innovation models into four categories, the knowledge creator, knowledge translator, knowledge integrator, and knowledge leverager, and assigned pharmaceutical companies to these models, depending on their specific approach. As a prominent example from the pharma industry, Eli Lilly has a strong history of collaboration that led to launching of their Open Innovation Drug Discovery program in 2009.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>4613</offset><text>To foster academia-industry interactions, a significant number of universities have created formal Academic Drug Discovery Centres (ADDCs), which include industrial collaboration. One of the earliest centers, the Actar AB center, was created at the Karolinska Institute in Sweden in 2000, followed by the Harvard NeuroDiscovery center in the US in 2001, with dozens of more ADDCs established in the EU and the US in the following decade. Building on the ADDC model, another concept that has emerged in the academia-industry interface is that of the Academic Drug Discovery Consortium. One of the first consortia was founded in the EU, and the longest existing academia-industry collaboration was the formation of the Division of Signal Transduction Therapy between the University of Dundee, six pharma companies, and twenty academic research teams (http://www.lifesci.dundee.ac.uk/unit/division-signal-transduction-therapy-dstt). This type of collaborative initiative can extend beyond the sharing of costs and may improve the efficiency of drug development and reduce duplication of effort. Regulators and governments are also increasingly engaged in supporting drug discovery, e.g., in Sweden where the government ring-fenced early-stage funding of €6 M per year (2013–2016) for the Science for Life Drug Discovery and Development platform (SciLifeLab DDD) established in 2011. Further examples of regulator and government engagement are the Critical Path Initiative in the United States (FDA) and the Cooksey Review of health research funding in the United Kingdom. With the advancement of Internet technology, collaborative work from a distance gained new significance and was manifested in a variety of different forms potentially benefiting open innovation, including the formation of virtual organizations, virtual enterprises, and collaborative virtual laboratories.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>6492</offset><text>Crowdsourcing represents an open innovation approach gaining momentum, which can be used to derive solutions that advance the medical field by collective intelligence and resources and actively engaging patients and the general public. Crowdsourcing approaches used in the context of medical research include innovation challenges (e.g., prize contests), hackathons (short events usually bringing participants together for a few days around a common theme with the aim of solving defined challenges, often with a focus on the area of computer programming), and online systems for collaboration (e.g., websites supporting the engagement of visitors to solve a defined problem).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>7169</offset><text>The direct involvement of nonprofessionals in scientific research, referred to as “citizen science,” is a highly potent collaborative approach for gaining new knowledge. Citizen science has been well-established in research fields, such as ecology and astronomy, and in the context of increasing significance of patient-centered medicine. Currently, there are broad ongoing efforts for citizen science implementation in health and biomedical research, whereby progress in these areas encounters some difficulties related to existing ethical issues, including consideration for possible risks for the involved citizen scientists or other humans.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>7818</offset><text>Our goal in this work is to gain new insights into open innovation in medical and pharmaceutical research by performing a full-scale bibliometric analysis, an approach that has proven its value in the quantitative characterization of various outputs of the scientific literature published in other biomedical research areas. Such full-scale bibliometric analysis might reveal information for major institutions, top scientists of the area, research impacts (reflected by citation counts), and main research topics and trends. Researchers and nonexperts can use such data for rapid orientation in the respective scientific area and to achieve some more specific goals, for example, identifying potential new collaboration partners. Open innovation, in general, as well as in medical research in particular, is currently a major trend with vibrant activities apart from publishing research, such as the organization of hackathons and the establishment of innovation hubs. In order to better understand participants and publishing trends in this research area, the present work focuses on the bibliometric characterization of its publication landscape.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>8968</offset><text>Materials and Methods</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>8990</offset><text>The digital literature database, Web of Science Core Collection, was accessed in early June 2020 in order to identify and analyze relevant publications. We therefore utilized the following search string: TS = (“open innovation*” OR “external innovation*” OR “patient cent* innovation*”) AND TS = (medic* OR illness* OR disease* OR health* OR pharma*). This search strategy recognized publications presenting the indicated phrases or their derivatives in the title, abstract, or keyword fields. The bibliographic information of the yielded publications was analyzed to reveal the most productive entities in terms of authors, organizations, countries, journals, research areas, etc. The complete records were exported to VOSviewer (www.vosviewer.com, version 1.6.15, Leiden University, The Netherlands), a dedicated bibliometric software, for further analyses and visualization of bibliometric networks. As a subanalysis, crowdsourc* was searched within the dataset in order to identify relevant articles.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>10007</offset><text>Nonparametric tests were used as the data were not normally distributed as tested by Shapiro–Wilk tests. Mann–Whitney U tests were conducted to test if publications with contributions from the industry (i.e., authors affiliated with biotechnology/pharmaceutical companies) had higher mean citation counts per publication than their nonindustry counterparts. Similarly, the group difference in Altmetric Attention Score, a score indicating social media attention tracked by Altmetric (www.altmetric.com), was tested. Articles were considered to have industrial contributions when at least one of the authors was affiliated with industry (articles published jointly with industry professionals and academic researchers were considered to have industrial contribution).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>10778</offset><text>Results</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>10786</offset><text>The search yielded 384 publications that accumulated over 5,000 citations (Figure 1), with an h-index of 32 and 13.2 citations per publication (CPP). There were 240 articles and 55 review publications, equivalent to a ratio of 4.4–1. There were 54 proceedings and 27 editorial materials. The first article was published in 2006, which used Millenium Pharmaceuticals (now known as Takeda Oncology, a subsidiary of Takeda Pharmaceutical) as one of the examples of early adopters of open innovation in the high-technology industries.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">fphar-11-587526-g001.jpg</infon><infon key="id">F1</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>11319</offset><text>Cumulative publication and citation counts of open innovation in medical and pharmaceutical research.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>11421</offset><text>The 10 most prolific authors, organizations (additionally including companies in the industry with two or more articles), countries, journals, and research areas are listed in Table 1. Most of the top 10 most prolific authors came from Italy, in particular from the University of Salerno. Four of the top 10 most prolific organizations were pharmaceutical companies. The top 10 countries were situated in North America and Europe, except China. Nine of the top 10 journals had an impact factor and were mostly concerning business/economics and pharmacology/pharmacy.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">T1.xml</infon><infon key="id">T1</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_caption</infon><offset>11988</offset><text>The 10 most prolific authors, organizations (additionally including companies in the industry with two or more articles), countries, journals, and research areas.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">T1.xml</infon><infon key="id">T1</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table</infon><infon key="xml">&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;table frame=&quot;hsides&quot; rules=&quot;groups&quot;&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;No. of publications (% of 384)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Citations per publication&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;3&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;italic&gt;Authors&lt;/italic&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Antonello Cammarano&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;16 (4.2)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;8.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Mauro Caputo&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;16 (4.2)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;8.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Francesca Michelino&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;16 (4.2)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;8.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Emilia Lamberti&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;14 (3.6)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;9.9&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; I. Sam Saguy&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;5 (1.3)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;18.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Alexander Schuhmacher&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;5 (1.3)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;27.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Giustina Secundo&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;5 (1.3)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;4.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Federico Frattini&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;4 (1.0)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;63.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Oliver Gassmann&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;4 (1.0)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;37.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Giuseppina Passiante&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;4 (1.0)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;3.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;3&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;italic&gt;Organizations&lt;/italic&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; University of Salerno&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;18 (4.7)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;7.7&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; University of London&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;10 (2.6)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;14.1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; AstraZeneca (industry)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;8 (2.1)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;44.9&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Eli Lilly (industry)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;8 (2.1)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;15.4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; GlaxoSmithKline (industry)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;8 (2.1)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;48.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; University of Rome Tor Vergata&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;8 (2.1)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;6.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Hebrew University of Jerusalem&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;6 (1.6)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;16.3&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Novartis (industry)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;6 (1.6)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;30.7&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; University of California system&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;6 (1.6)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;137.2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;6 (1.6)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;27.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Bayer AG (industry)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;5 (1.3)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;30.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Johnson &amp;amp; Johnson (industry)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;4 (1.0)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;72.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Sanofi S.A. (industry)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;4 (1.0)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;7.5&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Boehringer Ingelheim (industry)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;3 (0.8)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;7.7&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Pfizer (industry)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;3 (0.8)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;29.7&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;3&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;italic&gt;Countries&lt;/italic&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; United States&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;95 (24.7)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;26.2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; United Kingdom&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;62 (16.1)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;15.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Italy&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;53 (13.8)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;13.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Germany&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;42 (10.9)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;15.3&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Netherlands&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;28 (7.3)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;25.3&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Sweden&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;23 (6.0)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;21.1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Spain&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;20 (5.2)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;9.1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Switzerland&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;20 (5.2)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;25.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Canada&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;18 (4.7)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;8.4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; China&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;18 (4.7)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;2.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;3&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;italic&gt;Journals (impact factor)&lt;/italic&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Drug Discovery Today (6.880)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;17 (4.4)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;24.2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Expert Opinion on Drug Discovery (4.421)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;12 (3.1)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;9.4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Sustainability (2.592)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;10 (2.6)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1.9&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; International Journal of Innovation Management (NA)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;9 (2.3)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;6.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; International Journal of Technology Management (1.160)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;9 (2.3)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;7.1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; R&amp;amp;D Management (2.354)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;9 (2.3)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;91.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Future Medicinal Chemistry (3.617)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;7 (1.8)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;4.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; European Journal of Innovation Management (1.793)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;6 (1.6)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;12.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Technology Analysis &amp;amp; Strategic Management (1.739)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;6 (1.6)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;7.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Research-Technology Management (1.407)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;5 (1.3)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;10.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;3&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;italic&gt;Research areas&lt;/italic&gt;
&lt;xref ref-type=&quot;table-fn&quot; rid=&quot;Tfn1&quot;&gt;
&lt;sup&gt;a&lt;/sup&gt;
&lt;/xref&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Business and economics&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;146 (38.0)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;17.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Pharmacology and pharmacy&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;80 (20.8)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;13.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Engineering&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;62 (16.1)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;16.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Science technology other topics&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;28 (7.3)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;6.3&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Healthcare sciences services&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;21 (5.5)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;6.3&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Operations research management science&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;21 (5.5)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;25.2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Computer science&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;20 (5.2)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;5.5&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Environmental sciences and ecology&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;17 (4.4)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;4.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Information science and library science&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;13 (3.4)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;6.7&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Food science technology&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;11 (2.9)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;20.7&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
</infon><offset>12151</offset><text>	No. of publications (% of 384)	Citations per publication	 	Authors	 	 Antonello Cammarano	16 (4.2)	8.6	 	 Mauro Caputo	16 (4.2)	8.6	 	 Francesca Michelino	16 (4.2)	8.6	 	 Emilia Lamberti	14 (3.6)	9.9	 	 I. Sam Saguy	5 (1.3)	18.6	 	 Alexander Schuhmacher	5 (1.3)	27.8	 	 Giustina Secundo	5 (1.3)	4.6	 	 Federico Frattini	4 (1.0)	63.8	 	 Oliver Gassmann	4 (1.0)	37.8	 	 Giuseppina Passiante	4 (1.0)	3.0	 	Organizations	 	 University of Salerno	18 (4.7)	7.7	 	 University of London	10 (2.6)	14.1	 	 AstraZeneca (industry)	8 (2.1)	44.9	 	 Eli Lilly (industry)	8 (2.1)	15.4	 	 GlaxoSmithKline (industry)	8 (2.1)	48.0	 	 University of Rome Tor Vergata	8 (2.1)	6.8	 	 Hebrew University of Jerusalem	6 (1.6)	16.3	 	 Novartis (industry)	6 (1.6)	30.7	 	 University of California system	6 (1.6)	137.2	 	 Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam	6 (1.6)	27.0	 	 Bayer AG (industry)	5 (1.3)	30.6	 	 Johnson &amp; Johnson (industry)	4 (1.0)	72.0	 	 Sanofi S.A. (industry)	4 (1.0)	7.5	 	 Boehringer Ingelheim (industry)	3 (0.8)	7.7	 	 Pfizer (industry)	3 (0.8)	29.7	 	Countries	 	 United States	95 (24.7)	26.2	 	 United Kingdom	62 (16.1)	15.0	 	 Italy	53 (13.8)	13.0	 	 Germany	42 (10.9)	15.3	 	 Netherlands	28 (7.3)	25.3	 	 Sweden	23 (6.0)	21.1	 	 Spain	20 (5.2)	9.1	 	 Switzerland	20 (5.2)	25.0	 	 Canada	18 (4.7)	8.4	 	 China	18 (4.7)	2.8	 	Journals (impact factor)	 	 Drug Discovery Today (6.880)	17 (4.4)	24.2	 	 Expert Opinion on Drug Discovery (4.421)	12 (3.1)	9.4	 	 Sustainability (2.592)	10 (2.6)	1.9	 	 International Journal of Innovation Management (NA)	9 (2.3)	6.6	 	 International Journal of Technology Management (1.160)	9 (2.3)	7.1	 	 R&amp;D Management (2.354)	9 (2.3)	91.6	 	 Future Medicinal Chemistry (3.617)	7 (1.8)	4.6	 	 European Journal of Innovation Management (1.793)	6 (1.6)	12.8	 	 Technology Analysis &amp; Strategic Management (1.739)	6 (1.6)	7.0	 	 Research-Technology Management (1.407)	5 (1.3)	10.6	 	Research areasa	 	 Business and economics	146 (38.0)	17.6	 	 Pharmacology and pharmacy	80 (20.8)	13.0	 	 Engineering	62 (16.1)	16.8	 	 Science technology other topics	28 (7.3)	6.3	 	 Healthcare sciences services	21 (5.5)	6.3	 	 Operations research management science	21 (5.5)	25.2	 	 Computer science	20 (5.2)	5.5	 	 Environmental sciences and ecology	17 (4.4)	4.8	 	 Information science and library science	13 (3.4)	6.7	 	 Food science technology	11 (2.9)	20.7	 	</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">T1.xml</infon><infon key="id">T1</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_footnote</infon><offset>14622</offset><text>Since the search string included the metaword pharma*, readers should be aware that the research area of “pharmacology and pharmacy” would be favored.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>14777</offset><text>There were 51 publications with authors affiliated with biotechnology/pharmaceutical companies, with a mean citation count per publication (CPP) of 23.3 (SD = 39.3), which was significantly higher than purely academic publications (11.6, SD = 43.5) (p = 0.001). Similarly, the former group of publications had an Altmetric score of 14.2 (SD = 34.7), significantly higher than the latter group (5.9, SD = 15.7) (p = 0.013). The public-private partnerships or initiatives introduced in these 51 industry articles are listed in Table 2.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">T2.xml</infon><infon key="id">T2</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_caption</infon><offset>15311</offset><text>Public-private partnerships or initiatives introduced in the industry articles concerning open innovation in medical and pharma research.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">T2.xml</infon><infon key="id">T2</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table</infon><infon key="xml">&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;table frame=&quot;hsides&quot; rules=&quot;groups&quot;&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Project name&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Objective&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Involved companies&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Open PHACTS &lt;xref rid=&quot;B56&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;Williams et al., 2012&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;To deliver and sustain an open pharmacological webspace to facilitate drug discovery research&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;AstraZeneca&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;INVITE GmbH &lt;xref rid=&quot;B7&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;Bieringer et al., 2013&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;To innovate, develop, and revolutionize technologies for chemical, pharmaceutical, and biotechnology purposes&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Bayer AG&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Grants4Targets &lt;xref rid=&quot;B49&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;Lessl et al., 2011&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;To provide financial support and expertise on target validation and drug discovery to external groups&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Bayer AG&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Phenotypic Drug Discovery (PD2) Initiative &lt;xref rid=&quot;B30&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;Lee et al., 2011&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;To make their phenotypic assays available to external research groups&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Eli Lilly&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Open Innovation Drug Discovery (OIDD) &lt;xref rid=&quot;B2&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;Alvim-Gaston et al., 2014&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B31&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;Lee et al., 2015&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;B13&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;Carroll et al., 2017&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;To identify novel molecules active in relevant disease biology models&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Eli Lilly&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Africa NCD Open Lab &lt;xref rid=&quot;B22&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;Hall et al., 2015&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;To share expertise and resources to conduct research on noncommunicable diseases in Africa&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;GlaxoSmithKline&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Observational Medical Outcomes Partnership &lt;xref rid=&quot;B45&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;Stang et al., 2010&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;To advance the active surveillance of medical product safety by using existing observational databases&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;GlaxoSmithKline and Johnson &amp;amp; Johnson&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;tranSMART &lt;xref rid=&quot;B10&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;Perakslis et al., 2010&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;To maintain a data warehouse for data sharing and partnership&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Johnson &amp;amp; Johnson&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Sanofi-MIT Partnership &lt;xref rid=&quot;B46&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;Stewart et al., 2016&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;To provide seed funding to academia for pharmaceutical research&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Sanofi&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
</infon><offset>15449</offset><text>Project name	Objective	Involved companies	 	Open PHACTS 	To deliver and sustain an open pharmacological webspace to facilitate drug discovery research	AstraZeneca	 	INVITE GmbH 	To innovate, develop, and revolutionize technologies for chemical, pharmaceutical, and biotechnology purposes	Bayer AG	 	Grants4Targets 	To provide financial support and expertise on target validation and drug discovery to external groups	Bayer AG	 	Phenotypic Drug Discovery (PD2) Initiative 	To make their phenotypic assays available to external research groups	Eli Lilly	 	Open Innovation Drug Discovery (OIDD) 	To identify novel molecules active in relevant disease biology models	Eli Lilly	 	Africa NCD Open Lab 	To share expertise and resources to conduct research on noncommunicable diseases in Africa	GlaxoSmithKline	 	Observational Medical Outcomes Partnership 	To advance the active surveillance of medical product safety by using existing observational databases	GlaxoSmithKline and Johnson &amp; Johnson	 	tranSMART 	To maintain a data warehouse for data sharing and partnership	Johnson &amp; Johnson	 	Sanofi-MIT Partnership 	To provide seed funding to academia for pharmaceutical research	Sanofi	 	</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>16632</offset><text>The term map of titles and abstracts showed that academia and pharmaceutical industry collaborated for various aspects, such as novel drug discovery (n = 6, CPP = 19.7) and delivery (n = 5, CPP = 23.0) (Figure 2). Highly cited terms revealed from the bibliometric analysis were high technology (n = 4, CPP = 185.3), outsourcing (n = 8, CPP = 94.3), drug administration (n = 5, CPP = 67.8), outbound open innovation (n = 5, CPP = 50.2), and public-private partnership (n = 14, CPP = 34.4) (Table 3). Meanwhile, the top 20 most recurring author keywords are listed in Table 4. Drug discovery, intellectual property, knowledge management, licensing, drug development, and entrepreneurship were among the most highly cited keywords.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">fphar-11-587526-g002.jpg</infon><infon key="id">F2</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>17361</offset><text>The recurring words and phrases in the titles and abstracts of open innovation in medical and pharmaceutical research publications. Words and phrases recurring in at least 1% of all publications (n = 4) were illustrated. The color of the circles represented the citations per publication (CPP) of publications that contained the concerning word or phrase. The size of the circles represented the number of publications. The proximity between the circles represented the frequency of cooccurrence of the concerning words or phrases.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">T3.xml</infon><infon key="id">T3</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_caption</infon><offset>17893</offset><text>Top 20 most recurring and most highly cited terms in the titles and abstracts, identified with VOSviewer. Terms recurring in at least 1% of publications (n = 4) were analyzed.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">T3.xml</infon><infon key="id">T3</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table</infon><infon key="xml">&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;table frame=&quot;hsides&quot; rules=&quot;groups&quot;&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Most recurring&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;italic&gt;N&lt;/italic&gt; (% of 384)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;CPP&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Most highly cited&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;italic&gt;N&lt;/italic&gt; (% of 384)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;CPP&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Open innovation&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;184 (47.9)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;15.9&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;High technology&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;4 (1.0)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;185.3&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Innovation&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;168 (43.8)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;14.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Wide range&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;8 (2.1)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;102.5&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Paper&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;139 (36.2)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;9.7&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Outsourcing&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;8 (2.1)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;94.3&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Research&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;136 (35.4)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;17.9&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Drug administration&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;5 (1.3)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;67.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Development&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;121 (31.5)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;12.7&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;FDA&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;4 (1.0)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;64.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Study&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;116 (30.2)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;11.1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Paradigm&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;16&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;57.9&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Analysis&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;106 (27.6)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;11.7&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Outbound open innovation&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;5 (1.3)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;50.2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Process&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;103 (26.8)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;10.2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Supply&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;5 (1.3)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;40.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Model&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;92 (24.0)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;24.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Medium sized enterprise&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;7 (1.8)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;35.9&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Company&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;92 (24.0)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;17.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Development process&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;10 (2.6)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;35.4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Industry&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;85 (22.1)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;20.4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Mode&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;10 (2.6)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;35.4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Firm&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;84 (21.9)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;14.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Growth&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;28 (7.3)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;34.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Approach&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;82 (21.4)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;12.2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Open innovation research&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;6 (1.6)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;34.7&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Knowledge&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;82 (21.4)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;11.5&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Communication technology&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;5 (1.3)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;34.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Technology&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;76 (19.8)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;12.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Public private partnership&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;14 (3.6)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;34.4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Data&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;75 (19.5)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;16.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;NPD&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;6 (1.6)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;34.3&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Collaboration&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;70 (18.2)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;11.2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Pharmaceutical firm&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;14 (3.6)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;33.9&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Challenge&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;69 (18.0)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;15.3&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Practice&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;46 (12.0)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;32.1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Strategy&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;69 (18.0)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;14.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Bio-pharmaceutical industry&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;9 (2.3)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;31.9&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Need&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;65 (16.9)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;11.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Success factor&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;6 (1.6)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;31.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
</infon><offset>18069</offset><text>Most recurring	N (% of 384)	CPP	Most highly cited	N (% of 384)	CPP	 	Open innovation	184 (47.9)	15.9	High technology	4 (1.0)	185.3	 	Innovation	168 (43.8)	14.8	Wide range	8 (2.1)	102.5	 	Paper	139 (36.2)	9.7	Outsourcing	8 (2.1)	94.3	 	Research	136 (35.4)	17.9	Drug administration	5 (1.3)	67.8	 	Development	121 (31.5)	12.7	FDA	4 (1.0)	64.8	 	Study	116 (30.2)	11.1	Paradigm	16	57.9	 	Analysis	106 (27.6)	11.7	Outbound open innovation	5 (1.3)	50.2	 	Process	103 (26.8)	10.2	Supply	5 (1.3)	40.8	 	Model	92 (24.0)	24.6	Medium sized enterprise	7 (1.8)	35.9	 	Company	92 (24.0)	17.6	Development process	10 (2.6)	35.4	 	Industry	85 (22.1)	20.4	Mode	10 (2.6)	35.4	 	Firm	84 (21.9)	14.0	Growth	28 (7.3)	34.8	 	Approach	82 (21.4)	12.2	Open innovation research	6 (1.6)	34.7	 	Knowledge	82 (21.4)	11.5	Communication technology	5 (1.3)	34.6	 	Technology	76 (19.8)	12.6	Public private partnership	14 (3.6)	34.4	 	Data	75 (19.5)	16.6	NPD	6 (1.6)	34.3	 	Collaboration	70 (18.2)	11.2	Pharmaceutical firm	14 (3.6)	33.9	 	Challenge	69 (18.0)	15.3	Practice	46 (12.0)	32.1	 	Strategy	69 (18.0)	14.0	Bio-pharmaceutical industry	9 (2.3)	31.9	 	Need	65 (16.9)	11.6	Success factor	6 (1.6)	31.8	 	</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">T3.xml</infon><infon key="id">T3</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_footnote</infon><offset>19241</offset><text>CPP, citations per publication; FDA, United States Food and Drug Administration; NPD, new product development.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">T4.xml</infon><infon key="id">T4</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_caption</infon><offset>19352</offset><text>Top 20 most recurring author keywords.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">T4.xml</infon><infon key="id">T4</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table</infon><infon key="xml">&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;table frame=&quot;hsides&quot; rules=&quot;groups&quot;&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Author keyword&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;italic&gt;N&lt;/italic&gt; (out of 384)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Citations per publication&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Open innovation&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;159&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;9.7&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Innovation&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;33&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;8.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Pharmaceutical industry&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;23&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;4.5&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Drug discovery&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;17&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;10.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Collaboration&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;12&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;4.3&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Intellectual property&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;12&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;17.5&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Crowdsourcing&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;5.5&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Knowledge management&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;16.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Bio-pharmaceutical&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;4.3&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Healthcare&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;7.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Innovation management&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;5.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Licensing&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;10.9&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;R&amp;amp;D&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;4.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Technology transfer&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;3.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Drug development&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;10.2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Open source&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;9.5&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Patents&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;9.5&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Absorptive capacity&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;8.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Business model&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;6.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Entrepreneurship&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;29.4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
</infon><offset>19391</offset><text>Author keyword	N (out of 384)	Citations per publication	 	Open innovation	159	9.7	 	Innovation	33	8.8	 	Pharmaceutical industry	23	4.5	 	Drug discovery	17	10.6	 	Collaboration	12	4.3	 	Intellectual property	12	17.5	 	Crowdsourcing	11	5.5	 	Knowledge management	11	16.6	 	Bio-pharmaceutical	10	4.3	 	Healthcare	8	7.6	 	Innovation management	8	5.6	 	Licensing	7	10.9	 	R&amp;D	7	4.6	 	Technology transfer	7	3.6	 	Drug development	6	10.2	 	Open source	6	9.5	 	Patents	6	9.5	 	Absorptive capacity	5	8.0	 	Business model	5	6.8	 	Entrepreneurship	5	29.4	 	</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>19938</offset><text>Discussion</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>19949</offset><text>In this work, we perform for the first time a full-scale bibliometric analysis of the literature on open innovation implications in medical and pharmaceutical research.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>20118</offset><text>We found that publications that documented open innovation in medical and pharmaceutical research mainly began to appear in the mid-2000s. Many pharmaceutical and biotechnology companies were active in open innovation research, as the industry could provide consultations, contract research outsourcing, sponsored grants, and training and education and help spinout companies. An interesting finding is that industry-affiliated articles were cited more often than nonindustry publications. This finding echoed the results of, in which pharmaceutical industry articles were found to have higher mean citation counts than those of non-National Institutes of Health (NIH) publications but less mean citation counts than those NIH-supported articles. Generally, this could be interpreted as the research outputs of the industry-affiliated publications were of better quality; however, one of the potential reasons for the higher citation counts could be that the biotechnology/pharmaceutical companies have well-established networks and connections to disseminate research outputs to the academic audience and the general public. Moreover, compared to academic institutions, companies might invest more funding in visibility-promotion campaigns. An extensive analysis of marketing, governmental, and academic data has revealed that medical marketing expenditure in the United States increased from 18 to 30 billion from 1997 to 2016. Indeed, findings from the current study demonstrate that industry articles also received more attention from online social media and thus had a higher Altmetric score. Readers should be aware that the Altmetric score is based on mentions in multiple social media channels such as Facebook and Twitter, as well as in Wikipedia, online blogs, and news outlets. The score does not reflect the context of the mentions. Along this line, a previous study showed that press releases by pharmaceutical companies tended to focus on qualitative results and harms and adverse events, but not on quantitative results and study limitations, which might create some bias of online attention to this research.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>22243</offset><text>Besides, the predominant contributions from North America and Europe made this research field distinct from other biomedical fields such as neuropharmacology or ethnopharmacology, in which Asian and South American countries also had considerable inputs. Furthermore, in respect to the geographical distribution of author affiliations, the research literature on open innovation in medical and pharmaceutical research also differs from the literature on business incubators, in which China ranked 2nd in terms of the number of published articles. Italy not only was prolific in terms of publication numbers but also produced highly cited articles, for example, an exploratory analysis on the top 20 worldwide biopharmaceutical firms that revealed the usage of various methods (licensing agreements, nonequity alliance, and purchase and supply of technical and scientific services) in partnering with other companies and universities for both inbound and outbound technologies and knowledge. Another highly cited article described the collaboration between the United States and Europe to establish a public-private partnership, called Open PHACTS, to facilitate drug discovery. A similar public-private partnership was reported in the United States that attempted to establish a national program of active drug safety surveillance by pooling observational data. In Europe, a BIGCHEM project, funded by the European Union (Horizon 2020), was initiated to foster big data analysis in the age of chemoinformatics to drive pharmaceutical research collaboration between the industry and academia. With respect to Asia, open innovation research works were also published but gathered fewer than 30 citations each. For instance, a Japanese study evaluated how much scientific knowledge the pharmaceutical industry has assimilated from universities and research institutes and found that such assimilation was associated with patent applications and patent efficiency. In China, it was reported that pharmaceutical firms are involved more actively in open innovation and intellectual property protection, catching up fast once they managed to establish research and development departments and started collaborations.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>24452</offset><text>The open innovation movement has yielded a number of promising outcomes in drug discovery. One example is the identification of arylpyrroles with highly potent antimalarial properties through a broad industry-academia partnering and an open-source research approach involving real-time sharing of all data and ideas and enabling broad participation, without pursuing patents. Moreover, it was found that JQ1, a thienotriazolodiazepine and BET inhibitor reported with its intellectual property released to the scientific community on an open access basis upon discovery, had a greater uptake by more interdisciplinary research communities and a larger number of downstream patents compared to the conventionally developed equivalents.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>25186</offset><text>Seventeen articles within the analyzed dataset were identified by searching for crowdsourc* to reveal crowdsourcing-related research applications. Though these articles were mainly about drug discovery and pharmaceuticals, examples from other sectors could also be identified. In the context of health and astronomy, the NASA Human Health and Performance Directorate organized crowdsourcing competitions to identify viable potential collaborations with the private sector in response to steep budget reductions. In medicine, contest-based crowdsourcing has similarly benefited the genome study community by identifying new approaches to accelerate the analysis speed of a standard genetics software package by 18–45-fold. In the context of health and food industry, crowdsourcing could be helpful by utilizing the crowd’s data in various safety and quality aspects such as developing systems of foodborne illness surveillance and identification of contaminated products.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>26161</offset><text>While our analysis reveals that open innovation is very common in the area of pharmaceutical development (Table 2), it can be observed that open innovation was also applied to other areas of the medical sector, such as medical devices. For example, a pair of open-source ptosis crutch glasses was invented to support the drooping eyelids of patients with myasthenia gravis, and the open-source platform approach allows further open innovation to improve the product. Another example was a balloon sinuplasty device invented to treat severe chronic sinusitis. Upon observing the traumatic procedures of the conventional surgical approach, a medical device company invented a device to compress and displace structures in the congested area instead of cutting and removing; by collaborating with the academia to test and fine-tune the device, large-scale clinical studies finally proved its efficacy.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>27060</offset><text>Electronic health records could also be optimized by open innovation in a bottom-up approach, by gathering the feedback of participants attending a workshop who worked together to identify shortcomings and propose solutions to streamline the steps in the workflow. To promote the building of infrastructure for digital health, some open-source meta-data registry framework and core catalogs could be shared with the community to encourage collaborations and cross-disciplinary deployment. Taking into consideration that information technologies were historically one of the pioneer areas adopting open innovation, as well as the recent development boost in sectors such as telehealth, artificial intelligence, virtual reality, and wearable technologies, it is very likely that in the future, there will be an increasing application of open innovation strategies in areas such as digital therapeutics and digital health technologies.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>27993</offset><text>Interestingly, only two publications within the analyzed literature set referred to &quot;citizen science&quot;, with one of them representing a review of Virtual Health Networks and the other one focusing on policy implications of open science. Another aspect waiting to be further developed in the future is patient-centered innovation. Focus interviews have shown that stakeholders in the healthcare sector were keen on patient-centered care innovations, and initiatives have been launched in drug development and diabetes therapy. More patient-centered initiatives should be encouraged, and their efficacy evaluated in the future.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>28618</offset><text>Limitations</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>28630</offset><text>Our work focused on the bibliometric analysis of publication- and citation-related data and the semantic content of the title, abstract, and keywords. Therefore, systematic review or analysis of the product approval and improvements of health resulting from open innovation was not covered. Along this line, it should be kept in mind that the ultimate goal of innovation is to yield new products and, therefore, a detailed analysis of product approvals resulting from open innovation represents a very important direction for future work.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>29169</offset><text>Since the search string used in our work included the metaword pharma*, it was expected that the research area of “pharmacology and pharmacy” would be highly ranked in the analyzed literature set. Therefore, readers should be aware that generalizations for the relative prevalence of open innovation in different research sectors should not be directly drawn based on the results of our study and, clearly, open innovation plays a very important role in other research areas outside the medical/healthcare/pharma sectors.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>29695</offset><text>Since our study is based on data derived from just one database (Web of Science), there is an implication that some relevant articles might have been missed. However, different databases count citations differently, so it was not feasible to merge data from multiple databases for the present analysis.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>29998</offset><text>Conclusion</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>30009</offset><text>By studying 384 published research articles in the existing academic literature, it was found that open innovation in medical and pharmaceutical research began to appear in the literature in mid-2000s and most of the research was done in North America and Europe, with Asia lagging behind. Publications with authors affiliated with biotechnology or pharmaceutical companies had a higher mean citation count than nonindustry-affiliated articles and also received more social media attention. Various public-private partnerships that concerned financial and expertise support, sharing of intellectual property, and open platforms enabling easier communications, were introduced in the analyzed publications. Pharmaceuticals/pharmacology was revealed as an active industrial sector with medical significance promoting open innovation. However, taking into consideration the strong history of open innovation in the area of information technologies, it is feasible to expect that, in the future, there will be an increasing application of open innovation strategies from companies operating on the interface of information technology and medicine (e.g., in the area of digital health technologies). To harness the significant opportunities offered by open innovation, all relevant parties must be open to the changing landscape and embrace new models of collaboration with enthusiasm, without losing sight that the real quest is the development of solutions and products for the betterment of human health.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">SUPPL</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>31512</offset><text>Data Availability Statement</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">SUPPL</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>31540</offset><text>The original contributions presented in the study are included in the article/Supplementary Material; further inquiries can be directed to the corresponding authors.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">AUTH_CONT</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>31706</offset><text>Author Contributions</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">AUTH_CONT</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>31727</offset><text>AA and HW designed the study. AY and AA collected and analyzed data. AY and AA wrote the first draft. HS, EK, FE, SV-K, MK-P, HW, and ES critically revised the draft. All authors agreed to the final version.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">COMP_INT</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>31935</offset><text>Conflict of Interest</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">COMP_INT</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>31956</offset><text>The authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">title</infon><offset>32129</offset><text>References</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1775</infon><infon key="lpage">1779</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Albort-Morant;given-names:G.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Ribeiro-Soriano;given-names:D.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.jbusres.2015.10.054</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J. Bus. Res</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">69</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>32140</offset><text>A bibliometric analysis of international impact of business incubators</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">294</infon><infon key="lpage">303</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Alvim-Gaston;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Grese;given-names:T.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Mahoui;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Palkowitz;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Pineiro-Nunez;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Watson;given-names:I.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.2174/1568026613666131127125858</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">24283973</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Curr. Top. Med. Chem</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">14</infon><infon key="year">2014</infon><offset>32211</offset><text>Open Innovation Drug Discovery (OIDD): a potential path to novel therapeutic chemical space</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">392</infon><infon key="lpage">399</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Angelidis;given-names:P.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Berman;given-names:L.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Casas-Perez;given-names:M. L.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Celi;given-names:L. A.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Dafoulas;given-names:G. E.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Dagan;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1080/03091902.2016.1213903</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">27538360</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J. Med. Eng. Technol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">40</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>32303</offset><text>The hackathon model to spur innovation around global mHealth</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">321</infon><infon key="lpage">332</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Arshad;given-names:Z.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Smith;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Roberts;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Lee;given-names:W. H.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Davies;given-names:B.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Bure;given-names:K.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1517/17460441.2016.1144587</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Expet Opin. Drug Discov</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">11</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>32364</offset><text>Open access could transform drug discovery: a case study of JQ1</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1690</infon><infon key="lpage">1698</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Arvidsson;given-names:P. I.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Sandberg;given-names:K.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Forsberg-Nilsson;given-names:K.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.drudis.2016.06.026</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">27373760</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Drug Discov. Today</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">21</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>32428</offset><text>Open for collaboration: an academic platform for drug discovery and development at SciLifeLab</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">22</infon><infon key="lpage">33</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Bianchi;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Cavaliere;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Chiaroni;given-names:D.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Frattini;given-names:F.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Chiesa;given-names:V.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.21275/v5i5.nov163196</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Technovation</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">31</infon><infon key="year">2011</infon><offset>32522</offset><text>Organisational modes for Open Innovation in the bio-pharmaceutical industry: an exploratory analysis</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">900</infon><infon key="lpage">910</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Bieringer;given-names:T.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Buchholz;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Kockmann;given-names:N.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.22215/etd/2004-05761</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Chem. Eng. Technol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">36</infon><infon key="year">2013</infon><offset>32623</offset><text>Future production concepts in the chemical industry: modular–small‐scale–continuous</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1231</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Black;given-names:N.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1136/bmj.39059.444120.80</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">17170394</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">BMJ</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">333</infon><infon key="year">2006</infon><offset>32713</offset><text>The Cooksey review of UK health research funding</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">977</infon><infon key="lpage">984</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Bonney;given-names:R.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Cooper;given-names:C. B.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Dickinson;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Kelling;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Phillips;given-names:T.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Rosenberg;given-names:K. V.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.7200/esicm.165.0511.2</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Bioscience</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">59</infon><infon key="year">2009</infon><offset>32762</offset><text>Citizen science: a developing tool for expanding science knowledge and scientific literacy</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">614</infon><infon key="lpage">616</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Braune;given-names:E.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Van Dam;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Szalma;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1038/clpt.2010.21</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">20376001</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Clin. Pharmacol. Ther</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">87</infon><infon key="year">2010</infon><offset>32853</offset><text>How informatics can potentiate precompetitive open-source collaboration to jump-start drug discovery and development</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">439</infon><infon key="lpage">452</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Camarinha-Matos;given-names:L. M.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Afsarmanesh;given-names:H.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1515/9783110640489-001</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J. Intell. Manuf</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">16</infon><infon key="year">2005</infon><offset>32970</offset><text>Collaborative networks: a new scientific discipline</text></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Camarinha-Matos;given-names:L. M.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Afsarmanesh;given-names:H.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Ollus;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Virtual Organizations: systems and practices</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2006</infon><offset>33022</offset></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">776</infon><infon key="lpage">785</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Carroll;given-names:G. P.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Srivastava;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Volini;given-names:A. S.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Piñeiro-Núñez;given-names:M. M.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Vetman;given-names:T.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.drudis.2017.01.009</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">28137644</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Drug Discov. Today</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">22</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>33023</offset><text>Measuring the effectiveness and impact of an open innovation platform</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">e20420</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Cen;given-names:Y.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Li;given-names:Y.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Huang;given-names:C.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Wang;given-names:W.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000020420</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">32481438</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Medicine (Baltimore)</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">99</infon><infon key="year">2020</infon><offset>33093</offset><text>Bibliometric and visualized analysis of global research on fungal keratitis from 1959 to 2019</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1533</infon><infon key="lpage">1545</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Chen;given-names:Y. M.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Wang;given-names:X. Q.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.2147/JPR.S258696</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">32612381</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J. Pain Res</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">13</infon><infon key="year">2020</infon><offset>33187</offset><text>Bibliometric analysis of exercise and neuropathic pain research</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">3</infon><infon key="lpage">28</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Chesbrough;given-names:H.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Bogers;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">New Frontiers in open innovation</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2014</infon><offset>33251</offset><text>Explicating open innovation: clarifying an emerging paradigm for understanding innovation</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">229</infon><infon key="lpage">236</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Chesbrough;given-names:H.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Crowther;given-names:A. K.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.ibusrev.2017.02.007</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">R&amp;D Manage</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">36</infon><infon key="year">2006</infon><offset>33341</offset><text>Beyond high tech: early adopters of open innovation in other industries</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">891</infon><infon key="lpage">897</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Chin-Dusting;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Mizrahi;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Jennings;given-names:G.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Fitzgerald;given-names:D.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1038/nrd1879</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">16247439</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Nat. Rev. Drug Discov</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">4</infon><infon key="year">2005</infon><offset>33413</offset><text>Outlook: finding improved medicines: the role of academic-industrial collaboration</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">52</infon><infon key="lpage">58</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Davis;given-names:J. R.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Richard;given-names:E. E.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Keeton;given-names:K. E.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.5539/ibr.v13n12p27</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Res. Technol. Manag</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">58</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>33496</offset><text>Open innovation at NASA: a new business model for advancing human health and performance innovations</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">22</infon><infon key="lpage">29</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Fortuna;given-names:G.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Aria;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Piscitelli;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Mignogna;given-names:M. D.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Klasser;given-names:G. D.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1111/jop.13077</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J. Oral Pathol. Med</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">11</infon><infon key="year">2020</infon><offset>33597</offset><text>Global research trends in complex oral sensitivity disorder: a systematic bibliometric analysis of the structures of knowledge</text></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Gassmann;given-names:O.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Enkel;given-names:E.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2004</infon><offset>33724</offset><text>Towards a theory of open innovation: three core process archetypes</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">S15</infon><infon key="lpage">S17</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Hall;given-names:M. D.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Dufton;given-names:A. M.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Katso;given-names:R. M.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Gatsi;given-names:S. A.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Williams;given-names:P. M.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Strange;given-names:M. E.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.5830/CVJA-2015-042</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">25962942</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Cardiovasc. J. Afr</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">26</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>33791</offset><text>Strategic investments in non-communicable diseases (NCD) research in Africa: the GSK Africa NCD open Lab</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">320</infon><infon key="lpage">2</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Harris;given-names:T.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Papadopoulos;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Goldstein;given-names:D. B.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.tibtech.2015.02.009</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">25987446</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Trends Biotechnol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">33</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>33896</offset><text>Academic-industrial partnerships in drug discovery in the age of genomics</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Hill;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Loh;given-names:P. R.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Bharadwaj;given-names:R. B.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Pons;given-names:P.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Shang;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Guinan;given-names:E.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1093/gigascience/gix009</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">GigaScience</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">6</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>33970</offset><text>Stepwise distributed open innovation contests for software development: acceleration of genome-wide association analysis</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">798</infon><infon key="lpage">801</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Hirsch;given-names:G.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1002/cpt.1237</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">30390315</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Clin. Pharmacol. Ther</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">105</infon><infon key="year">2019</infon><offset>34091</offset><text>Leaping together toward sustainable, patient-centered innovation: the value of a multistakeholder safe haven for accelerating system change</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">S53</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Hodson;given-names:R.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1038/533S53a</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">27167389</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Nature</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">533</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>34231</offset><text>Open innovation</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">A18</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Hussey;given-names:P.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Tully;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Farrell;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Coyne;given-names:E.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Connolly;given-names:P.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Glynn;given-names:C.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1515/9783110640489-005</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Int. J. Integrated Care</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">19</infon><infon key="year">2019</infon><offset>34247</offset><text>Building infrastructure for digital health using Open innovation 2.0 in co design of a meta data registry framework to support integrated care</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1699</infon><infon key="lpage">1710</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Kirkegaard;given-names:H. S.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Valentin;given-names:F.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1504/ijeim.2007.014596</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">24953708</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Drug Discov. Today</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">19</infon><infon key="year">2014</infon><offset>34390</offset><text>Academic drug discovery centres: the economic and organisational sustainability of an emerging model</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">e2828</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Kuriya;given-names:B.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Schneid;given-names:E. C.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Bell;given-names:C. M.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0002828</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">18716675</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">PLoS One</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">3</infon><infon key="year">2008</infon><offset>34491</offset><text>Quality of pharmaceutical industry press releases based on original research</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">588</infon><infon key="lpage">602</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Lee;given-names:J. A.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Chu;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Willard;given-names:F. S.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Cox;given-names:K. L.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Sells Galvin;given-names:R. J.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Peery;given-names:R. B.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1177/1087057111405379</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">21521801</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J. Biomol. Screen</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">16</infon><infon key="year">2011</infon><offset>34568</offset><text>Open innovation for phenotypic drug discovery: the PD2 assay panel</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">e0130796</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Lee;given-names:J. A.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Shinn;given-names:P.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Jaken;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Oliver;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Willard;given-names:F. S.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Heidler;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0130796</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">26177200</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">PLoS One</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">10</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>34635</offset><text>Novel phenotypic outcomes identified for a public collection of approved drugs from a publicly accessible panel of assays</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">12</infon><infon key="lpage">39</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Murphy;given-names:B. P.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:O’raghallaigh;given-names:P.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Carr;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1177/1460458220906067</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Health Inf. J</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">7</infon><infon key="year">2020</infon><offset>34757</offset><text>Nurturing the digital baby: open innovation for development and optimization</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">139</infon><infon key="lpage">154</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Narin;given-names:F.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Rozek;given-names:R. P.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/0048-7333(88)90039-x</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Res. Pol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">17</infon><infon key="year">1988</infon><offset>34834</offset><text>Bibliometric analysis of US pharmaceutical industry research performance</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">e15368</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:O'donnell;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Lewis;given-names:D.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Marchante Fernández;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Wäldchen;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Cleal;given-names:B.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Skinner;given-names:T.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.2196/15368</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">31742563</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">JMIR Res. Protoc</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">8</infon><infon key="year">2019</infon><offset>34907</offset><text>Evidence on user-led innovation in diabetes technology (the OPEN project): protocol for a mixed methods study</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">120</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Reed;given-names:P.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Conrad;given-names:D. A.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Hernandez;given-names:S. E.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Watts;given-names:C.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Marcus-Smith;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1186/1471-2296-13-120</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">23241305</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">BMC Fam. Pract</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">13</infon><infon key="year">2012</infon><offset>35017</offset><text>Innovation in patient-centered care: lessons from a qualitative study of innovative health care organizations in Washington State</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1159</infon><infon key="lpage">1175</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Ren;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Su;given-names:P.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/0048-7333(83)90024-0</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Technol. Anal. Strat. Manag</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">27</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>35147</offset><text>Open innovation and intellectual property strategy: the catch-up processes of two Chinese pharmaceutical firms</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1129</infon><infon key="lpage">1132</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Rifai;given-names:N.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Topol;given-names:E.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Chan;given-names:E.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Lo;given-names:Y. M.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Wittwer;given-names:C. T.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1373/clinchem.2015.243667</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">26152753</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Clin. Chem</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">61</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>35258</offset><text>Disruptive innovation in laboratory medicine</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">137</infon><infon key="lpage">143</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Saidi;given-names:T.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Sivarasu;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Douglas;given-names:T. S.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1080/17434440.2018.1421455</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Expet Rev. Med. Dev</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">15</infon><infon key="year">2018</infon><offset>35303</offset><text>Open source modular ptosis crutch for the treatment of myasthenia gravis</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">491</infon><infon key="lpage">509</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Saito;given-names:H.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Sumikura;given-names:K.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/b978-0-12-811065-2.00006-0</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Int. J. Innovat. Manag</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">14</infon><infon key="year">2010</infon><offset>35376</offset><text>An empirical analysis on absorptive capacity based on linkage with academia</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">S56</infon><infon key="lpage">8</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Savage;given-names:N.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1038/533S56a</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">27167391</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Nature</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">533</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>35452</offset><text>Competition: unlikely partnerships</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">5923</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Schnoor;given-names:J. L.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1017/cbo9780511522031.003</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">17937254</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Environ. Sci. Technol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">41</infon><infon key="year">2007</infon><offset>35487</offset><text>Citizen science</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1133</infon><infon key="lpage">1137</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Schuhmacher;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Germann;given-names:P. G.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Trill;given-names:H.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Gassmann;given-names:O.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.drudis.2013.07.013</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">23892183</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Drug Discov. Today</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">18</infon><infon key="year">2013</infon><offset>35503</offset><text>Models for open innovation in the pharmaceutical industry</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">80</infon><infon key="lpage">96</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Schwartz;given-names:L. M.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Woloshin;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.4324/9781315591186</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">30620375</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">JAMA</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">321</infon><infon key="year">2019</infon><offset>35561</offset><text>Medical marketing in the United States, 1997–2016</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">63</infon><infon key="lpage">72</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Soon;given-names:J. M.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Saguy;given-names:I. S.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1017/cbo9780511522031.005</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Trends Food Sci. Technol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">66</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>35613</offset><text>Crowdsourcing: a new conceptual view for food safety and quality</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">600</infon><infon key="lpage">6</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Stang;given-names:P. E.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Ryan;given-names:P. B.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Racoosin;given-names:J. A.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Overhage;given-names:J. M.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Hartzema;given-names:A. G.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Reich;given-names:C.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.7326/0003-4819-153-9-201011020-00010</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">21041580</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Ann. Intern. Med</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">153</infon><infon key="year">2010</infon><offset>35678</offset><text>Advancing the science for active surveillance: rationale and design for the Observational Medical Outcomes Partnership</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">647</infon><infon key="lpage">653</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Stewart;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Barone;given-names:P.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Bellisario;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Cooney;given-names:C.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Sharp;given-names:P.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Sinskey;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1002/cpt.504</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">27617845</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Clin. Pharmacol. Ther</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">100</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>35797</offset><text>Leveraging industry-academia collaborations in Adaptive biomedical innovation</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">A05</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Stodden;given-names:V.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1017/cbo9780511522031.007</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J. Sci. Commun</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">9</infon><infon key="year">2010</infon><offset>35875</offset><text>Open science: policy implications for the evolving phenomenon of user-led scientific innovation</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">615</infon><infon key="lpage">621</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Tetko;given-names:I. V.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Engkvist;given-names:O.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Koch;given-names:U.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Reymond;given-names:J. L.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Chen;given-names:H.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1002/minf.201600073</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">27464907</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Mol Inform</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">35</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>35971</offset><text>BIGCHEM: challenges and opportunities for big data analysis in chemistry</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">288</infon><infon key="lpage">292</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Lessl;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Schoepe;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Sommer;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Schneider;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Asadullah;given-names:K.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.drudis.2010.11.013</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">21129498</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Drug Discov. Today</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">16</infon><infon key="year">2011</infon><offset>36044</offset><text>Grants4Targets—an innovative approach to translate ideas from basic research into novel drugs</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1</infon><infon key="lpage">12</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Woodcock;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Woosley;given-names:R.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1146/annurev.med.59.090506.155819</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">18186700</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Annu. Rev. Med</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">59</infon><infon key="year">2008</infon><offset>36140</offset><text>The FDA critical path initiative and its influence on new drug development</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1504</infon><infon key="lpage">1514</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Trequattrini;given-names:R.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Lombardi;given-names:R.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Lardo;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Della Rosa;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Bolici;given-names:F.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>36215</offset><text>A Review of Virtual Health Networks: online communities that manage health information reducing environmental uncertainty</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">e6762</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Tucker;given-names:J. D.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Day;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Tang;given-names:W.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Bayus;given-names:B.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.7717/peerj.6762</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">30997295</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">PeerJ</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">7</infon><infon key="year">2019</infon><offset>36337</offset><text>Crowdsourcing in medical research: concepts and applications</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1450032</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Wan;given-names:H.-H.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Quan;given-names:X. I.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.7324/japs.2019.90515</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Int. J. Innovat. Technol. Manag</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">11</infon><infon key="year">2014</infon><offset>36398</offset><text>Toward a framework of the process of open innovation—Case of acclarent in the medical device Industry</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">121</infon><infon key="lpage">133</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Wass;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Vimarlund;given-names:V.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1177/1833358316639458</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">HIM J</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">45</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>36502</offset><text>Healthcare in the age of open innovation - a literature review</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">3</infon><infon key="lpage">14</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Wiggins;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Wilbanks;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.2139/ssrn.3620176</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Am. J. Bioeth</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">19</infon><infon key="year">2019</infon><offset>36565</offset><text>The rise of citizen science in health and biomedical research</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1188</infon><infon key="lpage">1198</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Williams;given-names:A. J.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Harland;given-names:L.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Groth;given-names:P.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Pettifer;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Chichester;given-names:C.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Willighagen;given-names:E. L.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.drudis.2012.05.016</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">22683805</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Drug Discov. Today</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">17</infon><infon key="year">2012</infon><offset>36627</offset><text>Open PHACTS: semantic interoperability for drug discovery</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">687</infon><infon key="lpage">701</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Williamson;given-names:A. E.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Ylioja;given-names:P. M.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Robertson;given-names:M. N.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Antonova-Koch;given-names:Y.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Avery;given-names:V.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Baell;given-names:J. B.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1021/acscentsci.6b00086</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">27800551</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">ACS Cent. Sci</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">2</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>36685</offset><text>Open source drug discovery: highly potent antimalarial compounds derived from the tres cantos arylpyrroles</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">112414</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Yeung;given-names:A. W. K.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Heinrich;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Kijjoa;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Tzvetkov;given-names:N. T.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Atanasov;given-names:A. G.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.jep.2019.112414</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">31751650</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J. Ethnopharmacol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">250</infon><infon key="year">2020</infon><offset>36792</offset><text>The ethnopharmacological literature: an analysis of the scientific landscape</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">852</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Yeung;given-names:A. W. K.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Tzvetkov;given-names:N. T.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Atanasov;given-names:A. G.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.3389/fnins.2018.00852</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">30505266</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Front. Neurosci</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">12</infon><infon key="year">2018</infon><offset>36869</offset><text>When neuroscience meets pharmacology: a neuropharmacology literature analysis</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">8278454</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Yeung;given-names:A. W. K.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Tzvetkov;given-names:N. T.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:El-Tawil;given-names:O. S.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Bungǎu;given-names:S. G.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Abdel-Daim;given-names:M. M.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Atanasov;given-names:A. G.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1155/2019/8278454</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">30728893</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Oxid Med. Cell Longev</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">2019</infon><infon key="year">2019a</infon><offset>36947</offset><text>Antioxidants: scientific literature landscape analysis</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">34</infon><infon key="lpage">40</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Yeung;given-names:A. W. K.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Tzvetkov;given-names:N. T.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Gupta;given-names:V. K.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Gupta;given-names:S. C.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Orive;given-names:G.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Bonn;given-names:G. K.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1002/biot.201000035</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Curr. Res. Biotechnol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">1</infon><infon key="year">2019b</infon><offset>37002</offset><text>Current research in biotechnology: exploring the biotech forefront</text></passage></document></collection>
