<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd">
<collection><source>PMC</source><date>20210402</date><key>pmc.key</key><document><id>8014172</id><infon key="license">NO-CC CODE</infon><passage><infon key="alt-title">LETTER TO THE EDITOR</infon><infon key="article-id_doi">10.1002/jso.26417</infon><infon key="article-id_pmc">8014172</infon><infon key="article-id_pmid">33559142</infon><infon key="article-id_publisher-id">JSO26417</infon><infon key="fpage">1204</infon><infon key="issue">5</infon><infon key="license">This article is being made freely available through PubMed Central as part of the COVID-19 public health emergency response. It can be used for unrestricted research re-use and analysis in any form or by any means with acknowledgement of the original source, for the duration of the public health emergency.</infon><infon key="lpage">1205</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Kaul;given-names:Pallvi</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Garg;given-names:Pankaj Kumar</infon><infon key="section_type">TITLE</infon><infon key="type">front</infon><infon key="volume">123</infon><infon key="year">2021</infon><offset>0</offset><text>Crowdsourcing and global collaboration during COVID‐19 pandemic: A silver lining</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>83</offset><text> Dear Editor, </text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>98</offset><text>With the initial cases of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS‐CoV‐2) infection first reported in December 2019 in the Wuhan city of China, 1  the coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID‐19) pandemic has completed it's first‐anniversary and has had an unprecedented adverse impact on almost all domains of basic and clinical research worldwide. Several authors 2 ,  3 ,  4 ,  5  have elaborated the short‐term and long‐term adverse consequences of the COVID‐19 pandemic on various facets of scientific research and its dissemination, and training. However, every adversity is an opportunity and brings positive changes as well, and so is the COVID‐19 pandemic. Several constructive changes that have been brought forward by the COVID‐19 pandemic will continue to shape the scientific research and training in the years to come (Figure 1).</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">JSO-123-1204-g001.jpg</infon><infon key="id">jso26417-fig-0001</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>964</offset><text>Displays the positive impact of COVID‐19 pandemic on scientific research and publications [Color figure can be viewed at wileyonlinelibrary.com]</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>1111</offset><text>The sheer pace with which the scientific community responded to the difficulties posed by the COVID‐19 pandemic is commendable considering that scientific research and dissemination is traditionally considered a slow process. A Pubmed search with the keyword “COVID” yielded 92,869 articles on January 21st, 2021 confirming a “Publication‐tsunami” of COVID‐related literature. However, the COVID‐19 pandemic has also provided an excellent opportunity for merging the latent and emerging issues with scientific review and research dissemination. The rapid output of scientific research in response to the COVID‐19 pandemic has reinforced that internal validity, credibility, and reproducibility are the critical components of scientific communication. Any loopholes in these critical components have tremendous potential for real‐world harm—akin to the Surgisphere debacle. 6  There is a need to share data generated through a large number of trials that are being conducted worldwide as it would bring in transparency and promote reusability of the data for secondary research. 7  At the same time, the medical diaspora and the scientific community must be wary of p‐hacking, file‐drawer effect, salami‐slicing, or any other identifiable biases that plague the clinical research and culminates into compromised patient care/treatment outcomes.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>2483</offset><text>Another positive impact of the current COVID‐19 pandemic has been a growing impetus to crowdsourcing in the health sector and clinical research. Crowdsourcing classically means involving a large number of people who work collectively to solve a problem or to complete a task with some objectives adhering to an adage—No one knows everything, but everyone knows something—collective intelligence. We believe that focussed crowdsourcing in healthcare should also include group participation (interinstitutional within a country or across the countries) and sharing solutions for the larger public benefit. The current pandemic has brought together researchers and clinicians from all over the world to crowdsource their innovative ideas, disease‐related data, and resources to quickly develop the treatment guidelines and research strategies. 8  The oncology community has also acclimatized to the existing trends and is promoting a tailored treatment approved by a multidisciplinary team consensus which is feasible and in the best interest of the patient. The zeal with which the scientists are collaborating worldwide with unwavering unity to confront the virus is unprecedented and unparallel. It has provided a new impetus to the progress of science. This crowdsourcing and global collaboration are especially crucial for developing countries lacking health resources and comprehensive research infrastructure. A review of early publications related to cancer and COVID‐19 infection highlighted that almost one‐fifth of the articles (38 of 212) was published as a part of international collaborations. 9  In an excellent example of crowdsourcing, COVIDsurg collaborative 10  analyzed the mortality and pulmonary complications in 1128 patients with perioperative SARS‐CoV‐2 infection; the data was collected from 235 hospitals in 24 countries.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>4345</offset><text>In conclusion, the COVID‐19 pandemic has certainly opened up new avenues for crowdsourcing and global collaboration through virtual meetings and networking for research in medicine and healthcare, as well as to harness the human intelligence and creativity of a large number of people residing in developing countries with scarce resources. There is also an urgent need to emphasize and ensure that the growing global public health research and evidence‐based medicine must translate into better patient care.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">title</infon><offset>4859</offset><text>REFERENCES</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">649</infon><infon key="issue">8</infon><infon key="lpage">657</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">32841948</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Respiration</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">99</infon><infon key="year">2020</infon><offset>4870</offset><text>Clinical characteristics of patients with severe pneumonia caused by the SARS‐CoV‐2 in Wuhan, China</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">829</infon><infon key="issue">10</infon><infon key="lpage">830</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">33283850</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Ann Acad Med Singap</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">49</infon><infon key="year">2020</infon><offset>4974</offset><text>The impact of COVID‐19 pandemic on medical research</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">JAMA Oncol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2020</infon><offset>5028</offset><text>Scientific rigor in the age of COVID‐19</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">57</infon><infon key="lpage">63</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">33444873</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Int J Surg</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">86</infon><infon key="year">2021</infon><offset>5070</offset><text>Impact of the coronavirus (COVID‐19) pandemic on scientific research and implications for clinical academic training—a review</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">24</infon><infon key="issue">1</infon><infon key="lpage">31</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">33084056</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Surg Oncol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">123</infon><infon key="year">2021</infon><offset>5200</offset><text>Impact of COVID‐19 lockdown measures on oncological surgical activity: analysis of the surgical pathology caseload of a tertiary referral hospital in Northwestern Italy</text></passage><passage><infon key="elocation-id">e102</infon><infon key="issue">25</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">32356626</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">N Engl J Med</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">382</infon><infon key="year">2020</infon><offset>5371</offset><text>Cardiovascular disease, drug therapy, and mortality in COVID‐19</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Ther Innov Regul Sci</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2020</infon><offset>5437</offset><text>Open science to address COVID‐19: sharing data to make our research investment go further</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1262</infon><infon key="lpage">1263</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">32761619</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Surg Oncol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">122</infon><infon key="year">2020</infon><offset>5529</offset><text>Cancer surgery in the era of COVID‐19 pandemic: changing dynamics</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">579</infon><infon key="lpage">593</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Surg Oncol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">122</infon><infon key="year">2020</infon><offset>5597</offset><text>Discordance of COVID‐19 guidelines for patients with cancer: a systematic review</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">27</infon><infon key="issue">10243</infon><infon key="lpage">38</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">32479829</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Lancet</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">396</infon><infon key="year">2020</infon><offset>5680</offset><text>Mortality and pulmonary complications in patients undergoing surgery with perioperative SARS‐CoV‐2 infection: an international cohort study</text></passage></document></collection>
