<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd">
<collection><source>PMC</source><date>20211111</date><key>pmc.key</key><document><id>8571913</id><infon key="license">CC BY-NC</infon><passage><infon key="article-id_doi">10.1093/jamiaopen/ooab090</infon><infon key="article-id_pmc">8571913</infon><infon key="article-id_pmid">34755049</infon><infon key="article-id_publisher-id">ooab090</infon><infon key="elocation-id">ooab090</infon><infon key="issue">4</infon><infon key="kwd">cancer survivors (D000073116) crowdsourcing (D063045) risk factors (D012307) expert systems (D005103)</infon><infon key="license">This is an Open Access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial License (https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/), which permits non-commercial re-use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original work is properly cited. For commercial re-use, please contact journals.permissions@oup.com</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Cheng;given-names:Alex C</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Wen;given-names:Li</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Li;given-names:Yanwei</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Koyama;given-names:Tatsuki</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Berry;given-names:Lynne D</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Pal;given-names:Tuya</infon><infon key="name_6">surname:Friedman;given-names:Debra L</infon><infon key="name_7">surname:Osterman;given-names:Travis J</infon><infon key="section_type">TITLE</infon><infon key="type">front</infon><infon key="volume">4</infon><infon key="year">2021</infon><offset>0</offset><text>Follow-up Interactive Long-Term Expert Ranking (FILTER): a crowdsourcing platform to adjudicate risk for survivorship care</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract_title_1</infon><offset>123</offset><text>Abstract</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract_title_1</infon><offset>132</offset><text>Objectives</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>143</offset><text>To develop an online crowdsourcing platform where oncologists and other survivorship experts can adjudicate risk for complications in follow-up.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract_title_1</infon><offset>288</offset><text>Materials and Methods</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>310</offset><text>This platform, called Follow-up Interactive Long-Term Expert Ranking (FILTER), prompts participants to adjudicate risk between each of a series of pairs of synthetic cases. The Elo ranking algorithm is used to assign relative risk to each synthetic case.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract_title_1</infon><offset>565</offset><text>Results</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>573</offset><text>The FILTER application is currently live and implemented as a web application deployed on the cloud.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract_title_1</infon><offset>674</offset><text>Discussion</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>685</offset><text>While guidelines for following cancer survivors exist, refinement of survivorship care based on risk for complications after active treatment could improve both allocation of resources and individual outcomes in long-term follow-up.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract_title_1</infon><offset>918</offset><text>Conclusion</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>929</offset><text>FILTER provides a means for a large number of experts to adjudicate risk for survivorship complications with a low barrier of entry.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>1062</offset><text>BACKGROUND AND SIGNIFICANCE</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>1090</offset><text> An estimated 5% of the US population (16.9 million people) are cancer survivors. For these individuals, care should focus on disease surveillance and health promotion to prevent or ameliorate chronic health issues and subsequent malignancies. Adverse health outcomes are well documented among cancer survivors, especially in underserved populations due to barriers to obtaining care such as financial toxicity, low income, transportation, and insurance inadequacy. Services must therefore address and minimize adverse cancer treatment sequele and decrease risk for recurrent or subsequent malignancies.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>1694</offset><text>For well over a decade, national best practice guidelines have recommended that cancer survivors receive survivorship care. Definitions of levels of survivorship care vary widely, but generally determine the frequency that patients are seen by an oncology team vs a primary care provider. A “one-size-fits-all” model is neither feasible nor sustainable. As cancer care is becoming more precise, so too should survivorship care. Care plans should be tailored to the level of services required and based on each patient’s unique set of risk factors. This concept of stratified survivorship care exists in the United Kingdom through the National Cancer Survivorship Initiative and has been appropriately proposed in the United States.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>2432</offset><text>As defined by Oeffinger and McCabe, an individual’s survivorship risk is their chance of premature mortality, serious morbidity, or adverse health status. Currently, risk stratification models for survivorship primarily consider intensity of the cancer treatment and likelihood of adverse health conditions, based on limited expert opinion. Development of a data-driven survivorship risk model would require rigorously collected and sufficiently comprehensive long-term follow-up data—a resource currently lacking in the electronic health record (EHR) or cancer registries. Expert opinion remains the best available resource to assign a survivor into a low, medium, or high-risk group. However, access to these experts is limited in the healthcare settings where they are needed most, such as in community-based rural clinics.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>3263</offset><text>OBJECTIVES</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>3274</offset><text>To address this gap, we are seeking to develop a survivorship risk model that calculates a patient’s required level of follow-up care based on their disease, treatment, genetic, socioeconomic, and demographic factors using clinical knowledge from a large group of experts. We have developed a risk stratification crowdsourcing platform called follow-up interactive long-term expert ranking (FILTER), which invites oncologists and survivorship care experts to judge survivorship follow-up complexity.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>3776</offset><text>MATERIALS AND METHODS</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>3798</offset><text>Design considerations for clinical expert crowdsourcing</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>3854</offset><text>Our goal was to leverage the expertise of many oncologists and survivorship experts to create a risk-informed algorithm for survivorship care. Crowdsourcing as a means of codifying clinical knowledge is a relatively new concept in oncology and clinical research. Nevertheless, expert data curation through tools custom-designed for crowdsourcing has been essential for generating datasets for machine learning and artificial intelligence research in healthcare.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>4316</offset><text>For success, such tools must address barriers inherent to development and implementation of a crowdsourcing platform. Table  1 summarizes some of these challenges and how our innovative design overcomes each barrier. Because we used a synthetic dataset instead of actual cancer cases, our institutional review board (IRB) determined the adjudication process to be nonhuman subjects research. We were able to avoid many of the regulatory hurdles common in crowdsourced medical research such as waivers of informed consent, privacy controls, and handling of sensitive data. Instead of developing extensive training materials to ensure experts of different backgrounds applied a uniform approach to rating, we developed our interface with simple instructions. Experts can sign up for an account and start adjudicating cases within minutes. Furthermore, each expert may adjudicate any number of cases with no minimum requirement. Even with just a few cases, each expert still provides information for the ranking algorithm to determine a synthetic case’s relative risk. This low barrier of entry facilitates knowledge capture from busy experts across a diverse range of expertise.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">ooab090-T1.xml</infon><infon key="id">ooab090-T1</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_caption</infon><offset>5497</offset><text>Summary of crowdsourcing platform barriers and how FILTER addresses these barriers</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">ooab090-T1.xml</infon><infon key="id">ooab090-T1</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table</infon><infon key="xml">&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;table frame=&quot;hsides&quot; rules=&quot;groups&quot;&gt;&lt;colgroup span=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;col valign=&quot;top&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col valign=&quot;top&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Crowdsourcing platform barrier&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;FILTER solution&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Experts are limited to a single institution’s staff and/or external experts under a data use agreement (DUA). IRB approval and oversight can delay data collection.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Use of synthetic cases instead of real patient information allows a large number of adjudicators from many institutions without IRB approvals or DUAs.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Due to experts of different types and levels of expertise, training participants on uniform criteria and approach for adjudication is difficult and can lead to low inter-rater agreement.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Use of a self-explanatory interface with simple instructions for adjudication obviates the need for training.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Each expert must adjudicate a minimum number of cases to ensure sufficient overlap for assessment of inter-rater reliability. This can delay the project as experts tend to be busy.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Experts can adjudicate as many or as few cases as they wish. Even with just a few cases, each expert provides information useful to determine risk.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Due to the complexity of clinical cases, accurate assessment of risk on an absolute scale may present challenges.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Requiring only one-to-one comparison of relative risk is easier to understand and judge.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
</infon><offset>5580</offset><text>Crowdsourcing platform barrier	FILTER solution	 	Experts are limited to a single institution’s staff and/or external experts under a data use agreement (DUA). IRB approval and oversight can delay data collection.	Use of synthetic cases instead of real patient information allows a large number of adjudicators from many institutions without IRB approvals or DUAs.	 	Due to experts of different types and levels of expertise, training participants on uniform criteria and approach for adjudication is difficult and can lead to low inter-rater agreement.	Use of a self-explanatory interface with simple instructions for adjudication obviates the need for training.	 	Each expert must adjudicate a minimum number of cases to ensure sufficient overlap for assessment of inter-rater reliability. This can delay the project as experts tend to be busy.	Experts can adjudicate as many or as few cases as they wish. Even with just a few cases, each expert provides information useful to determine risk.	 	Due to the complexity of clinical cases, accurate assessment of risk on an absolute scale may present challenges.	Requiring only one-to-one comparison of relative risk is easier to understand and judge.	 	</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">ooab090-T1.xml</infon><infon key="id">ooab090-T1</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_footnote</infon><offset>6784</offset><text>FILTER: follow-up interactive long-term expert ranking.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>6840</offset><text>RESULTS</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>6848</offset><text>Ranking interface and algorithm</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>6880</offset><text>The FILTER application has been deployed on the cloud and is available for experts to create an account and adjudicate cases. Figure  1 is a screenshot of the FILTER interface with an example matchup that an expert might adjudicate. For each adjudication, the expert is presented with the question, “Which of the following scenarios requires a higher level of survivorship follow up?”</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">ooab090f1.jpg</infon><infon key="id">ooab090-F1</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>7271</offset><text>Expert adjudicator FILTER interface.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>7308</offset><text>The expert has the option to choose the case to the right, the case to the left, or rank as equal. After each judgment, the scores for the two cases are adjusted using the Elo rating algorithm.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>7502</offset><text> RA is the current score and RBi is the score of opponent.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>7561</offset><text>This algorithm, originally developed to rate chess players, sets an expectation that cases with higher scores will likely “win” against cases with lower scores. With each selection, the “winning” case is increased in point value, and the point value of the “losing” case is decreased. The magnitude of point-value change is dependent on how far apart the scores started, with larger changes in the event of an “upset”. We chose the Elo ranking algorithm over others primarily because Elo does not require us to predefine the number of cases that we want to adjudicate, which allows us to add new cases as more matchups are adjudicated. Additionally, the resulting Elo score is parametric, which allows us to consider the magnitude of differences in scores rather than just their order.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>8363</offset><text>New case creation and matchup algorithm</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>8403</offset><text>Because neither the number of experts nor the number of adjudications per expert is prespecified, we designed FILTER to dynamically generate new synthetic cases whenever a sufficient number of matchups have occurred. Each new case is randomly assigned risk factors from each domain in Table  2. This list was generated by authors (TO, DF, and TP) who are experts in oncology survivorship and genetic risk factors in cancer. Our matchup algorithm ensures new cases matched to enough existing cases to establish a starting rank. Existing cases are also periodically rematched against one another to reconfirm their place in the ranking.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">ooab090-T2.xml</infon><infon key="id">ooab090-T2</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_caption</infon><offset>9040</offset><text>Survivorship risk factors by domain</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">ooab090-T2.xml</infon><infon key="id">ooab090-T2</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table</infon><infon key="xml">&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;table frame=&quot;hsides&quot; rules=&quot;groups&quot;&gt;&lt;colgroup span=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;col valign=&quot;top&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col valign=&quot;top&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt;Surgery&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt;Radiation&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Breast resection&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Radiation to the breast&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Lung resection&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Radiation to the lung&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Kidney resection&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Radiation to the kidney&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Colon resection&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Radiation to the colon&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Small intestine resection&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Radiation to the small intestine&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Extremity resection&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Radiation to the extremity&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Pancreas resection&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Radiation to the pancreas&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Liver resection&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Radiation to the liver&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Brain resection&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Radiation to the brain&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Larynx resection&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Radiation to the larynx&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Esophagus resection&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Radiation to the esophagus&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Lymph node resection&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Radiation to the lymph node&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Testicle resection&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Radiation to the testicle&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Ovary resection&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Radiation to the ovary&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Uterus resection&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Radiation to the uterus&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Bladder resection&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Radiation to the bladder&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Prostate resection&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Radiation to the prostate&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Breast removal&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Radiation to the neck&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Lung removal&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Radiation to the stomach&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Kidney removal&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Colon removal&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt;Systemic drug&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Small intestine removal&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Anthracyline (like adriamycin)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Extremity removal&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Vinca alkaloid (like vincristine)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Pancreas removal&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Tumor antibiotic (like bleomycin)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Liver removal&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Alkylating agent (like cyclophosphamide)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Larynx removal&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Cisplatin&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Esophagus removal&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Carboplatin&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Lymph node removal&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Oxaliplatin&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Testicle removal&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Microtubule inhibitor (like paclitaxel)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Ovary removal&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Immunotherapy (like pembroluzimab)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Uterus removal&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Monocloncal antibody (like blinatumomab)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Bladder removal&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Tetrahydrofolate reductase inhibitor (like pemetrexed)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Prostate removal&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Corticosteroids&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Stomach removal&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Antimetabolites (like mercaptopurine or cytarabine)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Thyroid removal&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Topoisomerase I inhibitor (like topotecan)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Topoisomerase II inhibitor (like etoposide)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt;Immune modulation&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Allogeneic transplant (CyTBI conditioning)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt;Genetic risks&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Allogeneic transplant (BuCy conditioning)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Multiple close family members with cancer&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Allogeneic transplant (BuFlu conditioning)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Inherited cancer gene mutation (eg, BRCA, Lynch) identified&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; CAR-T cell therapy&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Increased risk of treatment toxicity due to inherited gene mutation&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Multiple primary cancers of paired organs or different organs&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt;Comorbidity&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Active autoimmune disease&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt;Age (years)&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Traumatic brain injury&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; 0–10&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Congestive heart failure (CHF)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; 11–20&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; COPD or obstructive airway disease&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; 21–30&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Renal failure&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; 31–40&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Obesity&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; 40–65&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Tobacco use&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; 65+&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Substance abuse&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Developmental delay&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt;Socioeconomic status&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Hepatic impairment&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Low&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Hypertension&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Medium&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Psychiatric illness&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; High&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Neuropathy&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt; Stroke&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
</infon><offset>9076</offset><text>Surgery	Radiation	 	 Breast resection	 Radiation to the breast	 	 Lung resection	 Radiation to the lung	 	 Kidney resection	 Radiation to the kidney	 	 Colon resection	 Radiation to the colon	 	 Small intestine resection	 Radiation to the small intestine	 	 Extremity resection	 Radiation to the extremity	 	 Pancreas resection	 Radiation to the pancreas	 	 Liver resection	 Radiation to the liver	 	 Brain resection	 Radiation to the brain	 	 Larynx resection	 Radiation to the larynx	 	 Esophagus resection	 Radiation to the esophagus	 	 Lymph node resection	 Radiation to the lymph node	 	 Testicle resection	 Radiation to the testicle	 	 Ovary resection	 Radiation to the ovary	 	 Uterus resection	 Radiation to the uterus	 	 Bladder resection	 Radiation to the bladder	 	 Prostate resection	 Radiation to the prostate	 	 Breast removal	 Radiation to the neck	 	 Lung removal	 Radiation to the stomach	 	 Kidney removal		 	 Colon removal	Systemic drug	 	 Small intestine removal	 Anthracyline (like adriamycin)	 	 Extremity removal	 Vinca alkaloid (like vincristine)	 	 Pancreas removal	 Tumor antibiotic (like bleomycin)	 	 Liver removal	 Alkylating agent (like cyclophosphamide)	 	 Larynx removal	 Cisplatin	 	 Esophagus removal	 Carboplatin	 	 Lymph node removal	 Oxaliplatin	 	 Testicle removal	 Microtubule inhibitor (like paclitaxel)	 	 Ovary removal	 Immunotherapy (like pembroluzimab)	 	 Uterus removal	 Monocloncal antibody (like blinatumomab)	 	 Bladder removal	 Tetrahydrofolate reductase inhibitor (like pemetrexed)	 	 Prostate removal	 Corticosteroids	 	 Stomach removal	 Antimetabolites (like mercaptopurine or cytarabine)	 	 Thyroid removal	 Topoisomerase I inhibitor (like topotecan)	 		 Topoisomerase II inhibitor (like etoposide)	 	Immune modulation		 	 Allogeneic transplant (CyTBI conditioning)	Genetic risks	 	 Allogeneic transplant (BuCy conditioning)	 Multiple close family members with cancer	 	 Allogeneic transplant (BuFlu conditioning)	 Inherited cancer gene mutation (eg, BRCA, Lynch) identified	 	 CAR-T cell therapy	 Increased risk of treatment toxicity due to inherited gene mutation	 		 Multiple primary cancers of paired organs or different organs	 	Comorbidity		 	 Active autoimmune disease	Age (years)	 	 Traumatic brain injury	 0–10	 	 Congestive heart failure (CHF)	 11–20	 	 COPD or obstructive airway disease	 21–30	 	 Renal failure	 31–40	 	 Obesity	 40–65	 	 Tobacco use	 65+	 	 Substance abuse		 	 Developmental delay	Socioeconomic status	 	 Hepatic impairment	 Low	 	 Hypertension	 Medium	 	 Psychiatric illness	 High	 	 Neuropathy		 	 Stroke		 	</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>11880</offset><text>Since risk factors for each synthetic case are selected randomly, it is possible that clinically unlikely combinations may occur. We considered creating a list of such combinations and eliminating them from possible synthetic cases. However, for almost every unlikely combination, we were able to come up with an edge case where that combination might occur. Our solution was to instruct experts to make their best determination of risk based on the synthetic case even if the combination of treatments would be impossible. We included a disclaimer whenever an expert logged in that stated that synthetic cases were generated randomly, and that many combinations would not be realistic. We also informed experts that the goal of the process was to determine the contribution of each factor to overall risk independently.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>12701</offset><text> Figure  2 illustrates the sequence of matchups starting from new case creation. In Phase 1, a new case is matched against roundup [log2(n)] existing cases selected at random, where n is the total number of existing cases. In Phase 2, each case matched to the new case is matched to roundup [log2(n)] other existing cases, selected at random. In each matchup both cases involved are score-adjusted immediately, according to the Elo formula. After all Phase 2 matchups have occurred, the newly added case is considered an existing case. Another new case is added, and the process repeats. We designed this algorithm so that matchups would be well distributed among cases. Additionally, we hold one case the same in a series of matchups (the new case in Phase 1 and subsequently matched cases in Phase 2) so that both cases do not change from matchup to matchup. We believe this will assist the expert cognitively to improve the ease and speed of adjudicating cases.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">ooab090f2.jpg</infon><infon key="id">ooab090-F2</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>13668</offset><text>Matchup algorithm following the addition of a new synthetic case “9” with eight existing cases.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>13768</offset><text>Incentives</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>13779</offset><text>Participation of experts is incentivized with gift cards for the three experts who adjudicate the most cases. When logged into FILTER, each expert can see his/her own case count, and the counts for the top adjudicators, on the leaderboard. Each expert is required to affiliate with an institution at the time of account creation. This information is used to display an institution leaderboard to encourage friendly competition among groups of experts.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>14231</offset><text>Initial testing</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>14247</offset><text>We have done initial testing with a group of 13 Vanderbilt-Ingram Cancer Center oncologists. These oncologists have adjudicated 1174 matchups for 64 cases. In the next phase of FILTER implementation, we plan to invite members of the National Comprehensive Cancer Network (NCCN) Survivorship Guidelines Panel to participate as experts. These individuals will be authenticated through their institutions’ email addresses.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>14669</offset><text>DISCUSSION</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>14680</offset><text>We have created an application with a low barrier of entry to obtain expert adjudication of risk. Although we have designed FILTER for risk of clinical complications in cancer survivorship, the platform is generalizable to other medical use cases that require risk or severity scores generated through crowdsourcing. As a crowdsourcing platform, FILTER is unique and powerful because it does not use real patient data, it does not require much instruction for experts to use, and it does not prescribe a minimum input for the contribution of each expert to be considered complete.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>15261</offset><text>FILTER has several limitations. Its ranking algorithm is limited to adjudicating a single ordinal or continuous scale. This precludes FILTER’s use to identify individual, disease, or treatment phenotypes, a common use case for crowdsourcing in cancer research. As experts start to use FILTER, other limitations may emerge. Given our invitation to a wide range of physician participants, inter-rater disagreement may arise due to differences in opinion based on training or background. In addition, “bad actors” may enter purposefully wrong or random information. We believe that, as with other crowdsourcing platforms, these limitations can be overcome by having a large number of adjudicators so that the wisdom of the crowd is captured.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>16006</offset><text>After adjudication of a sufficient number of cases, our next step is to use the risk scores as outcomes in a regression model that will ascertain the contribution of each factor to survivorship risk. The end result will be an online tool that calculates survivorship risk based on the risk factors in Table  2. One limitation to determining how many experts we must engage is that there is no prior data to determine the extent to which experts will disagree on levels of risk. Part of what we will assess in pilot testing with the NCCN survivorship guidelines panel is expert agreement and risk score variability. We estimate that there will need to be at least 870 synthetic cases to obtain a reliable regression model. Assuming FILTER’s matchup algorithm effectively rates those 870 cases, we would need 77 266 matchups adjudicated. Therefore, we anticipate that there must be 772 experts adjudicating an average of 100 matchups each to get a reliable model.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>16972</offset><text>CONCLUSION</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>16983</offset><text>The FILTER crowdsourcing platform addresses a critical need for capturing clinical knowledge from experts when real-world data are scarce. Results from data obtained using FILTER will allow oncologists to better assess patient need for cancer survivorship follow-up care, thus allowing healthcare systems to allocate resources and services according to need.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ACK_FUND</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>17342</offset><text>FUNDING</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ACK_FUND</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>17350</offset><text>This work was supported by the National Cancer Institute grant numbers R01 CA240093-02S1 and P30 CA068485.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">AUTH_CONT</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>17457</offset><text>AUTHOR CONTRIBUTIONS</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">AUTH_CONT</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>17478</offset><text>TO conceived of the crowdsourcing platform and use of the Elo rating algorithm. TO, TP, and DF compiled the list of risk factors. LW, AC, and YL developed the platform. TK created the risk model and LB built the risk calculator. All authors contributed to the final manuscript.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">COMP_INT</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>17756</offset><text>CONFLICT OF INTEREST STATEMENT</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">COMP_INT</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>17787</offset><text>None declared.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">SUPPL</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>17802</offset><text>DATA AVAILABILITY </text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">SUPPL</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>17821</offset><text>No new data were generated or analyzed in support of this research. </text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">title</infon><offset>17890</offset><text>REFERENCES</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1029</infon><infon key="lpage">36</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">27371756</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Cancer Epidemiol Biomarkers Prev</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">25</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>17901</offset><text>Anticipating the ‘Silver Tsunami’: prevalence trajectories and comorbidity burden among older cancer survivors in the United States</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">3991</infon><infon key="lpage">4008</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">17577017</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Clin Oncol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">25</infon><infon key="year">2007</infon><offset>18037</offset><text>American Society of Clinical Oncology clinical evidence review on the ongoing care of adult cancer survivors: cardiac and pulmonary late effects</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">534</infon><infon key="lpage">44</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">26620816</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Cancer Surviv</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">10</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>18182</offset><text>Racial and ethnic disparities in cost-related medication non-adherence among cancer survivors</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1257</infon><infon key="lpage">64</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">25564986</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Cancer</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">121</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>18276</offset><text>Economic hardship of minority and non-minority cancer survivors 1 year after diagnosis: another long-term effect of cancer? Economic hardship in cancer survivors</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">5117</infon><infon key="lpage">24</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">17093273</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Clin Oncol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">24</infon><infon key="year">2006</infon><offset>18438</offset><text>Models for delivering survivorship care</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">e30–8</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">28049575</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Lancet Oncol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">18</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>18478</offset><text>Integrating primary care providers in the care of cancer survivors: gaps in evidence and future opportunities</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">14</infon><infon key="lpage">20</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">23257892</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Br J Cancer</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">108</infon><infon key="year">2013</infon><offset>18588</offset><text>Implementing improved post-treatment care for cancer survivors in England, with reflections from Australia, Canada and the USA</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">e187</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">29764795</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Med Internet Res</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">20</infon><infon key="year">2018</infon><offset>18715</offset><text>Mapping of crowdsourcing in health: systematic review</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">273</infon><infon key="lpage">80</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">29888085</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">AMIA Jt Summits Transl Sci Proc</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">2017</infon><infon key="year">2018</infon><offset>18769</offset><text>A crowdsourcing framework for medical data sets</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">103571</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">32961307</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Biomed Inform</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">110</infon><infon key="year">2020</infon><offset>18817</offset><text>User-centered design of a web-based crowdsourcing-integrated semantic text annotation tool for building a mental health knowledge base</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">800</infon><infon key="lpage">9</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Informetr</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">11</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>18952</offset><text>Who is the ‘Journal Grand Master’? A new ranking based on the Elo rating system</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2021</infon><offset>19036</offset></passage></document></collection>
