<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd">
<collection><source>PMC</source><date>20220616</date><key>pmc.key</key><document><id>8824391</id><infon key="license">CC BY</infon><passage><infon key="article-id_doi">10.1007/s40747-022-00661-5</infon><infon key="article-id_pmc">8824391</infon><infon key="article-id_pmid">35155081</infon><infon key="article-id_publisher-id">661</infon><infon key="fpage">2507</infon><infon key="issue">3</infon><infon key="kwd">Crowdsourcing Memory programming City logistics Variable neighborhood search</infon><infon key="license">Open AccessThis article is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License, which permits use, sharing, adaptation, distribution and reproduction in any medium or format, as long as you give appropriate credit to the original author(s) and the source, provide a link to the Creative Commons licence, and indicate if changes were made. The images or other third party material in this article are included in the article’s Creative Commons licence, unless indicated otherwise in a credit line to the material. If material is not included in the article’s Creative Commons licence and your intended use is not permitted by statutory regulation or exceeds the permitted use, you will need to obtain permission directly from the copyright holder. To view a copy of this licence, visit http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/.</infon><infon key="lpage">2525</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Cao;given-names:Lei</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Ye;given-names:Chun-ming</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Cheng;given-names:Ran</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Wang;given-names:Zhen-kun</infon><infon key="section_type">TITLE</infon><infon key="title">Keywords</infon><infon key="type">front</infon><infon key="volume">8</infon><infon key="year">2022</infon><offset>0</offset><text>Memory-based variable neighborhood search for green vehicle routing problem with passing-by drivers: a comprehensive perspective</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>129</offset><text>A business delivery model with professional vehicles as well as occasional passing-by vehicles is investigated in this paper. The drivers deliver parcels from the distribution center to customers and the passing-by driver can get a certain amount of compensation in return. To give a satisfactory solution from the perspective of platform owner, customers, professional drivers, occasional drivers, and authority, a multi-layer comprehensive model is proposed. To effectively solve the proposed model, we introduce an improved variable neighborhood search (VNS) with a memory-based restart mechanism. The new algorithm is evaluated on instances derived from Solomon’s benchmark and real-life beer delivery instances. Taguchi experiment is used to tune parameters in the proposed VNS, followed by component analysis and real-life experiments. Experimental results indicate that the proposed strategies are effective and the new delivery model in this paper has some advantages over traditional and single-delivery ones from the comprehensive perspectives of stakeholders in the crowdsourcing logistics system.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>1240</offset><text>Introduction</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>1253</offset><text>Urbanization and e-commerce are the keys to drive the strong demand for last-mile delivery and same-day delivery services. The last few decades have seen a great boom in city logistics. More geographic concentration and increasing online orders per person give rise to a great increase in the quantity of the goods to be handled. Especially, e-commerce plays an important role in the current prevention and control of COVID-19 because of its advantage of technology and business model. It is worth mentioning that the COVID-19 may further change the shopping habits of residents. More and more vehicles travelling on urban roads bring lots of negative impacts on health, environment, and safety.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>1949</offset><text>After the Paris Summit in 2015, more and more countries began to pay attention to carbon emissions. To achieve the goal of the Paris Agreement, many countries have taken some effective measures, such as legislation, fiscal incentives, carbon tax, and carbon trading, etc. In the field of logistics, environmental protection awareness of residents and new governmental legislation force companies to change their economic-oriented operating strategies.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>2401</offset><text>The rapid development and popularization of mobile and wireless communication technologies may enable achieving some more creative solutions for performing a low-cost and eco-friendly logistics delivery operation. Meanwhile, various new operation modes based on the sharing economy are emerging in many social aspects. Crowdsourcing logistics (CL) mode is produced in the context of the sharing economy, where the crowd can share their excess transport capacity and spare time. Alternative terms crowdshipping, crowdsourcing delivery, crowd logistics, cargo hitching, and collaborative logistics are also found in the realm of the CL. In this paper, we follow the broader definition by Rai et al. who described the CL as “information connectivity enabled marketplace concept that matches supply and demand for logistics services with an undefined and external crowd that has the free capacity with regards to time and/or space, participates voluntarily and is compensated accordingly”.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>3391</offset><text>Alnaggar et al. grouped the crowdsourcing logistics platform (CLP) into two main categories, e-retailers and couriers. As far as we know, for e-retailers, Amazon Flex and Walmart Spark Delivery are currently the only available crowdsourcing delivery platforms in North America. Jingdong Daojia is among the pilot crowdsourcing delivery platforms in China. In contrast, courier crowdsourcing delivery companies are quickly growing in number. Typical companies of this type include Postmates, Deliv, UberEats, Roadie, PiggyBee, DHL MyWays, UberFreight, and Renren Kuaidi.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>3961</offset><text>Crowdsourcing logistics promises social, economic, and environmental benefits covering a range of stakeholders. The platforms attempt to achieve a win–win situation by connecting enterprises with part-time individuals who have spare capacity and time. For crowdsourcing logistics enterprises, crowdsourcing delivery can help them reduce logistics costs, especially for last-mile delivery. It also helps satisfy the growing demand for e-commerce logistics, especially during certain e-commerce promotional periods (i.e., Black Friday in North America, Double Eleven in China). In addition to saving of fixed costs, these part-time drivers can work anytime and anywhere, adding flexibility to the delivery process. From an environmental perspective, crowdsourcing delivery may help alleviate the traffic congestion problem and reduce carbon emissions. From a social perspective, crowdsourcing logistics provides employment opportunities for people who have trouble getting a full-time job, or want to earn extra money. Nonetheless, crowdsourcing delivery has some pitfalls and uncertainties. Such service may not be as reliable as those provided by the traditional delivery mode. Crowd drivers are often idle and lack motivation of delivery when the compensation is low, which results in an unguaranteed number of occasional delivery personnels. Moreover, it is a difficult problem to balance compensation and convenience for crowd drivers when CLP owner assigns tasks to them. Thus, companies have to consider the uncertainty as well as the sustainability of the large pool of part-time labor force. Last but not least, some scholars claimed that many factors determine whether crowd logistics has a positive or negative impact on the environment. Thus, the positive environmental impact of crowd logistics is thus up for debate in crowdsourcing delivery.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>5818</offset><text>Generally, the main challenges of crowdsourcing delivery are: (1) The introduction of occasional drivers complicates the neighborhood structures, where moving may occur in professional routes or occasional routes. Furthermore, a new solution may also be obtained by operating customers who belong to different types of routes. (2) The formulated problem is similar to a vehicle routing problem with profit. The difference is that orders should be assigned reasonably to professional drivers or occasional drivers to guarantee service level instead of cost or benefit firstly. An efficient encoding method is needed to represent assignment and routing both in the professional routes and occasional routes. (3) There are several stakeholders in the crowdsourcing logistics system, the interests of which are conflicting. It is a tricky problem to balance these interests. (4) In terms of the tradeoff between exploration and exploitation for neighborhood-based search algorithms, the memory representation mechanism requires elaborate modifications to work efficiently.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>6887</offset><text>To meet the above challenges, a comprehensive model is proposed to consider the satisfaction of stakeholders in the crowdsourcing logistics system, and an enhanced variable neighborhood search algorithm is applied to solve that model.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>7122</offset><text>The remainder of this paper is organized as follows. Related works and contributions gives the literature review of vehicle routing problem with occasional (crowd) drivers and contributions of this paper. In Problem description and formulation, green vehicle routing problem with passing-by drivers and time windows is described in detail. Solution approach gives a specific designed variable neighborhood search algorithm for the model in this paper. Instance generation and Computational experiments are about instance generation, parameter tuning, and experiments. Conclusion ends this paper with conclusions and future work.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>7751</offset><text>Related works and contributions</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>7783</offset><text>As an emerging logistics operation mode, the crowdsourcing logistics is not only applied in the business community, but also increasingly favored by the academic community. Related academic research mainly focuses on matching, routing, driver scheduling, and compensation. In this section, we only review literature related to operations research (OR), especially the routing community, that explicitly addresses crowdsourcing delivery.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>8220</offset><text>Both Amazon and Walmart consider using crowdshipping, who employ crow already on the road to pick up goods from their stores and transport goods to their customers. The concept of crowdshipping proposed by Walmart has spawned a series of quantitative studies and mathematical models. In a study done by Archetti et al., a static deterministic model was introduced called the vehicle routing problem with occasional drivers (VRPOD). In this variant of the vehicle routing problem (VRP), the company owns a fleet of professional vehicles that can only perform closed routes, and a set of static and deterministic occasional drivers (ODs) that can only visit one customer before they head to their intended destination without returning to the depot. Since then, other variants of the VRPOD have been explored.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>9028</offset><text>Based on the research of Archetti et al., Macrina et al. introduced time windows for both customers and ODs and allowed multiple deliveries in their mathematical model. The work of Macrina et al. was recently extended by Macrina et al., who introduced the transshipment nodes in the service network. Dahle et al. extended the model proposed in to a version of pickup and delivery routing problem with time windows and ODs. is among few studies about green vehicle routing problems with ODs, focusing on the environmental impacts of the three types of vehicles.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>9589</offset><text>All the studies above model crowdsourcing logistics as a static system, neglecting the evolution and uncertainty of information. Recently, several researchers have started to study crowdsourcing logistics in the context of stochastic or uncertain parameters. Dahle et al. considered the availability of ODs as an uncertain parameter and assumed stochastic information of ODs’ appearance was known in advance. By comparing with deterministic model, they highlighted that the use of a stochastic formulation might lead to more profitable solutions in terms of saving costs. Dayarian and Savelsbergh considered a VRPOD variant with dynamic customers requests. They developed and compared two rolling horizon dispatching methods. Considering ODs may reject assignments, Gdowska et al. gave each pair (OD-request) a random probability to study dynamic VRPOD. Their results pointed out the need of defining a dynamic compensation scheme for ODs. More recently, Archetti et al. investigated a vehicle routing problem in which customer requests were either known in advance, or arrive online during the distribution process.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>10708</offset><text>Most studies about VRPOD highlight the advantage of using crow in terms of reduction of operational costs. A few aforementioned studies have been devoted to a comprehensive consideration of economic cost, stakeholders’ satisfaction, and external cost (e.g., environmental cost) in crowdsourcing model. Actually, high satisfaction of stakeholders is the guarantee for the reliable and orderly operation of the novel logistics system. At least six stakeholders are directly related to crowdsourcing logistics: senders who need the service of shipments, customers who receive the goods, platform providers who coordinate supply and demand, logistics service providers (LSPs) who provide traditional transport services, the crowd, and authority (or society). Rai et al. studied stakeholders in crowdsourcing logistics system quantificationally, indicating that usage of current platform results in higher external transport costs and thus a higher environmental impact, when compared to traditional goods delivery mode.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>11726</offset><text>In addition to OR-based combinatorial optimization theories, there are many other theories that can support a more eco-friendly and satisfactory crowd logistics system design, such as green economy, consumer utility theory, and equity theory. For the sake of concise and clear literature review structure, the related theory is applied in Problem description and formulation.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>12102</offset><text>The variable neighborhood search algorithm (VNS) is an effective algorithm for solving combinatorial optimization problems. Various strategies were proposed to improve performance of classic VNS. Stenger et al. proposed an adaptive variable neighborhood search algorithm. The algorithm selected a shaking solution from a solution pool, and applied the selection method of removal and insertion operators in the adaptive large neighborhood search algorithm. Kalayci used the ant colony algorithm to restart VNS for the sake of obtaining a high-quality initial solution. Based on historical search success rate, Li et al. proposed a novel method to select neighborhood structure. It is worth mentioning that reinforcement learning is another research line of neighborhood structure selection, and Silva et al. are among the rare studies related to this methodology. To accelerate the speed of local search phase, Thevenin applied a quick evaluation method of solution. Besides, memory mechanism is usually used to enhance VNS (e.g., Pacheco et al. and Li et al.).</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">Tab1.xml</infon><infon key="id">Tab1</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_caption</infon><offset>13164</offset><text>Concerns of Stakeholders</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">Tab1.xml</infon><infon key="id">Tab1</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table</infon><infon key="xml">&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;table frame=&quot;hsides&quot; rules=&quot;groups&quot;&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Stakeholder&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Concerns(s)&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;4&quot;&gt;CLP owner&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Operation cost&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Service level&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Sufficient supply of ODs&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Rate of customer covered&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Occasional driver&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Compensation&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Professional driver&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Equality&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Customer&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Delivery in time window&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Authority&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Carbon emission&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
</infon><offset>13189</offset><text>Stakeholder	Concerns(s)	 	CLP owner	Operation cost	 	Service level	 	Sufficient supply of ODs	 	Rate of customer covered	 	Occasional driver	Compensation	 	Professional driver	Equality	 	Customer	Delivery in time window	 	Authority	Carbon emission	 	</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>13440</offset><text>To sum up, the main scientific contributions of this work are: (1) To improve the quality and reliability of service of the whole crowd logistics system from a comprehensive perspective of stakeholders. Concerns of different stakeholders in this paper are summarized in Table 1. (2) To propose a variant of VRPOD which allows the passing-by drivers to deliver parcels and multi-delivery. Most literature assumes that crowdsourcing drivers are in-store customers, but this idea was hard to implement in practice. Passing-by drivers are seen as crowd delivery drivers in this work. Actually, in-store customers are one kind of passing-by drivers. To increase willingness to act of ODs, we allow them to deliver more than one parcel, which is different from. (3) To propose a memory-based variable neighborhood search algorithm. Currently, there are a few meta-heuristic algorithms proposed for solving VRPOD, such as. This work enhances the basic variable neighborhood search by introducing memory into restart phase, which gives one certain direction for developing neighborhood-based algorithms.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>14536</offset><text>Problem description and formulation</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>14572</offset><text>It is worth mentioning that the research background of this paper is urban commodity transportation, and the only sender has the ownership of CLP. To reduce operating costs and improve delivery efficiency, a CLP owner uses its own professional drivers and occasional drivers to complete the delivery of orders. An occasional driver can be seen as a taxi or truck driver passing by the distribution center. Both the professional drivers and the occasional drivers pick up the goods from the distribution center and deliver them to the customers. The professional driver needs to return to the distribution center, while the occasional driver goes directly to his or her destination after completing the delivery task. At the same time, occasional drivers can get corresponding compensation according to the task attributes. The scheduling plan needs to meet the constraints of service level, occasional driver action, vehicle capacity, while considering customer covered rate, usage rate and equity of professional routes, and operating cost which includes fuel cost, overtime wage, and carbon emission cost. The problem in this paper is named as the green vehicle routing problem with partial crowdsourcing and participants’ satisfaction (GVRP-PCPS). To clarify the scope of application of this study, the following specific assumptions are made:</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>15921</offset><text>Assumption 1</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>15934</offset><text>: occasional drivers can participate in one or more deliveries if the compensation meets their expectations;</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>16043</offset><text>Assumption 2</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>16056</offset><text>: where the en-route occasional driver receives pushed notifications and his or her destination is known by the CLP owner;</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>16179</offset><text>Assumption 3</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>16192</offset><text>: compensation of crowd delivery task is proportional to the sum of distance between distribution center and customer location in the occasional driver route;</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>16351</offset><text>Assumption 4</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>16364</offset><text>: all vehicles in the crowdsourcing logistics system are homogeneous, which means that they have the same capacity and velocity;</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>16493</offset><text>Assumption 5</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>16506</offset><text>: the loaded quantity of goods at the distribution center is equal to the total of customer demands in each route.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>16621</offset><text>In Section “Notation and Symbol”, notations for the mathematical model are given. The interests of stakeholders are analyzed in Subsection “Stakeholders’ satisfaction and optimized objectives”, which is applied to formalize the objectives in Subsection “Mathematical model for GVRP-PCPS”.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">Tab2.xml</infon><infon key="id">Tab2</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_caption</infon><offset>16926</offset><text>Set and its description</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">Tab2.xml</infon><infon key="id">Tab2</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table</infon><infon key="xml">&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;table xmlns:mml=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML&quot; xmlns:xlink=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink&quot; frame=&quot;hsides&quot; rules=&quot;groups&quot;&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Symbol&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;
&lt;italic&gt;C&lt;/italic&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Set of customers&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;
&lt;italic&gt;A&lt;/italic&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Set of all arcs&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;
&lt;italic&gt;N&lt;/italic&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Set of all nodes&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;
&lt;italic&gt;S&lt;/italic&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Set of occasional driver’ origins&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;
&lt;italic&gt;V&lt;/italic&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Set of occasional drivers’ destinations&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;
&lt;italic&gt;K&lt;/italic&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Set of occasional vehicles&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;
&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq1&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M1&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$P_u$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M2&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;P&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;u&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq1.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Set of used professional vehicles&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;
&lt;italic&gt;P&lt;/italic&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Set of professional vehicles&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
</infon><offset>16950</offset><text>Symbol	Description	 	C	Set of customers	 	A	Set of all arcs	 	N	Set of all nodes	 	S	Set of occasional driver’ origins	 	V	Set of occasional drivers’ destinations	 	K	Set of occasional vehicles	 		Set of used professional vehicles	 	P	Set of professional vehicles	 	</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>17221</offset><text>Notation and symbol</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">Tab3.xml</infon><infon key="id">Tab3</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_caption</infon><offset>17241</offset><text>Constant and its description</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">Tab3.xml</infon><infon key="id">Tab3</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table</infon><infon key="xml">&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;table xmlns:mml=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML&quot; xmlns:xlink=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink&quot; frame=&quot;hsides&quot; rules=&quot;groups&quot;&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Symbol&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;
&lt;italic&gt;Q&lt;/italic&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Capacity of vehicle&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;
&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq2&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M3&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$\alpha $$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M4&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;α&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq2.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;A large number in mathematic model&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;
&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq3&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M5&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$R^S$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M6&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:msup&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;S&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:msup&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq3.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Minimal action cost&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;
&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq4&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M7&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$R^V$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M8&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:msup&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;V&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:msup&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq4.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Variable cost coefficient&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;
&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq5&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M9&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$\lambda $$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M10&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;λ&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq5.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Compensation coefficient&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;
&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq6&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M11&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$w_1$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M12&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;w&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;1&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq6.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Fuel price&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;
&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq7&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M13&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$w_2$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M14&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;w&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;2&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq7.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Carbon tax price&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;
&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq8&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M15&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$w_3$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M16&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;w&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;3&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq8.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Overtime wage per unit time&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;
&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq9&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M17&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$E_f$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M18&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;E&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;f&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq9.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Carbon emission conversion factor&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;
&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq10&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M19&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$\mu _0$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M20&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;μ&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;0&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq10.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Fuel consumption rate of empty vehicle&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;
&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq11&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M21&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$\mu ^{\text {*}}$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M22&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:msup&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;μ&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mtext&gt;*&lt;/mml:mtext&gt;&lt;/mml:msup&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq11.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Maximum fuel consumption rate&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;
&lt;italic&gt;Sal&lt;/italic&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Basic salary per day of professional drivers&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;BT&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Basic work time per day&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;DT&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Maximum work time per day&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;SL&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Designed service level of CLP&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
</infon><offset>17270</offset><text>Symbol	Description	 	Q	Capacity of vehicle	 		A large number in mathematic model	 		Minimal action cost	 		Variable cost coefficient	 		Compensation coefficient	 		Fuel price	 		Carbon tax price	 		Overtime wage per unit time	 		Carbon emission conversion factor	 		Fuel consumption rate of empty vehicle	 		Maximum fuel consumption rate	 	Sal	Basic salary per day of professional drivers	 	BT	Basic work time per day	 	DT	Maximum work time per day	 	SL	Designed service level of CLP	 	</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">Tab4.xml</infon><infon key="id">Tab4</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_caption</infon><offset>17757</offset><text>Variable and its description</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">Tab4.xml</infon><infon key="id">Tab4</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table</infon><infon key="xml">&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;table xmlns:mml=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML&quot; xmlns:xlink=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink&quot; frame=&quot;hsides&quot; rules=&quot;groups&quot;&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Symbol&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq45&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M89&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$c_{ij}$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M90&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;c&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi mathvariant=&quot;italic&quot;&gt;ij&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq45.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Travel cost of arc &lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq46&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M91&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$\left( i,j \right) $$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M92&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mfenced close=&quot;)&quot; open=&quot;(&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;,&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;j&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mfenced&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq46.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq47&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M93&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$t_{ij}$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M94&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;t&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi mathvariant=&quot;italic&quot;&gt;ij&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq47.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Travel time of arc &lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq48&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M95&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$\left( i,j \right) $$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M96&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mfenced close=&quot;)&quot; open=&quot;(&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;,&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;j&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mfenced&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq48.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq49&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M97&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$d_{ij}$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M98&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;d&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi mathvariant=&quot;italic&quot;&gt;ij&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq49.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Distance of arc &lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq50&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M99&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$\left( i,j \right) $$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M100&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mfenced close=&quot;)&quot; open=&quot;(&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;,&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;j&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mfenced&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq50.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq51&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M101&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$[e_i,l_i]$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M102&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mo stretchy=&quot;false&quot;&gt;[&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;,&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;l&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mo stretchy=&quot;false&quot;&gt;]&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq51.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Time window of customer &lt;italic&gt;i&lt;/italic&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq52&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M103&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$[EST_i,LST_i]$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M104&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mo stretchy=&quot;false&quot;&gt;[&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;E&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;S&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;T&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;,&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;L&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;S&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;T&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mo stretchy=&quot;false&quot;&gt;]&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq52.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Acceptable time window of customer &lt;italic&gt;i&lt;/italic&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq53&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M105&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$q_i$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M106&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;q&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq53.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Demand of customer &lt;italic&gt;i&lt;/italic&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq54&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M107&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$ser_i$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M108&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq54.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Service time of customer &lt;italic&gt;i&lt;/italic&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq55&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M109&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$\gamma _i$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M110&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;γ&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq55.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Sensitivity coefficients of customer &lt;italic&gt;i&lt;/italic&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq56&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M111&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$x_{ij}$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M112&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;x&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi mathvariant=&quot;italic&quot;&gt;ij&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq56.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;A binary variable equal to 1 if and only if arc &lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq57&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M113&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$(i,j) \in A$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M114&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mo stretchy=&quot;false&quot;&gt;(&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;,&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;j&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo stretchy=&quot;false&quot;&gt;)&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;∈&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;A&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq57.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt; is traversed by a professional vehicle&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq58&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M115&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$r_{ij}^{k}$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M116&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:msubsup&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi mathvariant=&quot;italic&quot;&gt;ij&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;k&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:msubsup&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq58.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;A binary variable indicating if arc (&lt;italic&gt;i&lt;/italic&gt;, &lt;italic&gt;j&lt;/italic&gt;) is traversed by a occasional vehicle &lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq59&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M117&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$k\in K$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M118&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;k&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;∈&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;K&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq59.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq60&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M119&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$y_i$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M120&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;y&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq60.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Decision variable specify the available capacity of he professional vehicle after visiting customer &lt;italic&gt;i&lt;/italic&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq61&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M121&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$y_{ij}$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M122&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;y&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi mathvariant=&quot;italic&quot;&gt;ij&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq61.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Mass of goods transported by professional vehicle in arc (&lt;italic&gt;i&lt;/italic&gt;, &lt;italic&gt;j&lt;/italic&gt;)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq62&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M123&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$a_{i}^{k}$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M124&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:msubsup&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;a&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;k&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:msubsup&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq62.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Available capacity of the vehicle associated with &lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq63&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M125&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$k\in K$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M126&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;k&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;∈&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;K&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq63.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt; after visiting customer &lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq64&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M127&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$i \in C$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M128&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;∈&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;C&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq64.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq65&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M129&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$a_{ij}^{k}$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M130&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:msubsup&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;a&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi mathvariant=&quot;italic&quot;&gt;ij&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;k&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:msubsup&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq65.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Mass of parcels transported by occasional vehicle &lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq66&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M131&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$k \in K$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M132&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;k&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;∈&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;K&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq66.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt; in arc (&lt;italic&gt;i&lt;/italic&gt;, &lt;italic&gt;j&lt;/italic&gt;)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq67&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M133&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$arr_{i}$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M134&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;a&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq67.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Arrival time of a professional vehicle at customer &lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq68&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M135&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$i \in C$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M136&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;∈&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;C&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq68.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq69&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M137&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$f_{i}^{k}$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M138&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:msubsup&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;f&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;k&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:msubsup&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq69.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Arrival time of &lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq70&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M139&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$k\in K$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M140&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;k&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;∈&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;K&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq70.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt; at customer &lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq71&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M141&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$i \in C$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M142&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;∈&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;C&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq71.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq72&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M143&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$\rho _{ij}$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M144&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;ρ&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi mathvariant=&quot;italic&quot;&gt;ij&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq72.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Fuel consumption rate of arc (&lt;italic&gt;i&lt;/italic&gt;, &lt;italic&gt;j&lt;/italic&gt;)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq73&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M145&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$\delta _k$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M146&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;δ&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;k&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq73.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Binary decision variable indicating if occasional &lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq74&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M147&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$k\in K $$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M148&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;k&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;∈&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;K&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq74.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt; is employed&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq75&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M149&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$p_{ik}$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M150&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;p&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi mathvariant=&quot;italic&quot;&gt;ik&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq75.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Compensation of &lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq76&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M151&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$k \in K$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M152&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;k&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;∈&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;K&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq76.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt; if customer is served by &lt;italic&gt;k&lt;/italic&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq77&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M153&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$\beta _{ik}$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M154&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;β&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi mathvariant=&quot;italic&quot;&gt;ik&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq77.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Binary decision variable indicating if customer &lt;italic&gt;i&lt;/italic&gt; is served by &lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq78&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M155&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$k\in K$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M156&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;k&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;∈&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;K&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq78.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq79&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M157&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$C_S$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M158&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;C&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;S&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq79.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Set of the served customers&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq80&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M159&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$FAI_p$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M160&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;F&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;A&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;I&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;p&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq80.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Fairness coefficient of professional driver &lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq81&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M161&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$p\in P$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M162&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;p&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;∈&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;P&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq81.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq82&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M163&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$overload_{k}$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M164&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;o&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;v&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;l&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;o&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;a&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;d&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;k&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq82.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq83&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M165&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$overload_{k}$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M166&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;o&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;v&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;l&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;o&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;a&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;d&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;k&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq83.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt; means the overload of &lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq84&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M167&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$k\in P\cup K$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M168&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;k&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;∈&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;P&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;∪&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;K&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq84.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq85&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M169&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$W{{T}_{k}}$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M170&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;W&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;T&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;k&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq85.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Duration of &lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq86&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M171&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$k\in P\cup K$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M172&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;k&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;∈&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;P&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;∪&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;K&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq86.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
</infon><offset>17786</offset><text>Symbol	Description	 		Travel cost of arc 	 		Travel time of arc 	 		Distance of arc 	 		Time window of customer i	 		Acceptable time window of customer i	 		Demand of customer i	 		Service time of customer i	 		Sensitivity coefficients of customer i	 		A binary variable equal to 1 if and only if arc  is traversed by a professional vehicle	 		A binary variable indicating if arc (i, j) is traversed by a occasional vehicle 	 		Decision variable specify the available capacity of he professional vehicle after visiting customer i	 		Mass of goods transported by professional vehicle in arc (i, j)	 		Available capacity of the vehicle associated with  after visiting customer 	 		Mass of parcels transported by occasional vehicle  in arc (i, j)	 		Arrival time of a professional vehicle at customer 	 		Arrival time of  at customer 	 		Fuel consumption rate of arc (i, j)	 		Binary decision variable indicating if occasional  is employed	 		Compensation of  if customer is served by k	 		Binary decision variable indicating if customer i is served by 	 		Set of the served customers	 		Fairness coefficient of professional driver 	 		 means the overload of 	 		Duration of 	 	</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>18966</offset><text>GVRP-PCPS is modeled on a complete graph , where N is the set of nodes and A is the set of arcs. Let C be the set of customers. Let P be the set of available professional vehicles. Let K be the set of occasional vehicles in the crowdsourcing logistics system. Let  the set of locations where ODs receive crowd orders, and  the set of ODs’ destinations. We define the node set as . 0 represents the depot (distribution center) where the professional drivers leave and return. Each arc  has a cost , a travel time , and a distance  between node i and node j. Note that , , and  satisfy the triangle inequality. Each node  has a time window , and each customer  has a demand  and service time . Q is the capacity of the vehicles. Let  be a binary variable equal to 1 if and only if a professional vehicle traverses arc (i, j), and  a binary variable equal to 1 if and only if  traverses arc (i, j). For each node , let  be the available capacity of a professional vehicle when it leaves from the node, and  the mass of parcels transported by professional vehicle in arc (i, j). Let  be the available capacity of the vehicle associated with  after visiting customer , and  the mass of parcels transported by occasional vehicle  in arc (i, j). For each node , let  be the arrival time of a professional vehicle at customer . Let  indicate the arrival time of vehicle  at customer . All parameters and variables used in Section 3 are shown in Tables 2, 3, 4.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>20425</offset><text>Stakeholders’ satisfaction and optimized objectives</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>20479</offset><text>The satisfaction of CLP owner, customer, occasional driver (OD), and professional driver (PD) and authority is included in our model. The CLP owner who requires goods to be transported wants to reduce operation cost and deliver goods on time through partial crowd delivery mode, while authorities are likely to support solutions enhancing the economic vitality of the city, or solutions with environmental benefits such as a decrease in congestion. Stakeholders’ satisfaction in CLP can be divided into service type, cost type, and balance type. Covered customer rate and service level are significant factors for sustainability of CLP. To describe optimized objectives easily in the following section, we define uncovered customer rate (UCR):where  means the set of served customers.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>21266</offset><text>Service level. In the general vehicle routing problem with time windows, the time of obtaining service for a certain customer is in the determined range , which means that the service level is good(1), otherwise it is bad (0). In real-life transportation problems, however, the time windows may be violated out of several practical considerations. A little bit deviation from the specified time window is acceptable to customers. We name the wider time window  as an acceptable time window of customer i. Thus, the service level cannot be described by two states. Fuzzy set theory is a strong tool to describe personal subjective feelings, which was applied in some routing problems with time window constraint.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>21978</offset><text>If the time when the professional or occasional driver arrives in the location of customer i is earlier than the claimed earliest service time , he or she should wait at customer i until the time window is open. Therefore, arriving early has almost no effect on customer satisfaction. Considering the difference in sensitivity of customers to tardiness, we distinguish customers by sensitivity coefficients . The customer service level associated with time window is characterized by fuzzy membership functions based on fuzzy set theory.  can be replaced by  in Formula 2 to describe the service level of the occasional driverOperating cost includes fuel cost of PD routes TFC, carbon emission cost TFEC, compensation of ODs ODS, and overtime wage of PD routes . According to, the fuel consumption per unit distance has a linear relationship with the load. We use this method to calculate fuel consumption rate in TFC and TCEC, as is shown in Formula 3where  means fuel consumption rate of arc (i, j);  means fuel consumption rate of empty vehicle;  means fuel consumption rate of vehicle with full capacity.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>23090</offset><text>Fuel cost of PDs routes which is related to arcs traversed, load in each traversed arc, and fuel pricewhere  means the fuel price.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>23221</offset><text>Carbon emission cost which includes direct carbon emission cost incurred by PD vehicle(s) and incremental carbon emission cost incurred by OD vehicle(s) because of detour(s)where  means carbon emission tax price;  means carbon emission conversion factor;  means binary decision variable indicating if occasional  is chosen;  means fuel consumption rate of vehicle  in arc (i, j).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>23602</offset><text>Compensation of ODs iswhere  means the compensation when vehicle  is assigned to customer ;  means binary decision variable indicating if customer i is served by .  means compensation coefficient.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>23799</offset><text>Overtime wage of PDs isWe use the inequality 8 to describe the phenomenon when occasional drivers make decisionwhere  means to minimal action cost;  means to variable cost coefficient;  means the compensation after occasional vehicle  deliver the goods of customer . In this paper, we assume that occasional drivers are homogeneous.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>24133</offset><text>The left side of the inequality 8 is the CLP’s compensation function. The right side of the inequality is participation threshold function of occasional driver. The first-to-second items of participation threshold function are minimal action cost and variable action cost.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>24409</offset><text>For the sake of reducing turnover rate, it is necessary to ensure that the scheduling plan is attractive to professional drivers. Equity is measured by comparing the ratio of contributions (or costs) and benefits (or rewards) for each person. We define  as the fairness coefficient of professional driver p. By comparing  with other drivers, each professional driver  has a feeling of unfairness .where Sal means the basic salary per day;  means to overtime wage per unit time;  is the duration of ; BT is the basic worktime per day.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>24943</offset><text>Thus, unfairness for PDs’ workload iswhere  means the set of used professional vehicles.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>25034</offset><text>Self-own vehicles are asset-heavy, and it is necessary to improve the usage rate of professional vehicles. Usage rate UR is used to describe the status of PDs in the schedule planOccasional drivers’ participation behavior is mainly stimulated by external factors such as money and material. If the compensation offered by company is higher than stimulation threshold, occasional driver is willing to participate in the delivery task. However, higher compensation means more cost for company, which is against the original intention of using crowd. Naturally, when the compensation is slightly larger than the stimulation threshold of occasional driver, it is more economical for the enterprise.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>25731</offset><text>Mathematical model for GVRP-PCPS</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>25764</offset><text>maximize the number of customers served by PDs and ODs.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>25820</offset><text>maximize the usage rate of professional vehicles.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>25870</offset><text>minimize the unfairness of PD routes.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>25908</offset><text>minimize the cost of operating cost.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">40747_2022_661_Fig1_HTML.jpg</infon><infon key="id">Fig1</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>25945</offset><text>Encoding and decoding process</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>25975</offset><text>Multi-objective optimization techniques such as lexicographic goal programming (LGP) are more appropriate for GVRP-PCPS solving, because CLP owner has obvious preference when he or she makes decision. The goals set in order of importance can be defined as follows: Satisfaction of customers served must be more than the service level designed by CLP owner in advance, which is added to constraints. In addition, OD action constraint must be met in the whole optimization process. According to descriptions above, the objective of GVRP-PCPS can be formulated as follows:Besides Formula 8, other constraints of GVRP-PCPS are formulated as follows. Formula 16–Formula 24 are linked to the professional vehicles. Formula 25–Formula 35 are linked to the occasional vehicles. Formula 37–Formula 40 are related to decision variablesFormulas 16 and 17 are the flow constraints of professional vehicles. Formula 18 guarantees the fulfillment of demand at customer vertices. Formula 19 restricts the initial load level to the maximum capacity of a vehicle. Formulas 20 and 23 allow to determine the arrival time at node j. Formula 24 imposes a maximum number of available professional vehicles. Formulas 25 and 26 are the flow constraints of ODs’ routes. Formula 27 guarantees a limit on the number of available ODs. Formula 28 guarantees the number of departs from original node of occasional vehicle k. Formula 29 guarantees the fulfillment of demand at customer vertices in OD routes. Formula 30 restricts the initial load level to the maximum capacity of vehicle . Formulas 31–35 allow to determine the arrival time. Formula 36 guarantees that each customer is visited at most once, by either a professional vehicle or an occasional vehicle. Formulas 37–40 are ranges of decision variables.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>27788</offset><text>Solution approach</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>27806</offset><text>Variable neighborhood search (VNS)</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>27841</offset><text>Variable neighborhood search (VNS) was first proposed by Mladenovic and Hansen to solve combinatorial and global optimization problems. VNS is derived from the idea of systematically changing neighborhoods during the search. In the classical implementation of VNS algorithm (Algorithm 1), four key components should be specified: (i) method to construct an initial solution; (ii) shaking method based on several neighborhood structures, which helps to slightly diversify the starting point of local search; (iii) local search, which improves the solution quickly, where meta-heuristic local search algorithm (i.e., SA, TS) and defined neighborhood operator can be used; and (iv) acceptance criterion that determines the termination of the search.  and  in Algorithm 1 are the neighborhood structure in shaking phase and local search, respectively.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>28691</offset><text>However, there are some limitations in basic VNS: (i) the shaking solution generated randomly may lead to cycling phenomenon which means that the shaking solution may not be in a promising area where better solution can be found; (ii) information in elite solutions which is created in search process cannot be exploited; (iii) local search based on the size of neighborhood may not be a good way to in terms of efficiency.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>29115</offset><text>In this paper, we propose an adapted version of VNS, inspired by the references above about VNS with learning and memory, to overcome the limitations of classic VNS. We name the adapted version of VNS in this paper as MVNS (memory-based variable neighborhood search).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>29383</offset><text>Memory-based variable neighborhood search</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>29425</offset><text>Solution representation and neighborhood structures</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>29477</offset><text>In MVNS, variable-size matrix is used to represent the solution of GVRP-PCPS (Fig. 1). The first line of matrix represents type (PD means professional driver, while OD means occasional driver) of routes as well as their numbers, and the other lines of matrix represents IDs of customers. Each column represents a feasible route, and customer in higher tier has higher priority to receive service. As is shown at the right side of decoding schematic diagram of Fig. 1, the decoded solution is composed of two professional routes and two occasional routes. For PDs, their origin and destination are both depot. For ODs, each of them has their own origin and destination.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>30146</offset><text>In this paper, we use four operators to create neighborhood solutions, namely, Relocate, Swap, 2-OPT, and CrossExchange. Operators used in the following section are summarized in Table 5. Except for 2-Opt and CrossExchange, both Swap and Relocate have two versions which are used in single route and pair of routes, respectively.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">Tab5.xml</infon><infon key="id">Tab5</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_caption</infon><offset>30476</offset><text>Neighborhood operator used in LVNS</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">Tab5.xml</infon><infon key="id">Tab5</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table</infon><infon key="xml">&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;table xmlns:mml=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML&quot; xmlns:xlink=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink&quot; frame=&quot;hsides&quot; rules=&quot;groups&quot;&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Operator&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Pair of routes&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Single route&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Relocate&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq150&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M343&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$\surd $$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M344&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;√&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq150.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq151&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M345&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$\surd $$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M346&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;√&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq151.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Swap&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq152&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M347&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$\surd $$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M348&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;√&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq152.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq153&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M349&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$\surd $$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M350&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;√&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq153.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;2-Opt&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq154&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M351&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$\surd $$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M352&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;√&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq154.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;CrossExchange&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq155&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M353&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$\surd $$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M354&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;√&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq155.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;/&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
</infon><offset>30511</offset><text>Operator	Pair of routes	Single route	 	Relocate			 	Swap			 	2-Opt			 	CrossExchange			 	</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>30601</offset><text>The Relocate operator moves a customer from its position in one route to another position in either the same or a different route. We name the Relocate operator in single route as Inner-relocate, and the Relocate operator between two routes as Outer-relocate. Take Outer-relocate for instance in Fig. 2, the edges , , and  are replaced by , (j, i) and , i.e., customer i from the origin route is placed after customer j in the destination route.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">40747_2022_661_Fig2_HTML.jpg</infon><infon key="id">Fig2</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>31048</offset><text>Relocate</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">40747_2022_661_Fig3_HTML.jpg</infon><infon key="id">Fig3</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>31057</offset><text>Swap</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>31062</offset><text>The Swap operator swaps two customers in single route or different routes. We name the Swap operator in single route as Inner-swap, and the Swap operator between two routes as Outer-swap. Take Outer-swap for instance in Fig. 3, the edges , , , and  are replaced by , , , and , i.e., two customers from different routes are simultaneously placed into the other routes.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">40747_2022_661_Fig4_HTML.jpg</infon><infon key="id">Fig4</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>31430</offset><text>2-OPT</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>31436</offset><text>2-Opt tries to improve the tour using two edges to replace the other two edges. As is shown in Fig. 4, the edges  and  are replaced by edges (i, j) and , thus reversing the direction of customers between  and j.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">40747_2022_661_Fig5_HTML.jpg</infon><infon key="id">Fig5</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>31649</offset><text>CrossExchange</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>31663</offset><text>CrossExchange tries to exchange two blocks in pair of routes to improve solution. Different from Outer-swap, the block in CrossExchange have a variable size. As is shown in Fig. 5, the block (j, ..., g) is created by breaking edge  and , while the block (i, ..., e) is created by breaking edge and . Two updated tours are created by moving block in origin tour into the broken position of the other tour.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>32072</offset><text>In the whole paper, operators used in shaking phase are Outer-relocate, 2-Opt, and CrossExchange, while those in local search phase are Inner-relocate, Inner-swap, Outer-relocate, and Outer-swap.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>32268</offset><text>Initialize solution</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>32288</offset><text>The put forward insertion heuristic (PFIH) for inserting customers into a route for the VRPTW was introduced by Solomon (1987). It is an efficient method for computing the cost of inserting a new customer into the current route. The feasibility of inserting a customer into a route is checked by inserting the customer between all the nodes in the current route and then select the edge that has the lowest additional insertion cost. The feasibility check examines all the constraints including time windows and load capacity. Only feasible insertion will be accepted. When the current route is full without accepting any new customer, PFIH will start a new route and repeat the procedure until all the customers are routed. PFIH serves the role of constructing route configuration for VRPTW, which is an efficient method to obtain feasible solutions. Detailed information of PFIH is available in Solomon’s paper (1987). In this paper, seed customer is chosen according to value calculated by Formula 41. The candidate customer with least value means seed customer. And then, unrouted customers are inserted at the best feasible position of current route until the constraints are not met for all the unrouted customerswhere  means the distance between depot and candidate customer c;  means earliest service time of customer c;  means the polar angle between customer c and last customer in the last route; , , and  mean weights, respectively.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>33735</offset><text>First, we use PFIH to create a set of candidate routes which are assigned to professional drivers. Because of the limited size of professional vehicles, additional routes are removed from set of candidate routes to make sure that its size is not larger than its limitation if necessary. Routes with lower load rate have lower priority to be kept in PD route set. If there are unrouted customers left, they can be assigned to feasible occasional routes. To give a concise description, we define several notations. Let  the set of customers who have not been assigned to any vehicle. Let  be the set of occasional routes. OD routes are created according to Algorithm 2.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>34404</offset><text>Memory-based restart</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>34425</offset><text>The essence of the memory restart algorithm is the repetition and incomplete utilization of experience, which precisely provides ideas for the design of combinatorial optimization algorithms. Taillard et al. first proposed a unified framework for adaptive memory programming. Subsequently, many scholars applied the idea of adaptive memory programming to solve vehicle routing problems. For more details on this methodology, readers could refer to the literature. Learning mechanism is also used to improve many meta-heuristics, such as Ant Colony Optimization, Tabu Search. Thevenin proposed an improved VNS with learning mechanism, where shaking solution was chosen according according to attractiveness of modified edges.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>35150</offset><text>Inspired by the improvement approach based on memory and learning mechanism, we propose two kinds of methods to record specific attributes which were ever found in elite solution, namely, route-based method and edge-based method. We name route-based restart method as MVNS-r and name edge-based restart method as MVNS-e.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>35471</offset><text>MVNS-r. OD route and PD route are recorded in the form of a four-tuple</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>35542</offset><text>.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>35544</offset><text>RouteType means which type the recorded route is (OD route or PD route). Route means the specified route. CoveredCustomerNum means how many customers are covered by the related route. Cost means the cost if the related route is chosen. If the route is PD route, the cost includes fuel cost, carbon cost, and overtime wage. Total of compensation and carbon emission cost account for OD route cost.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>35941</offset><text>To evaluate routes in memory, we define a lexicographic order for all the records. RouteType has priority over CoveredCustomerNum and Cost, while CoveredCustomerNum has priority over Cost. In practice, PD route is a better option for the sake of improving self-own vehicles’ usage rate, and CLP operators prefer PD route to OD route.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>36277</offset><text>According to the partial order relationship of routes in memory, any route pair can be compared. Routes in new-found elite solution are used to update the memory with fixed size according to lexicographic order. It is worthy to note that, the better record is, the smaller its index is. At the very beginning of MVNS-r, initial solution is used to initialize memory structure.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>36654</offset><text>To enhance the diversity of solutions created by memory, we use both biased and uniform selection method. If a random number rand() is not larger than greedy degree , route is chosen from memory according to Formula 42; otherwise, route is chosen evenlywhere I is the number of records in memory. For biased method, sum of selection probability for each operator  is obviously equal to 1.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>37043</offset><text>The pseudocode of route-based restart method is shown in Algorithm 3.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>37114</offset><text>MVNS-e. Edge-based restart method is from the fact that elite solutions always have a good mix of common edges. Reasonable combination of these edges can improve the quality of restart solution, which helps VNS search in a promising area. To bias the random selection of edges in restart phase, we adapt the notion of move attractiveness to VNS. The moves with higher attractiveness values have higher priority to be performed. The attributes modified by a move must be of course clearly identified.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_4</infon><offset>37614</offset><text>Definition 1</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>37627</offset><text>Attributes of GVRP-PCPS. Attributes of GVRP-PCPS are characteristics related to the solution. In a complete solution of GVRP-PCPS, there are two types of routes, namely, PD route and OD route. For OD route, we merely consider the route with served customer(s). In this paper, attribute means one certain professional or occasional driver visits customer i and customer j in succession. We define the attribute as  or .</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_4</infon><offset>38046</offset><text>Definition 2</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>38059</offset><text>Weight of attribute. If attribute  belongs to one improvement solution (now or before), there is a weight for this attribute  at the iteration t which describes how good the attribute  is based on historical experience.  is updated by global optimal solution at t iteration  according to Formula 43. There is no weight for all the attributes at the very beginning of MVNS-e.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>38435</offset><text>In the update process of attributes’ weight, those that are not in new global optimal solution but recorded in archive are decayed by coefficient . At the same time, weights of attributes belong to both archive and  are enhanced. The increment of weights is as Formula 44. M is constant to control incremental degreeIt can be seen that the strength of the attribute weight changes as the number of iterations increases: the weights of those attributes that often appear in the optimal solution of each iteration are relatively larger; those short-lived good attribute weight will gradually weaken, because they have not been strengthened.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>39077</offset><text>In the whole optimization, once better solution is found, it can used to update edge-based memory according to Formula 43.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_4</infon><offset>39200</offset><text>Definition 3</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>39213</offset><text>Solution attractiveness: Solution attractiveness means the total of weights of attributes in solution</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>39315</offset><text>Thus, we can obtain the solution with the largest attractiveness in the candidate solution pool, using current solution and the selected operator, as is shown in Formula 46where N is the selected neighborhood operator, which is chosen randomly. The size of candidate pool is a constant.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>39603</offset><text>The pseudocode of edge-based restart method is shown in Algorithm 4.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>39673</offset><text>Framework of MVNS</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">40747_2022_661_Fig6_HTML.jpg</infon><infon key="id">Fig6</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>39691</offset><text>The flowchart of MVNS</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>39713</offset><text>In MVNS, once the ID of shaking neighborhood , restart procedure will be executed according to Sect. “Memory-based restart”.  means the number of neighborhoods used in shaking phase. </text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>39901</offset><text>Shaking phase. The order of neighborhood in shaking phase is Outer-relocate, 2-Opt, and CrossExchange. If better solution can not be found through local search phase whose initial solution is shaking solution created in ,  will be selected if it exists.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>40155</offset><text>Local search phase. The order of neighborhood in local search phase is Inner-relocate, Swap, and CrossExchange. Two acceptance strategies are common in local search, namely, first-accept (FA) and best-accept (BA). The first-accept strategy selects the first better neighbor that satisfies the constraints. The best-accept strategy examines all better neighbors satisfying the constraints and selects the best among them. In this paper, we use FA to improve the shaking solution to accelerate the optimization process.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>40673</offset><text>Restart phase. Route-based restart method and edge-based restart are integrated into pseudocode of MVNS. As for MVNS-e, the neighborhoods used in edge-based restart phase are the same to those used in shaking phase.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>40889</offset><text>The pseudocode of MVNS is shown in Algorithm 5. For a clear description of MVNS, a flowchart is also given for summarizing the process of the proposed algorithm and integrating the components.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>41083</offset><text>Instance generation</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">Tab6.xml</infon><infon key="id">Tab6</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_caption</infon><offset>41103</offset><text>Parameters in MVNS</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">Tab6.xml</infon><infon key="id">Tab6</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table</infon><infon key="xml">&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;table xmlns:mml=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML&quot; xmlns:xlink=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink&quot; frame=&quot;hsides&quot; rules=&quot;groups&quot;&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Component&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Parameter&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Range&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Value&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;6&quot;&gt;Edge-based restart&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;italic&gt;M&lt;/italic&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;italic&gt;M&lt;/italic&gt; is a constant to control incremental degree of&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;5,10,15&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;New-found better solution.(Formula &lt;xref rid=&quot;Equ43&quot; ref-type=&quot;&quot;&gt;43&lt;/xref&gt;)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;/&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq220&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M453&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$\rho $$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M454&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;ρ&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq220.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq221&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M455&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$\rho $$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M456&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;ρ&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq221.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt; is used to attenuate the attractive value of&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0.85,0.9,0.95&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0.85&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Attribute recorded.(Formula &lt;xref rid=&quot;Equ44&quot; ref-type=&quot;&quot;&gt;44&lt;/xref&gt;)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;/&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;italic&gt;SN&lt;/italic&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;italic&gt;SN&lt;/italic&gt; is used to control the number of&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;40,50,60&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;50&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Shaking solutions.(Section “Memory-based restart”)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;/&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;4&quot;&gt;Route-based restart&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq222&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M457&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$q_0$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M458&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;q&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;0&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq222.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq223&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M459&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$q_0$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M460&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;q&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;0&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq223.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt; means greedy degree for using .&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0.85,0.9,0.95 0.9&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0.9&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;(Section “Memory-based restart”)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;/&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;italic&gt;MZ&lt;/italic&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;italic&gt;MZ&lt;/italic&gt; means the size of memory.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;40,50,60&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;60&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;(Section “Memory-based restart”)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;/&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;Other&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;italic&gt;RM&lt;/italic&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;When there is no improvement within &lt;italic&gt;RM&lt;/italic&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;5,10,15&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;15&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Outermost loops the algorithm will terminate. (Algorithm 5)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;/&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
</infon><offset>41122</offset><text>Component	Parameter	Description	Range	Value	 	Edge-based restart	M	M is a constant to control incremental degree of	5,10,15	10	 		New-found better solution.(Formula 43)			 		 is used to attenuate the attractive value of	0.85,0.9,0.95	0.85	 		Attribute recorded.(Formula 44)			 	SN	SN is used to control the number of	40,50,60	50	 		Shaking solutions.(Section “Memory-based restart”)			 	Route-based restart		 means greedy degree for using .	0.85,0.9,0.95 0.9	0.9	 		(Section “Memory-based restart”)			 	MZ	MZ means the size of memory.	40,50,60	60	 		(Section “Memory-based restart”)			 	Other	RM	When there is no improvement within RM	5,10,15	15	 		Outermost loops the algorithm will terminate. (Algorithm 5)			 	</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>41854</offset><text>In this paper, we use two kinds of data set to assess the effectiveness of model and the proposed algorithm. The first data set is derived from Solomon’s VRPTW benchmark. To obtain the test instances for the GVRP-PCPS, given a VRPTW instance with customers whose coordinates , we randomly generated the origins and destinations for ODs, in the square with lower left hand corner  and upper right hand corner . The number of ODs is equal to the number of customers. To make more ODs available in crowdsourcing logistics system, we shrink the number of vehicles in original benchmark. The shrinking factors SF are set to 0.5.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>42480</offset><text>The second data set is derived from a real-life city beer distribution situation. The latitude and longitude of the distribution center are (30.942738, 121.084699). 194 customers’ locations in Shanghai are known in the form of (latitude, longitude). Shortest distance between two locations is obtained from Gaode Map based on real road network, which is recorded in distance matrix. Origins and destinations of ODs are generated by the same means in the first test situation. To accelerate the process of simulation, distance between ODs’ location and customers’ locations or depot is calculated according to harversine formula, where earth radius is 6367 (km). As for real-life instance, the scheduled earliest delivery time  of customer  is one random ranging from 0 to 600 (min), and the scheduled latest delivery time  is one random ranging from  to 600 (min). In both adapted benchmark instance and real-life instance, the latest service time of customer  is one random number sampled from range  evenly, and sensitivity coefficient of customer  is created within .</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>43559</offset><text>Other details of instances are shown in Appendix.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>43609</offset><text>Computational experiments</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>43635</offset><text>This section presents the results of our computational experiments. All computations were performed on an Intel Core i7-5700HQ CPU, with 2.60 GHz and 16 GB of RAM. The MVNS and the mathematical model were implemented in Matlab R2018a. We divided the computational study into two parts. The first part aims to assess the performance of the MVNS in terms of both efficiency and effectiveness. In the second part, the MVNS is tested on real-life instances.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>44089</offset><text>Benchmark test</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>44104</offset><text>There are six classes of instances in Solomon’s benchmark set, and we choose the first one of each class as the tested instance of that class, namely, C101, C201, R101, R201, RC101, and RC201. Because of the lack of parameters about GVRP-PCPS in Solomon’s benchmark, it is necessary to add some virtual parameters to origin benchmark instances, which is acceptable for the sake of tuning and component analysis. The related parameters of benchmark instances are shown in Appendix.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>44589</offset><text>Algorithm parameter tuning</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>44616</offset><text>There are six main parameters in MVNS-r and MVNS-e. The descriptions about these parameters are shown in Table 6. An important step in adopting MVNS to solve real-life problems is to find appropriate parameters for it. Refer to, we give the range of each parameter, as is shown in Table 6. Taguchi experiments of  (MVNS-r) and  (MVNS-e) are conducted on six Solomon instances. Each experiment with certain parameter combination in Taguchi experiment table is repeated for 20 times. The value after tuning is shown in Table 6.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>45142</offset><text>Component analysis</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>45161</offset><text>To validate effectiveness of the proposed memory restart mechanism in this paper, three versions of VNS are conducted, namely classic VNS (CVNS), MVNS-r, and MVNS-e. Each instance experiment for each version of VNS is repeated for 20 times. Sum of ranks among 60 solutions for each instance and each algorithm is recorded in Table 7. Statistical Friedman test is used to analyze the results above. Box-plot results are shown in Fig. 7. The p value of Friedman test is 0.0057, which indicates that there are obvious differences between the three algorithms. From the experimental results in Table 7 and Fig. 7, MVNS-r has advantage over the other two versions of VNS in terms of accuracy. Although MVNS-e shows poor performance in solving six benchmark instances, it does give a promising direction to design memory-based or learning-based algorithm, which has been proved by. Shrinking the size of record in memory phase or usage of various operators in restart phase may be a good strategy to enhance edge-based restart method.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">Tab7.xml</infon><infon key="id">Tab7</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_caption</infon><offset>46193</offset><text>Rank comparation</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">Tab7.xml</infon><infon key="id">Tab7</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table</infon><infon key="xml">&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;table frame=&quot;hsides&quot; rules=&quot;groups&quot;&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Instance Set&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;CVNS&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;MVNS-r&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;MVNS-e&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;C101&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;587&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;526&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;717&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;C201&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;507&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;407&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;916&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;R101&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;683&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;448&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;699&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;R201&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;738&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;255&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;837&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;RC101&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;1008&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;319&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;503&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;RC201&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;648&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;418&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;764&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
</infon><offset>46210</offset><text>Instance Set	CVNS	MVNS-r	MVNS-e	 	C101	587	526	717	 	C201	507	407	916	 	R101	683	448	699	 	R201	738	255	837	 	RC101	1008	319	503	 	RC201	648	418	764	 	</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>46362</offset><text>From the perspective of computational complexity, the proposed strategies in both MVNS-r and MVNS-e do not result in the increment of algorithm running cost. Based on the above analysis, we use MVNS-r to optimize real-life instances in Sect. 6.2.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">40747_2022_661_Fig7_HTML.jpg</infon><infon key="id">Fig7</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>46609</offset><text>Box-plot of three versions of VNS</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>46643</offset><text>Real-life instance</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>46662</offset><text>In this section, the performance of the algorithm in terms of solution quality is tested with respect to different instance parameters, including minimal action cost (), variable cost coefficient (), compensation coefficient (), fuel price (), and carbon tax price (). For sensitivity analysis, the range of each parameter is given in Appendix. In Sect. 6.2, repeat times are 20 for each instance parameter setting, and mean value of each indicator is recorded.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>47124</offset><text>Potential benefits of employing occasional drivers</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">40747_2022_661_Fig8_HTML.jpg</infon><infon key="id">Fig8</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>47175</offset><text>Potential benefits of employing ODs</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>47211</offset><text>Motivation of action for ODs is that the compensation obtained is higher than expectation. To validate the supply of ODs have positive effect on service, we take , , and  as independent variables, while the optimized objective UCR is controlled variable. From Fig. 8, we can conclude the more motivated the ODs are, the better UCR is. From the perspective of CLP owner, higher compensation is not cost-effective, because it cannot lead to significant improvement of UCR in a higher range of compensation coefficient.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">40747_2022_661_Fig9_HTML.jpg</infon><infon key="id">Fig9</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>47729</offset><text>Analysis of combination</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>47753</offset><text>To analyze the effect of employing heterogeneous ODs on crowdsourcing logistics in this paper, we introduce nine kinds of passing-by drivers into this system, who are parameterized by (,). Results are shown in Fig. 9. As the the compensation coefficient increases, there is a downward trend of indicator UCR. However, passing-by drivers with higher minimal action cost and higher variable cost coefficient do not participate in crowdsourcing delivery task regardless of the given value of  ranging from 1 to 4.6. It is a significant management insight that differentiated pricing strategy for compensation can balance cost and UCR according to the characters of ODs.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>48421</offset><text>The Influence of fuel price and carbon emission coefficient</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>48481</offset><text>External market factors, such fuel price and carbon tax price, may give rise to change of operating strategy. In this section, we study how fluctuations in external market influence the usage of ODs under the same service level. To study intrinsical characteristic of problem in this section, we only consider two objectives, namely, UCR and operating cost (). Case 1–Case 10 are same except for OD information. ODs are added to each case incrementally. Quantity of ODs in each Case  is  larger than Case 1. Figures 10 and  11 show how rate of ODs used changes as  and  increases. In both Figs. 10 and  11, picture above summarizes all the cases, while picture below includes mean curve of ten cases and its linear fitting line.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">40747_2022_661_Fig10_HTML.jpg</infon><infon key="id">Fig10</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>49215</offset><text>Rate of ODs used with fuel price</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">40747_2022_661_Fig11_HTML.jpg</infon><infon key="id">Fig11</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>49248</offset><text>Rate of ODs used with carbon tax price</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">40747_2022_661_Fig12_HTML.jpg</infon><infon key="id">Fig12</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>49287</offset><text>Cost Component with carbon tax price</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>49324</offset><text>Compared to carbon market, sensitivity of ODs’ participation in fuel market is lower. It seems that choosing ODs become an option when carbon tax price increases, which reduces carbon emissions of PDs and adds a small amount of emissions related to detours. It will be quite important to make decision considering carbon trading, because saving means profitable.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">40747_2022_661_Fig13_HTML.jpg</infon><infon key="id">Fig13</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>49689</offset><text>Analysis of delivery mode</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>49715</offset><text>To analyze cost changes with carbon tax price, operating cost component at different parameter level of  is summarized in Fig. 12. The value of bar graph is shown at the left of Fig. 12, while stippled line shows the change of carbon tax price. Although the carbon tax price changes linearly, the change trend of operating cost is not obvious. In addition, TFC and ODS account for a large proportion at each level of . Management insight from these results is that carbon tax has limited moderation for CLP owner if they focus too much on cost, and the government should take some other actions of carbon pricing.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>50331</offset><text>Benefits of allowing multi-delivery</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">Tab8.xml</infon><infon key="id">Tab8</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_caption</infon><offset>50367</offset><text>Delivery mode comparation</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">Tab8.xml</infon><infon key="id">Tab8</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table</infon><infon key="xml">&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;table frame=&quot;hsides&quot; rules=&quot;groups&quot;&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Instance&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Delivery mode&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;UCR&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;UR&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;UF&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Cost&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;RF01&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Zero&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0.446&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;1.835&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0.577&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;1406&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Single&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0.072&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;1.877&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0.780&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;2551&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;Multi&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0.072&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;1.901&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0.835&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;2658&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;RF02&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Zero&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0.437&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;1.786&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0.535&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;2240&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Single&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0.037&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;1.890&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0.596&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;4376&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;Multi&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0.03&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;1.920&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0.573&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;3793&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;RF03&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Zero&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0.481&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;1.933&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0.486&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;585&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Single&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;1.965&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0.608&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;1029&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;Multi&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;2.284&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0.499&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;976&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;RF04&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Zero&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0.377&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;1.926&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0.458&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;1894&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;Single&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0.066&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;1.951&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0.729&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;3468&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Multi&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0.066&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;1.929&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0.678&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;3241&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;RF05&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Zero&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0.471&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;1.897&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0.459&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;1669&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Single&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0.050&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;1.860&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0.798&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;3842&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;Multi&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0.050&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;1.870&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0.642&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;3280&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;RF06&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Zero&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0.426&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;1.921&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0.365&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;864&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Single&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0.056&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;1.901&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0.749&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;1969&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;Multi&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0.056&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;1.981&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0.496&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;1771&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
</infon><offset>50393</offset><text>Instance	Delivery mode	UCR	UR	UF	Cost	 	RF01	Zero	0.446	1.835	0.577	1406	 	Single	0.072	1.877	0.780	2551	 	Multi	0.072	1.901	0.835	2658	 	RF02	Zero	0.437	1.786	0.535	2240	 	Single	0.037	1.890	0.596	4376	 	Multi	0.03	1.920	0.573	3793	 	RF03	Zero	0.481	1.933	0.486	585	 	Single	0	1.965	0.608	1029	 	Multi	0	2.284	0.499	976	 	RF04	Zero	0.377	1.926	0.458	1894	 	Single	0.066	1.951	0.729	3468	 	Multi	0.066	1.929	0.678	3241	 	RF05	Zero	0.471	1.897	0.459	1669	 	Single	0.050	1.860	0.798	3842	 	Multi	0.050	1.870	0.642	3280	 	RF06	Zero	0.426	1.921	0.365	864	 	Single	0.056	1.901	0.749	1969	 	Multi	0.056	1.981	0.496	1771	 	</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>51010</offset><text>To validate the effectiveness of GVRP-PCPS (Multi) proposed in this paper, two compared models are used, namely, traditional delivery mode without ODs (Zero) and adapted version of GVRP-PCPS only allowing single delivery in OD route (Single). Results are shown in Table 8. Six real-life instances are generated randomly, which are named as RF01-RF06. Cost in Table 8 means operating cost, namely, the fourth optimized objective in Section “Problem description and formulation”. In Table 8, “Multi” delivery mode has advantage over the other two modes except for RF04 in terms of lexicographic objective function value. However, the difference between “Multi” and “Single” on RF04 is very small in terms of objective UR.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>51749</offset><text>To further validate the effectiveness of the proposed model, we evaluate this model from the perspective of ODs’ satisfaction and participation. ODs’ satisfaction means average compensation of all the employed OD routes. Participation can be described by the rate of ODs used in the previous statement. In Fig. 13, “Multi” and “Single” show the similar performance in terms of UCR on six real-life instances. However, ODs in “Multi” have higher satisfaction than that in “Single” . Higher satisfaction means more stable in crowdsourcing logistics. Although “Single” has advantage over “Multi” in terms of rate of ODs used, it is less acceptable than “Multi” in practice.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>52452</offset><text>Conclusions and future research</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>52484</offset><text>In this paper, we have proposed a novel VRP model under the situation of sharing economy from a comprehensive perspective. Interests of stakeholders in the system have been optimized hierarchically by memory-based variable neighborhood search algorithm. The strategies to enhance VNS have been proved to effective through component analysis, which has enriched the pool of algorithms for partially crowdsourcing logistics delivery mode. The model in this paper may be further utilized to improve performance of management considering given goal constraints and priorities. Furthermore, memory-based VNS in this paper can be adjusted to solve other VRPs with various objectives. Finally, experimental results of real-life beer delivery indicate the importance of differentiated pricing, and authority might encourage companies to reduce carbon emissions by more effective means, such as carbon quota mechanism and subsidies for alternative energy vehicles.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>53440</offset><text>As a novel mode with characteristic of light asset, crowdsourcing logistics still face a series of problems. As for this study, there are some optimized objectives which can be improved hierarchically (e.g., service type and balance type ), while some objectives should be optimized simultaneously (e.g., cost type and balance type) from the perspective of practice. Thus, it is a tricky problem to handle these objectives. In addition, the number of objectives in crowdsourcing logistics is usually larger than three, which adds the difficulty of optimization. It may be a promising research direction to use methodology of many-objective optimization in solving problems related to crowdsourcing logistics.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>54149</offset><text>For the sake of modeling easily, many parameters in this paper are static and homogeneous, such as characters of customers, arrival of ODs, and the type of vehicles. How to model these uncertainties is the key to improve value of mathematic model in engineering. Stochastic programming and behaviour science may narrow this gap between theory and application.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>54509</offset><text>The need to reduce carbon emissions is growing globally, operation management of crowdsourcing logistics under the situation of carbon trading or market is less paid attention to. In the future, we will study crowdsourcing logistics with carbon trading to give a more eco-friendly solution.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">APPENDIX</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>54800</offset><text>Appendix A: Benchmark test</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">Tab9.xml</infon><infon key="id">Tab9</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_caption</infon><offset>54827</offset><text>Parameters in benchmark test</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">Tab9.xml</infon><infon key="id">Tab9</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table</infon><infon key="xml">&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;table xmlns:mml=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML&quot; xmlns:xlink=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink&quot; frame=&quot;hsides&quot; rules=&quot;groups&quot;&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Symbol&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Value&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq252&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M517&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$R^S$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M518&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:msup&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;S&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:msup&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq252.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Minimal action cost&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq253&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M519&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$R^V$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M520&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:msup&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;V&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:msup&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq253.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Variable cost coefficient&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0.1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq254&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M521&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$\lambda $$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M522&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;λ&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq254.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Compensation coefficient&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0.5&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq255&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M523&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$w_1$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M524&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;w&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;1&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq255.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Fuel price&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq256&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M525&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$w_2$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M526&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;w&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;2&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq256.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Carbon tax price&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0.25&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq257&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M527&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$w_3$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M528&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;w&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;3&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq257.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Overtime wage per unit time&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq258&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M529&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$E_f$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M530&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;E&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;f&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq258.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Carbon emission conversion factor&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;2.37&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq259&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M531&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$\mu _0$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M532&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;μ&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;0&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq259.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Fuel consumption rate of empty vehicle&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0.08&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq260&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M533&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$\mu ^{\text {*}}$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M534&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:msup&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;μ&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mtext&gt;*&lt;/mml:mtext&gt;&lt;/mml:msup&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq260.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Fuel consumption rate of vehicle&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0.12&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;With full capacity&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;/&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;italic&gt;Sal&lt;/italic&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Basic salary per day&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;200&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;italic&gt;SL&lt;/italic&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Designed service level of CLP&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0.9&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
</infon><offset>54856</offset><text>Symbol	Description	Value	 		Minimal action cost	1	 		Variable cost coefficient	0.1	 		Compensation coefficient	0.5	 		Fuel price	7	 		Carbon tax price	0.25	 		Overtime wage per unit time	6	 		Carbon emission conversion factor	2.37	 		Fuel consumption rate of empty vehicle	0.08	 		Fuel consumption rate of vehicle	0.12	 		With full capacity		 	Sal	Basic salary per day	200	 	SL	Designed service level of CLP	0.9	 	</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">Tab10.xml</infon><infon key="id">Tab10</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_caption</infon><offset>55271</offset><text>Information of products</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">Tab10.xml</infon><infon key="id">Tab10</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table</infon><infon key="xml">&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;table frame=&quot;hsides&quot; rules=&quot;groups&quot;&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;Type&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Length&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Width&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Height&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Weight&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;(cm)&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;(cm)&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;(cm)&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;(kg)&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Type 1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;40&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;17&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;12&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;7.92&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Type 2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;40&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;20&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;17&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;9&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Type 3&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;27.5&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;20&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;17&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Type 4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;38.5&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;36.5&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;35.5&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;7.92&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Type 5&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;27.5&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;20&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;12&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;3.96&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
</infon><offset>55295</offset><text>Type	Length	Width	Height	Weight	 	(cm)	(cm)	(cm)	(kg)	 	Type 1	40	17	12	7.92	 	Type 2	40	20	17	9	 	Type 3	27.5	20	17	6	 	Type 4	38.5	36.5	35.5	7.92	 	Type 5	27.5	20	12	3.96	 	</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">Tab11.xml</infon><infon key="id">Tab11</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_caption</infon><offset>55471</offset><text>Parameter setting (a)</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">Tab11.xml</infon><infon key="id">Tab11</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table</infon><infon key="xml">&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;table xmlns:mml=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML&quot; xmlns:xlink=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink&quot; frame=&quot;hsides&quot; rules=&quot;groups&quot;&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Analyzed parameters&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Range&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Step&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Unit&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq261&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M535&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$R_{k}^{S}$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M536&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:msubsup&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;k&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;S&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:msubsup&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq261.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;[0,180]&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;20&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Yuan&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq262&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M537&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$R_{k}^{V}$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M538&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:msubsup&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;k&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;V&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:msubsup&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq262.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;[1,4.6]&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0.4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Yuan/km&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq263&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M539&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$\lambda $$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M540&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;λ&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq263.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;[1,4.6]&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0.4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Yuan/km&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq264&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M541&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$w_1$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M542&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;w&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;1&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq264.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;[6.5,8.3]&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0.2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Yuan/L&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq265&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M543&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$w_2$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M544&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;w&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;2&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq265.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;[0.05, 0.5]&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0.05&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Yuan/kg&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
</infon><offset>55493</offset><text>Analyzed parameters	Range	Step	Unit	 		[0,180]	20	Yuan	 		[1,4.6]	0.4	Yuan/km	 		[1,4.6]	0.4	Yuan/km	 		[6.5,8.3]	0.2	Yuan/L	 		[0.05, 0.5]	0.05	Yuan/kg	 	</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">Tab11.xml</infon><infon key="id">Tab11</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_foot</infon><offset>55649</offset><text> The reference range of  is from www.globalpetrolprices.com</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">Tab11.xml</infon><infon key="id">Tab11</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_foot</infon><offset>55709</offset><text> The reference range of  is from www.statista.com</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">Tab12.xml</infon><infon key="id">Tab12</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_caption</infon><offset>55759</offset><text>Parameter setting (b)</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">Tab12.xml</infon><infon key="id">Tab12</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table</infon><infon key="xml">&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;table xmlns:mml=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML&quot; xmlns:xlink=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink&quot; frame=&quot;hsides&quot; rules=&quot;groups&quot;&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;Analyzed parameters&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot; colspan=&quot;6&quot;&gt;Other parameters&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq270&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M553&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$R_{k}^{S}$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M554&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:msubsup&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;k&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;S&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:msubsup&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq270.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq271&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M555&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$R_{k}^{V}$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M556&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:msubsup&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;k&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;V&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:msubsup&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq271.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq272&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M557&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$\lambda $$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M558&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;λ&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq272.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq273&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M559&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$w_1$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M560&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;w&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;1&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq273.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq274&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M561&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$w_2$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M562&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;w&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;2&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq274.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;italic&gt;SL&lt;/italic&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq275&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M563&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$R_{k}^{S}$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M564&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:msubsup&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;k&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;S&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:msubsup&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq275.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;\&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0.05&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0.9&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq276&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M565&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$R_{k}^{V}$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M566&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:msubsup&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;R&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;k&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;V&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:msubsup&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq276.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;20&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;\&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0.05&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0.9&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq277&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M567&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$\lambda $$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M568&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;λ&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq277.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;20&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;\&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0.05&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0.9&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq278&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M569&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$w_1$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M570&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;w&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;1&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq278.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;20&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;\&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0.05&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0.9&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;inline-formula id=&quot;IEq279&quot;&gt;&lt;alternatives&gt;&lt;tex-math id=&quot;M571&quot;&gt;\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$w_2$$\end{document}&lt;/tex-math&gt;&lt;mml:math id=&quot;M572&quot;&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;w&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;2&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;&lt;inline-graphic xlink:href=&quot;40747_2022_661_Article_IEq279.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/alternatives&gt;&lt;/inline-formula&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;20&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;\&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;0.9&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
</infon><offset>55781</offset><text>Analyzed parameters	Other parameters	 						SL	 		\	1	2	7	0.05	0.9	 		20	\	2	7	0.05	0.9	 		20	1	\	7	0.05	0.9	 		20	1	2	\	0.05	0.9	 		20	1	2	7	\	0.9	 	</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">APPENDIX</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>55932</offset><text>In Solomon’s benchmark, distance between two nodes are equal to travelling time, which means that velocity of vehicle is 1. The added parameters are given in Table 9. BT and DT are equal to upper of depot’s time window in each instance.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">APPENDIX</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>56174</offset><text>Appendix B: Real-life instance</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">APPENDIX</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>56205</offset><text>For each real-life experiment in Section “Real life instance”, chosen customers are generated randomly from candidate set of 194 customers. Quantity of each type is a random ranging from 1 to 10. Information about products is shown in Table 10. The travelling speed of vehicles in real-life instance is set to 50km/h.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">APPENDIX</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>56528</offset><text>Unchanged parameters are given:(30 Yuan/h), (2.37 kg/L)1, (0.08 L/km), (0.12 L/km), Sal(200 Yuan), BT(8 h), DT(10 h). Analyzed parameters are given in Tables 11 and 12. Vehicle parameters in this paper are given referring to Jinbei. Maximum loading weight of vehicles is set to 2000 kg. In real life, maximum loading volume is another important constraint. In real-life instances, we add this volume constraint to GVRP-PCPS to make solution suitable for practice. Maximum loading volume of vehicles is set to 3.04 .</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">APPENDIX</infon><infon key="type">footnote</infon><offset>57045</offset><text>https://www.interregs.com/catalogue/details/CHN-2799919/gb-27999-2019/fuel-consumption-evaluation-methods-and-targets-for-passenger-cars</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">APPENDIX</infon><infon key="type">footnote</infon><offset>57182</offset><text>This work was supported by the National Natural Science Foundation of China (Grant Nos. 61903178, 61906081, 71840003, and U20A20306), the Shenzhen Science and Technology Program (Grant No. RCBS20200714114817264), the Key Soft Science Project of “Science and Technology Innovation Action Plan” of Shanghai Science and Technology Commission (Grant No. 20692104300), Guangdong Provincial Key Laboratory (Grant No. 2020B121201001), the Program for Guangdong Introducing Innovative and Enterpreneurial Teams (Grant No. 2017ZT07X386), and the Shenzhen Peacock Plan (Grant No. KQTD2016112514355531)</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">APPENDIX</infon><infon key="type">footnote</infon><offset>57778</offset><text>Publisher's Note</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">APPENDIX</infon><infon key="type">footnote</infon><offset>57795</offset><text>Springer Nature remains neutral with regard to jurisdictional claims in published maps and institutional affiliations.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">APPENDIX</infon><infon key="type">title</infon><offset>57914</offset><text>Declaration</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">COMP_INT</infon><infon key="type">title</infon><offset>57926</offset><text>Conflict of interest</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">COMP_INT</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>57947</offset><text>The authors declare that they have no conflict of interest.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">title</infon><offset>58007</offset><text>References</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">5</infon><infon key="issue">01</infon><infon key="lpage">18</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Dong;given-names:L</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Miao;given-names:G</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Wen;given-names:W</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1142/S1793930521000015</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">East Asian Policy</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">13</infon><infon key="year">2021</infon><offset>58018</offset><text>China’s carbon neutrality policy: objectives, impacts and paths</text></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Sundararajan;given-names:A</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">The sharing economy: the end of employment and the rise of crowd-based capitalism</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>58084</offset></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">320</infon><infon key="lpage">331</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Ritter;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Schanz;given-names:H</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2018.12.154</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Clean Prod</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">213</infon><infon key="year">2019</infon><offset>58085</offset><text>The sharing economy: a comprehensive business model framework</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">222</infon><infon key="issue">1</infon><infon key="lpage">235</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Arslan Alp;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Niels;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Leo;given-names:K</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Rob;given-names:Z</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1287/trsc.2017.0803</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Transp Sci</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">53</infon><infon key="year">2019</infon><offset>58147</offset><text>Crowdsourced delivery-a dynamic pickup and delivery problem with ad hoc drivers</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1</infon><infon key="issue">3</infon><infon key="lpage">13</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Buldeo;given-names:RH</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Sara;given-names:V</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Jan;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Cathy;given-names:M</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Eur Transp Res Rev</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">9</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>58227</offset><text>Crowd logistics: an opportunity for more sustainable urban freight transport?</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1025139</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Aliaa;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Fatma;given-names:G</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Bookbinder James;given-names:H</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Omega</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">98</infon><infon key="year">2021</infon><offset>58305</offset><text>Crowdsourced delivery: a review of platforms and academic literature</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1</infon><infon key="issue">3</infon><infon key="lpage">13</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Li;given-names:Y</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Yuewu;given-names:Yu</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1007/s12544-017-0251-y</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Eur Transp Res Rev</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">9</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>58374</offset><text>The use of freight apps in road freight transport for co2 reduction</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>58442</offset><text>Dablanc L, Morganti E, Arvidsson N, Woxenius J, Browne M, Saidi N (2017) The rise of on-demand ’instant deliveries’ in European cities. In: Supply Chain Forum: An International Journal, volume 18, pages 203–217. Taylor &amp; Francis</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>58678</offset><text>Barr A, Wohl J (2013) Exclusive: Walmart may get customers to deliver packages to online buyers. REUTERS–Business Week</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">472</infon><infon key="issue">2</infon><infon key="lpage">480</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Claudia;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Martin;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Grazia;given-names:SM</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.ejor.2016.03.049</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Eur J Oper Res</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">254</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>58799</offset><text>The vehicle routing problem with occasional drivers</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>58851</offset><text>Macrina G, Pugliese Luigi Di P, Guerriero F, Laganà D (2017) The vehicle routing problem with occasional drivers and time windows. In: International conference on optimization and decision science, pp 577–587. Springer</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">104806</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Macrina;given-names:G</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Di Puglia;given-names:L</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Pugliese;given-names:FG</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Laporte;given-names:G</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.cor.2019.104806</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Comput Oper Res</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">113</infon><infon key="year">2020</infon><offset>59074</offset><text>Crowd-shipping with time windows and transshipment nodes</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">122</infon><infon key="lpage">133</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Dahle;given-names:L</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Andersson;given-names:H</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Christiansen;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Speranza;given-names:MG</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.cor.2019.04.023</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Comput Oper Res</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">109</infon><infon key="year">2019</infon><offset>59131</offset><text>The pickup and delivery problem with time windows and occasional drivers</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>59204</offset><text>Macrina G, Guerriero F (2018) The green vehicle routing problem with occasional drivers. In: New trends in emerging complex real life problems, pp 357–366, Springer, New York</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>59381</offset><text>Dahle L, Andersson H, Christiansen M (2017) The vehicle routing problem with dynamic occasional drivers. In: International conference on computational logistics, pp 49–63, Springer, New York</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">2153</infon><infon key="issue">9</infon><infon key="lpage">2174</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Dayarian;given-names:I</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Savelsbergh;given-names:M</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1111/poms.13219</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Prod Oper Manag</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">29</infon><infon key="year">2020</infon><offset>59574</offset><text>Crowdshipping and same-day delivery: employing in-store customers to deliver online orders</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">90</infon><infon key="lpage">100</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Katarzyna;given-names:G</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Ana;given-names:V</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Pedro;given-names:PJ</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.trpro.2018.09.011</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Transp Res Procedia</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">30</infon><infon key="year">2018</infon><offset>59665</offset><text>Stochastic last-mile delivery with crowdshipping</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>59714</offset><text>Archetti C, Guerriero F, Macrina G (2021) The online vehicle routing problem with occasional drivers. Comput Oper Res 127:105144</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>59843</offset><text>Rai HB, Verlinde S, Macharis C (2018) Shipping outside the box. Environmental impact and stakeholder analysis of a crowd logistics platform in Belgium. J Clean Product 202:806–816</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">64</infon><infon key="issue">1</infon><infon key="lpage">80</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Stenger;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Vigo;given-names:D</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Enz;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Schwind;given-names:M</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1287/trsc.1110.0396</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Transp Sci</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">47</infon><infon key="year">2013</infon><offset>60025</offset><text>An adaptive variable neighborhood search algorithm for a vehicle routing problem arising in small package shipping</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">163</infon><infon key="lpage">175</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Kalayci Can;given-names:B</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Can;given-names:K</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.eswa.2016.09.017</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Expert Syst Appl</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">66</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>60140</offset><text>An ant colony system empowered variable neighborhood search algorithm for the vehicle routing problem with simultaneous pickup and delivery</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1401</infon><infon key="issue">5</infon><infon key="lpage">1408</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Li;given-names:X</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Haiyan;given-names:X</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Li;given-names:M</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1007/s00170-013-4866-4</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Int J Adv Manuf Technol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">87</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>60280</offset><text>A memory-based complete local search method with variable neighborhood structures for no-wait job shops</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>60384</offset><text>Amélia LSM, de Souza Sérgio R, Jamilson Freitas Souza M, Lúcia C, Bazzan A (2019) A reinforcement learning-based multi-agent framework applied for solving routing and scheduling problems. Expert Systems with Applications, 131:148–171</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">344</infon><infon key="lpage">353</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Thevenin;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Zufferey;given-names:N</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.dam.2018.03.019</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Discret Appl Math</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">261</infon><infon key="year">2019</infon><offset>60628</offset><text>Learning variable neighborhood search for a scheduling problem with time windows and rejections</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">28</infon><infon key="lpage">37</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Pacheco;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:García;given-names:I</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Álvarez;given-names:A</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.knosys.2014.02.014</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Knowl-Based Syst</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">62</infon><infon key="year">2014</infon><offset>60724</offset><text>Enhancing variable neighborhood search by adding memory: App cation to a real logistic problem</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>60819</offset><text>Feng L, Zhou L, Gupta A, Zhong J, Zhu Z, Tan K-C, Qin K (2019) Solving generalized vehicle routing problem with occasional drivers via evolutionary multitasking. IEEE Trans Cybern</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">3</infon><infon key="lpage">18</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Zadeh;given-names:LA</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Adv Fuzzy Set Theory Appl</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">11</infon><infon key="year">1979</infon><offset>60999</offset><text>Fuzzy sets and information granularity</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">793</infon><infon key="issue">5–8</infon><infon key="lpage">802</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Mehdi;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Mahdavi;given-names:AV</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Mehdi;given-names:K</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Int J Adv Manuf Technol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">75</infon><infon key="year">2014</infon><offset>61038</offset><text>A mathematical model and a solving procedure for multi-depot vehicle routing problem with fuzzy time window and heterogeneous vehicle</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">504</infon><infon key="lpage">527</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Farid;given-names:GS</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Simak;given-names:N</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Reza;given-names:T-M</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Keivan;given-names:G</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.asoc.2013.08.015</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Appl Soft Comput</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">14</infon><infon key="year">2014</infon><offset>61172</offset><text>A multi-objective dynamic vehicle routing problem with fuzzy time windows: model, solution and application</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1419</infon><infon key="issue">7</infon><infon key="lpage">1431</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Xiao;given-names:Y</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Zhao;given-names:Q</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Kaku;given-names:I</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Yuchun;given-names:X</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.cor.2011.08.013</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Comput Oper Res</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">39</infon><infon key="year">2012</infon><offset>61279</offset><text>Development of a fuel consumption optimization model for the capacitated vehicle routing problem</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1097</infon><infon key="issue">11</infon><infon key="lpage">1100</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Mladenović;given-names:N</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Hansen;given-names:P</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/S0305-0548(97)00031-2</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Comput Oper Res</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">24</infon><infon key="year">1997</infon><offset>61376</offset><text>Variable neighborhood search</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1</infon><infon key="issue">1</infon><infon key="lpage">16</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Taillard Éric;given-names:D</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Gambardella Luca;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Michel;given-names:G</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Jean-Yves;given-names:P</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/S0377-2217(00)00268-X</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Eur J Oper Res</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">135</infon><infon key="year">2001</infon><offset>61405</offset><text>Adaptive memory programming: a unified view of metaheuristics</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">28</infon><infon key="issue">1</infon><infon key="lpage">47</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Olivera;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Viera;given-names:O</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.cor.2005.02.044</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Comput Oper Res</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">34</infon><infon key="year">2007</infon><offset>61467</offset><text>Adaptive memory programming for the vehicle routing problem with multiple trips</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">2309</infon><infon key="issue">9</infon><infon key="lpage">2327</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Tarantilis Christos;given-names:D</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.cor.2004.03.005</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Comput Oper Res</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">32</infon><infon key="year">2005</infon><offset>61547</offset><text>Solving the vehicle routing problem with adaptive memory programming methodology</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1111</infon><infon key="issue">6</infon><infon key="lpage">1127</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Xiangyong;given-names:L</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Peng;given-names:T</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Aneja;given-names:YP</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.tre.2010.02.004</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Transp Res Part E: Log Transp Rev</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">46</infon><infon key="year">2010</infon><offset>61628</offset><text>An adaptive memory programming metaheuristic for the heterogeneous fixed fleet vehicle routing problem</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">114</infon><infon key="issue">1</infon><infon key="lpage">130</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Li;given-names:K</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Fialho;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Kwong;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Zhang;given-names:Q</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1109/TEVC.2013.2239648</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">IEEE Trans Evol Comput</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">18</infon><infon key="year">2013</infon><offset>61731</offset><text>Adaptive operator selection with bandits for a multiobjective evolutionary algorithm based on decomposition</text></passage></document></collection>
