<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd">
<collection><source>PMC</source><date>20220727</date><key>pmc.key</key><document><id>9115421</id><infon key="license">NO-CC CODE</infon><passage><infon key="alt-title">Crowdsourcing and COVID‐19: How Public Administrations Mobilize Crowds to Find Solutions to Problems Posed by the Pandemic</infon><infon key="article-id_doi">10.1111/puar.13489</infon><infon key="article-id_pmc">9115421</infon><infon key="article-id_pmid">35600426</infon><infon key="article-id_publisher-id">PUAR13489</infon><infon key="fpage">756</infon><infon key="issue">4</infon><infon key="license">This article is being made freely available through PubMed Central as part of the COVID-19 public health emergency response. It can be used for unrestricted research re-use and analysis in any form or by any means with acknowledgement of the original source, for the duration of the public health emergency.</infon><infon key="lpage">763</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Colovic;given-names:Ana</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Caloffi;given-names:Annalisa</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Rossi;given-names:Federica</infon><infon key="section_type">TITLE</infon><infon key="type">front</infon><infon key="volume">82</infon><infon key="year">2022</infon><offset>0</offset><text>Crowdsourcing and COVID‐19: How Public Administrations Mobilize Crowds to Find Solutions to Problems Posed by the Pandemic</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract_title_1</infon><offset>126</offset><text>Abstract</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>135</offset><text> We discuss how public administrations have used crowdsourcing to find solutions to specific problems posed by the COVID‐19 pandemic, and to what extent crowdsourcing has been instrumental in promoting open innovation and service co‐creation. We propose a conceptual typology of crowdsourcing challenges based on the degree of their openness and collaboration with the crowd that they establish. Using empirical evidence collected in 2020 and 2021, we examine the extent to which these types have been used in practice. We discuss each type of crowdsourcing challenge identified and draw implications for public policy. </text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title</infon><offset>760</offset><text>Evidence for Practice</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>782</offset><text>Public administrations have used crowdsourcing during the COVID‐19 pandemic to respond to the new and urgent needs of the population.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>918</offset><text>We propose a conceptual distinction between four different types of crowdsourcing challenges, depending on the degree of co‐creation between seekers and solvers and the degree of openness of the solution.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>1125</offset><text>Public administrations have used all four types of crowdsourcing; “open co‐creation” challenges constitute a small share of all public crowdsourcing challenges.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>1292</offset><text>There is scope for more extensive use of “open co‐creation” challenges in the context of policies responding to large‐scale complex problems such as the COVID‐19 pandemic.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>1474</offset><text>The scale and urgency of the COVID‐19 pandemic have led governments to implement rapid and complex interventions in a variety of social and economic domains (Huang ). A global wicked issue (Moon ), the pandemic is characterized by complexity and uncertainty (Steen and Brandsen ), affecting every aspect of life, disrupting social, organizational, and political processes (Dahlke et al. ; Shi et al. ) and highlighting the strong interdependency between social and political systems (Grizzle, Goodin, and Robinson ; Schomaker, Hack, and Mandry ). The rapid spread of the pandemic has forced governments to implement multiple, and sometimes unprecedented, measures to prevent the collapse of healthcare systems and national economies worldwide (Bel, Gasulla, and Mazaira‐Font ; Capano and Lippi ; Mei ). These include making substantial investments in areas such as research and development (R&amp;D) for vaccines and treatments, mechanisms to track the spread of infection, and the production of protection and risk reduction devices.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>2519</offset><text>Crowdsourcing has played a role in this particular context. Public administrations' increasing adoption of new digital technologies—including, in particular, platform government practices, as well as open data and open‐source practices—has facilitated the use of crowdsourcing to respond quickly and creatively to new and urgent needs of citizens (Bryson et al. ; Kim, Andersen, and Lee ; O'Reilly ). For example, Lim (2020, cited in Kim, Andersen, and Lee ) recounts how the South Korean government, faced with a shortage of respiratory masks, published the Application Programming Interfaces that managed the pharmacy administration system, allowing private developers to design apps to track the availability of masks in pharmacies in real‐time.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>3280</offset><text>Crowdsourcing is the practice of obtaining solutions (services, ideas, or other contributions) from a crowd (an undefined, large group of people) by means of an internet‐disseminated open call, often via crowdsourcing platforms (Howe ). The seeker and the solvers of the crowdsourced solution do not have a hierarchical relationship, and their collaboration takes place on equal terms (Schenk and Guittard ).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>3693</offset><text>Crowdsourcing has become a tool of public administrations, used to serve various purposes (Brabham ; Bryson et al. ; Liu ; Nam ). For example, crowdsourcing serves as a distributed problem‐solving model for public administrations, with the potential to involve citizens in policy design and implementation and in improving public services (Liu ). It is also used to co‐produce public services and improve their effectiveness, acceptance, and legitimacy (Dutil ; Liu ; Weng et al. ). Finally, it is an important tool of collaborative government (Hall ; Hartley, Sørensen, and Torfing ; Steen and Brandsen ), e‐government (Aldemir and Şen ; Hardy and Williams ; Linders ), open government (Brabham ), and platform government (Agarwal ; Cordella and Paletti ; Kim, Andersen, and Lee ; Dijck, José, and De Waal ). In particular, the concept of platform government is used to denote the government's use of new IT platforms in order to engage in extensive collaboration with users, going beyond the simple adoption of e‐government practices, and moving toward service co‐creation, whereby providers and users cooperate to recognize and exploit value co‐creation opportunities (Alves ; Uppström ). Another important related feature of platform government is the production and use of open data and open‐source software and, more generally, the adoption of open innovation practices (Bonina and Eaton ; Kim, Andersen, and Lee ; Mergel and Desouza ). In the public sector, governments engage in open innovation when they leverage the resources and knowledge contributed by a variety of constituents, such as government departments and agencies, citizens, and private sector organizations, in order to solve public problems. Open innovation practices can be instrumental both in increasing the value and innovativeness of existing public services, and in co‐creating entirely new services with users (Bekkers and Tummers ; Liu ; Mergel and Desouza ; Mu and Wang ). Yet, the use of crowdsourcing, as a tool of platform government to elicit solutions from the crowd, can imply different degrees of collaboration and co‐creation between seekers and solvers, and different degrees of openness in the innovation process. Examining the extent to which governments effectively use crowdsourcing to support service co‐creation and open innovation, particularly in the context of the urgent and systematic problems posed by the COVID‐19 pandemic, can help us to better understand governments' ability to use this instrument to its full potential, and highlight areas in which its use could be improved.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>6332</offset><text>In this article, therefore, we investigate the following question: To what extent has crowdsourcing been used by governments to support co‐creation and open innovation processes to tackle the issues associated with the COVID‐19 pandemic? </text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>6575</offset><text>To respond to this question, we built an original dataset of crowdsourcing challenges (calls to participate in competitions, propose ideas, or perform specific tasks) related to COVID‐19, based on a systematic search on the major crowdsourcing platforms for those challenges that had been launched and funded by organizations of a public nature in two distinct periods, in 2020 and 2021.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>6965</offset><text>The paper is structured as follows. In the next section, building on the open innovation literature, we propose a framework for analyzing crowdsourcing as a tool to promote open innovation and service co‐creation, by distinguishing what we call “open co‐creation” from other types of crowdsourcing, according to a typology spanning two dimensions: the degree of the openness of the challenge, and the level of collaboration with the crowd. We then describe our data and methodology and, in the following section, we present our analysis. Finally, in the last section, we conclude with some implications for policy.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>7588</offset><text>Crowdsourcing as an Instrument of Platform Government: A Framework for Analysis</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>7668</offset><text>The theoretical literature and the discussion of empirical cases of platform government highlight three fundamental features of this phenomenon, which, at least in theory, are fully consistent with the use of crowdsourcing. First, the extensive use of platforms, that is, new digital technologies, in all the various stages of design and implementation of public services (Kim, Andersen, and Lee ). Second, the presence of some degree of co‐creation with the various types of users that the service is intended to benefit (such as the citizens directly interested in the service; Hartley, Sørensen, and Torfing ) and/or other stakeholders interested in contributing to its existence (such as the providers of technology or expertise needed to deliver the service; Hartley, Sørensen, and Torfing ; Kim, Andersen, and Lee ; Linders ). This co‐creation is between equals: the public administration leads the process, but not in a hierarchical relationship with the relevant stakeholders, such that the former disposes and the latter benefits or responds. Third, services develop as a result of the availability of information, data, or software that are, to some extent, open. In addition, many of these services produce open data (Bonina and Eaton ).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>8929</offset><text>The first feature—the use of platforms—is certainly present in all types of crowdsourcing. This is not necessarily the case, however, for the other two features. Services that are defined or implemented through challenges launched on crowdsourcing platforms may not be fully co‐created, and they may not involve the use and/or release of open data. As noted by Agrawal , moving some services online does not, in itself, make them innovative. Similarly, the use of crowdsourcing may not automatically imply that the public administration is adopting open government practices, as the data used in the crowdsourcing challenge may not be publicly available. Furthermore, the extended and non‐hierarchical collaboration that should, theoretically, take place through crowdsourcing, may not materialize in practice (Mergel and Desouza ).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>9772</offset><text>A wide range of crowdsourcing challenges can be identified, with various degrees of co‐creation and openness (Eggers and Singh ). In figure 1, we depict some possibilities, considering the two characteristics defined above (the degree of co‐creation and the degree of openness), which may be present to varying degrees; for simplicity, we consider the two extremes of high or low. While the quadrant shown in figure 1 identifies four different types of crowdsourcing based on these extremes, in practice we expect wider range of possibilities to exist, in which the characteristics shown on the axes take on intermediate levels; in other words, we expect that specific crowdsourcing challenges found in practice will be more or less close to each type, rather than being neatly attributable to one of the four categories.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">PUAR-82-756-g001.jpg</infon><infon key="id">puar13489-fig-0001</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>10601</offset><text>Types of Crowdsourcing Challenges</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>10635</offset><text>In figure 1, we identify four types of crowdsourcing challenges. If the degree of the crowd's autonomy in defining the service is low, the service is not co‐created (Fu, Wang, and Zhao ; Lember, Brandsen, and Tõnurist ), but is essentially defined by the public administration, which chooses its features. For example, the public administration may require that the solutions offered by the crowd must fall within a certain category of eligible solutions, which has been specified in advance with a high level of detail. The public administration may also want to specify who is entitled to participate in the challenge, including some categories of individuals while excluding others. If the degree of openness of the challenge is low, this type of crowdsourcing is very similar to the traditional sourcing (“e‐sourcing” or “e‐procurement,” in this case). Instead, a challenge could combine a low degree of co‐creation and a high degree of openness. This is the case of challenges aiming to release open data or open‐source software, responding to the public administration's detailed specifications (“release of public data”).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>11790</offset><text>When the degree of co‐creation is high, the crowdsourcing participants engage in a horizontal collaboration with the public administration to co‐create the service (Alves ; Lember, Brandsen, and Tõnurist ). Here, the participants do not simply provide information and suggestions within a well‐defined framework of services specified by the public administration, they also propose ideas and content concerning the type of services that should be offered and define their characteristics. Depending on the level of openness, various types of crowdsourcing challenges with a high degree of co‐creation can be identified. If the challenge involves neither the exchange of open data or software, nor the dissemination of information beyond the participants, this could be a situation where the public administration invites an unspecified crowd to provide ideas about services it could–should offer and their characteristics (“elicitation of ideas”). Finally, when the crowd is also supposed to use and deliver open data and open‐source software, we have “open co‐creation.”</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>12887</offset><text>Co‐creation and the presence of open data might be particularly important when providing rapid solutions to novel problems, as in the case of the recent COVID‐19 pandemic. These two features are present in the examples discussed by Kim, Andersen, and Lee . Using the interpretative scheme in figure 1 and a dataset of public or public–private challenges collected from the most widely used crowdsourcing platforms, we discuss the extent to which governments have used crowdsourcing to support co‐creation and open innovation processes during the COVID‐19 pandemic.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>13464</offset><text>Data Collection and Analysis</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>13493</offset><text>We extracted data from 20 different internet platforms on which crowdsourcing challenges were posted (i.e., Battle of concepts, Challenge.com, Desafios, Ennomotive, Foldit Lab, GitHub, Hackster.io, HeroX, Inocrowd, IdeaScale Crowd, InnoCentive, Innoget, JOGL, Kaggle, MyGov, OpenIdeo, Starthubs, Synsapien, Crowdcity testing methods sourcing platform, #DATA4COVID19 Living Repository), identified through a keyword search online. Some of these platforms were created for the specific purpose of hosting COVID‐related challenges, and some were closed down some time after the outbreak of the pandemic. 1  </text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>14100</offset><text>The first data extraction took place between April and September 2020, thus covering the first few months after the pandemic outbreak. The second extraction took place between October and November 2021. Restricting our focus to challenges mentioning COVID‐19, we identified 158 challenges, of which 83 were either fully public—issued and funded by a public administration—(n = 41), or led by a public–private partnership (n = 42). For each challenge, we collected detailed information about the funders, the characteristics of the challenge (duration, reward, budget, geographical target), the details of the expected solution and its dissemination (intellectual property rights—IPR, licensing, data‐sharing), and the characteristics of the eligible solvers (nature, location).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>14894</offset><text>The public administrations issuing these challenges included ministries and governments, defense forces, and health administrations. Almost all public administrations were at the national level (i.e., national governments or national research centers). On average, each challenge funded by public–private partnerships included seven different organizations, including governments, research centers, hospitals, leading multinational enterprises (e.g., Amazon or Microsoft), and non‐governmental organizations (NGOs). Some local municipalities also featured among the public administrations involved in public–private partnerships.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>15531</offset><text>The challenges focused on a number of problems that arose during the pandemic. For example, many challenges relied on the crowd to create new masks or treatments for COVID‐19 infections; others tried to develop systems for the home care of sick patients, for sharing real‐time information on the spread of contagion and methods of prevention; others were intended to help citizens fact‐check online discussions to counter disinformation. Given the specialized nature of the tasks involved, most were open to an expert crowd. Only 35 percent of the challenges involved a monetary prize. When a monetary prize was offered, the budget allocated by the seekers was rather high (48 percent of the challenges had a budget of more than one million USD) even though it was generally divided among several winners. Some of these challenges had a specific geographical target, while others sought solutions that could potentially be applied anywhere. Table 1 shows some key features of the challenges.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">puar13489-tbl-0001.xml</infon><infon key="id">puar13489-tbl-0001</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_caption</infon><offset>16530</offset><text>General Features of the Crowdsourcing Challenges</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">puar13489-tbl-0001.xml</infon><infon key="id">puar13489-tbl-0001</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table</infon><infon key="xml">&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;table frame=&quot;hsides&quot; rules=&quot;groups&quot;&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;thead valign=&quot;bottom&quot;&gt;&lt;tr style=&quot;border-bottom:solid 1px #000000&quot;&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;bottom&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;bottom&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Challenges (%)&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Type of public funder&lt;xref rid=&quot;puar13489-note-0001&quot; ref-type=&quot;table-fn&quot;&gt;
&lt;sup&gt;a&lt;/sup&gt;
&lt;/xref&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;padding-left:10%&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;National governments&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;52.1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;padding-left:10%&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Supra‐national governments&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;6.3&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;padding-left:10%&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Local governments&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;4.2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;padding-left:10%&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Research organizations&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;22.9&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;padding-left:10%&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Research and government&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;12.5&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;padding-left:10%&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Health organizations&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;2.1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Reward for winners&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;padding-left:10%&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Winners receive monetary funds&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;34.9&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;padding-left:10%&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Winners receive other rewards&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;25.3&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;padding-left:10%&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;No reward&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;39.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Total budget of the challenge&lt;xref rid=&quot;puar13489-note-0001&quot; ref-type=&quot;table-fn&quot;&gt;
&lt;sup&gt;a&lt;/sup&gt;
&lt;/xref&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;padding-left:10%&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Below USD100,000&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;24.1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;padding-left:10%&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;From USD100,000 to USD1,000,000&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;27.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;padding-left:10%&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Above USD1,000,000&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;48.3&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Geographical target&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;padding-left:10%&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Worldwide&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;36.1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;padding-left:10%&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Restricted to one or more countries&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;63.9&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
</infon><offset>16579</offset><text>	Challenges (%)	 	Type of public fundera	 	National governments	52.1	 	Supra‐national governments	6.3	 	Local governments	4.2	 	Research organizations	22.9	 	Research and government	12.5	 	Health organizations	2.1	 	Reward for winners	 	Winners receive monetary funds	34.9	 	Winners receive other rewards	25.3	 	No reward	39.8	 	Total budget of the challengea	 	Below USD100,000	24.1	 	From USD100,000 to USD1,000,000	27.6	 	Above USD1,000,000	48.3	 	Geographical target	 	Worldwide	36.1	 	Restricted to one or more countries	63.9	 	</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">puar13489-tbl-0001.xml</infon><infon key="id">puar13489-tbl-0001</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_footnote</infon><offset>17115</offset><text>Refers only to the challenges that have a monetary prize.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>17173</offset><text>To operationalize the concept of co‐creation, we looked at the description of the challenge. By definition, all the challenges we considered involved collaboration with the public. However, in line with our previous characterization, we considered those challenges in which the public administration specified in advance, with a high level of detail, the type of service it expected to receive from the crowd, as having a relatively low level of co‐creation between the seeker and the solvers. In fact, in these cases, the crowd's task was relatively limited and very clearly defined by the public administration. Moreover, very often, these challenges did not require the mobilization of an indistinct crowd, but of very specific categories of solvers. As a result, these challenges were very similar to external service sourcing, which is not a particularly new or necessarily typical mode of platform government. Conversely, we considered those challenges where the public administration defined a problem area very broadly and asked for ideas from the crowd, without specifying in advance the type of service it expected to receive, as having a high degree of co‐creation. Here, the contribution of the crowd was indeed substantial, as the crowd was both contributing to identifying the problem, and to providing its solution.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>18510</offset><text>In order to operationalize the concept of openness, we looked at two fundamental aspects: (1) how the IPR and/or licensing was managed; (2) how the dissemination of solutions was governed. We deemed that challenges requiring participants to issue open‐source licenses and disclose all information about their proposal (data used, codes) had a high level of openness. Conversely, we considered challenges where the participants did not have to share their solution and where they held the IPR with respect to the proposed solution, as having a relatively low level of openness.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>19089</offset><text>Table 2 shows how each of the attributes we considered in order to operationalize the degree of co‐creation and openness of the challenges was distributed among the 83 public and public–private challenges.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">puar13489-tbl-0002.xml</infon><infon key="id">puar13489-tbl-0002</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_caption</infon><offset>19300</offset><text>Attributes Used to Operationalize the Degree of Co‐Creation and Openness of the Crowdsourcing Challenges</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">puar13489-tbl-0002.xml</infon><infon key="id">puar13489-tbl-0002</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table</infon><infon key="xml">&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;table frame=&quot;hsides&quot; rules=&quot;groups&quot;&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;thead valign=&quot;bottom&quot;&gt;&lt;tr style=&quot;border-bottom:solid 1px #000000&quot;&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;bottom&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Attributes&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;bottom&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;bottom&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Challenges (%)&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;3&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Degree of co‐creation between seekers and solvers&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;5&quot; style=&quot;padding-left:10%&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Level of detail of the tasks and the timeframe in which they are to be carried out&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;High&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;21.7&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Medium‐high&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;30.1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Medium‐low&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;14.4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Low&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;18.1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;NA&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;15.7&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;2&quot; style=&quot;padding-left:10%&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Participants' location&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Worldwide&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;53.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Restricted to one or more countries&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;47.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;3&quot; style=&quot;padding-left:10%&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Participants' types&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;All types&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;44.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Only individuals and teams&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;42.2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Only organizations&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;13.3&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;3&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Degree of openness of the solution&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;3&quot; style=&quot;padding-left:10%&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;IPR&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Seekers handle IPR&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;8.4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Proponents have exclusive ownership of IPR&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;68.7&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Not determined in advance&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;22.9&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;4&quot; style=&quot;padding-left:10%&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Licensing&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Participants required to grant free license to proponent&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;2.7&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Participants required to issue open‐source license&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;9.5&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;License not required&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;52.7&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Not determined in advance&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;35.1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;3&quot; style=&quot;padding-left:10%&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Data‐sharing conditions&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Participants not required to share data&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;17.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Participants required to share data&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;58.1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Not determined in advance&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;24.3&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
</infon><offset>19407</offset><text>Attributes		Challenges (%)	 	Degree of co‐creation between seekers and solvers	 	Level of detail of the tasks and the timeframe in which they are to be carried out	High	21.7	 	Medium‐high	30.1	 	Medium‐low	14.4	 	Low	18.1	 	NA	15.7	 	Participants' location	Worldwide	53.0	 	Restricted to one or more countries	47.0	 	Participants' types	All types	44.6	 	Only individuals and teams	42.2	 	Only organizations	13.3	 	Degree of openness of the solution	 	IPR	Seekers handle IPR	8.4	 	Proponents have exclusive ownership of IPR	68.7	 	Not determined in advance	22.9	 	Licensing	Participants required to grant free license to proponent	2.7	 	Participants required to issue open‐source license	9.5	 	License not required	52.7	 	Not determined in advance	35.1	 	Data‐sharing conditions	Participants not required to share data	17.6	 	Participants required to share data	58.1	 	Not determined in advance	24.3	 	</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>20319</offset><text>We then used a qualitative content analysis of the challenges to analyze how the attributes listed in table 2 were combined within individual challenges. In this way, we identified challenges that are representative examples of the four ideal types of crowdsourcing identified in figure 1. We describe them in what follows through some examples.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>20667</offset><text>Types of Crowdsourcing Challenges</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>20701</offset><text>In this section, we describe some of the challenges most representative of the four different types of crowdsourcing challenges that public administrations can use in situations requiring a response to citizens' new and urgent needs. The COVID‐19 pandemic, to which our analysis refers, is a good example of such a situation, although similar needs could also emerge in other circumstances.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>21094</offset><text> E‐Procurement </text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>21112</offset><text>This is the case where the crowd is called upon to respond to a precise, detailed need of the public administration, with a number of participant constraints, and without the requirement to use open practices. It could be assumed that this type of challenge aims to achieve goals not necessarily related to gathering inputs from a wide variety of constituents (i.e., the crowd), but rather to facilitate innovation in the public sector (like ordinary procurement, although in a somewhat modified form; Demircioglu and Vivona ; Lenderink, Halman, and Voordijk ) or support economic recovery (Pircher ). While it is not always possible to clearly attribute challenges to a specific type, we found 11 challenges, which could be considered very close to this type, based on their degree of co‐creation and openness (using the attributes listed in table 2). An example is a challenge launched by the National Research Council (NRC) Canada at the end of May 2020. The challenge, posted on the HeroX platform and relaunched on many Canadian government sites, was “seeking a solution for reagents required for nucleic acid sample preparation and rapid and efficient SARS‐CoV‐2 Ribonucleic Acid (RNA) extraction in order to perform downstream molecular diagnostics of COVID‐19 with capability to integrate within existing and/or potential microfluidic platforms for sample‐to‐answer solutions that can be deployed on the frontline for rapid testing.” 2  The NRC specified 17 mandatory features that an acceptable solution would have to display. The challenge described in great detail the time frame in which the solution was to be delivered, including a series of intermediate milestones that the solver had to respect, as well as a set of conditions that the solver must meet. Only for‐profit small businesses (with up to 499 employees) located in Canada were eligible to participate. Such companies had to have an R&amp;D department located in Canada, 50 percent of the employees' salaries had to be paid to Canadian residents, and at least 50 percent of the senior executives had to be Canadian residents. The challenge participants were not required to disseminate the proposed solution to third parties, but only to communicate it to the seeker. The winners received a grant from the NRC to produce the solution. They held all IPR attached to the solution.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>23484</offset><text>This challenge does not seem particularly different from a standard procurement scenario, except for the fact that the medium through which the request for services is disseminated is a crowdsourcing platform. While this allows for a much wider range of potential contributors, the presence of a set of constraints imposed by the NRC also on this aspect makes this example closer to e‐procurement than to more open forms of collaboration.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>23925</offset><text> Release of Open Data </text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>23948</offset><text>The second case, more consistent with open practices than the previous one, is where the seeker specifies many aspects of the expected solution in advance, but allows for open dissemination of information about the solutions submitted. Based on an analysis of the attributes of the challenges (as listed in table 2), we found that seven challenges could be considered close to this type. An example is a challenge launched in May 2020 by the European Commission. The challenge required the participants to provide solutions to a number of COVID‐19‐related problems, such as the design of portable devices for COVID‐19 at the clinical point of care, or the production of digital tools for real‐time surveillance of COVID‐19 patients. Solutions had to be close to market and have already received the Conformité européenne (CE) marking to “proceed to large scale testing, piloting and deployment operations in critical healthcare areas” or should have been “innovative solutions that have already been validated in lab environments (TRL 6‐7 or higher) with the aim to help accelerate developments and achieve conformity assessment (CE marking).” 3  In a series of calls published on the European Commission's website and relaunched throughout various networks, challenge requirements were specified in great detail. Participants could only be organizations, and in particular, consortia among innovative firms (including small and medium‐sized enterprises — SMEs) and/or other organizations. Although constraining the types of participants, the challenge met a number of open innovation criteria. Participants were required to issue open‐source licenses, where applicable. The challenge contained rapid data‐sharing clauses, such that all solutions had to be disseminated to everyone. Data had to be accessible and re‐usable by anyone who might want to use the data or the proposed solutions and develop them in some way (even those not allowed to participate in the challenge).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>25958</offset><text>It is precisely the presence of all these clauses that differentiates this type of challenge from e‐procurement. Besides funding some consortia with grants to produce a public service, the European Commission was also funding the production of open‐source solutions and freely available data with this challenge. In this sense, the challenge is compatible with an open government logic.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>26349</offset><text> Elicitation of Ideas </text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>26372</offset><text>The third case refers to challenges that aim to elicit contributions from the crowd, leaving the crowd a large degree of freedom. All possible types of participants are allowed. However, participants are not required to disseminate their solution to third parties and they do not adhere to open practices. We found that a small subset of challenges (four) could be considered very close to this type, based on their attributes as listed in table 2. An example is a challenge launched by the Korean government and the Seoul Institute of Technology, asking solvers to come up with new ideas for masks and other personal protective equipment to prevent the transmission of respiratory viruses. The challenge was published on the InnoCentive platform in June 2020. To respond to the challenge, all solvers had to do was to send a written idea to the seekers. The challenge was aimed at eliciting ideas from the crowd, with no particular constraints on the characteristics of the participants or the type of solution expected. It did not ask participants to disseminate the solution found or to make the data available. This can be considered a typical example of a challenge aimed at eliciting ideas that will eventually be transformed into services for citizens.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>27633</offset><text> Open Co‐Creation </text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>27654</offset><text>The fourth and final example is that of open co‐creation, with a high degree of collaboration between the seeker and the solvers, and open dissemination of information. We found seven challenges that fitted well with this model of open co‐creation, again based on their attributes as listed in table 2. The OpenCovid19 Initiative, a challenge posted on the JOGL platform, is an example of this type of crowdsourcing. The challenge was aimed at developing “open‐source and low‐cost tools and methodologies that are safe and easy to use to fight the COVID‐19 pandemic. All projects are open source and are ready to welcome volunteering contributors from all around the world.” 4  The challenge was proposed as an act of horizontal governance, in which the crowd (of any kind) was called upon to contribute not only to the solution, but also to the identification of the problem. Moreover, the challenge, posted on the HeroX platform and launched by a network of public organizations (including the Agence Française de Développement, NESTA, and Open‐Source Pharma), did not foresee any restriction on the type of participants, operating on the belief that different people could provide their different perspectives on identifying the most pressing problems and proposing how to solve them. This challenge is an example of open co‐creation.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>29013</offset><text> Key Drivers of the Choice to Use Different Types of Challenges </text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>29078</offset><text>Under the same label of crowdsourcing, we found four different types of uses of the crowd on the part of public administrations or public–private partnerships. These uses can be more or less in line with the idea of collaboration between equals and open innovation. We might then ask which factors drive the government's choice to use each type of challenge. To address this question, we further analyzed the content of the challenges, comparing those that were more representative of each of the four types. This qualitative analysis suggests that there are two main drivers that differ across the four types.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>29691</offset><text>The first driver is the object of the challenge. Many of the challenges related to goods or services close to being commercialized on the market, and/or that concerned goods requiring standard approval procedures (e.g., medical devices), tended to be positioned in the “low” end of the co‐creation spectrum. That is, they took the form of public procurement (or pre‐commercial procurement) 5  or, in some cases, procurement with open data production. For example, among the challenges we classified as e‐procurement we included a challenge issued by the Canadian National Research Council, which sought a “low cost system (unit cost &lt;$25) that can continuously measure temperature, peripheral capillary oxygen saturation (SpO2), blood pressure (BP), pulse and respiration rates, and transmit this information wirelessly to a base station for COVID‐19 patient monitoring in locales including ERs, general wards, communities and homes.” 6  Services that were further away from commercialization and/or did not necessarily require standard approval procedures by health authorities, took various other forms and were more often positioned in the “high” end of the co‐creation spectrum. For example, among the challenges we classified as open co‐creation, we included a challenge issued by a consortium of municipalities and other organizations in Colombia and various other countries, which consisted of a “hackathon to provide solutions to the challenge of mobilizing critical workers at the same time as reducing contagion among citizens due to COVID‐19 pandemic.” 7  Therefore, we suggest that a first important driver in the government's decision to use a specific type of challenge might be the nature of the product or service that is the object of the challenge.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>31488</offset><text>The second driver is the familiarity with open government practices of the public administration issuing the challenge. We found that some governments (e.g., Canada or the European Union) tended to issue challenges that were positioned at the “low” end of the co‐creation and openness dimensions. First, they mostly used the crowd selectively. Second, the object of collaboration was usually a well‐structured project, pre‐defined in detail by the public authority; for example, “a solution that will provide alternative filtration materials at large scale volumes that are suitable for use in the manufacture of N95 respirators and surgical masks for healthcare workers” 8  and “solutions related to robotic technologies, that are in later stages of development and can be applied quickly to the healthcare sector to support healthcare professionals in fighting COVID‐19.” 9  Third, the challenge was usually not open to an indistinct crowd, but restricted to certain categories of agents (companies or individuals), located in specific countries, contrary to the idea that global wicked problems require global mobilization (Moon ). Fourth, in the majority of these crowdsourcing challenges, participants retained their IPR and were not obliged to share data, which might lead to fragmented responses to particular aspects of the COVID‐19 problem rather than a mutualization of efforts to tackle the pandemic as a whole. Instead, in the United States, many challenges were open to the collaboration of an indistinct crowd, and more consistent with open innovation practices. In particular, considering the challenges issued by US public administrations (such as, among others, The White House Office of Science and Technology Policy, DARPA, National Science Foundation, National Institute of Health, National Institute of Standards and Technology), we noticed that none of them imposed restrictions on the type or geographical location of participants, and they all required the participants to make their data publicly available, with few restrictions on IP use. Many of them provided very loose descriptions of the expected outcomes, such as “design a binder against COVID‐19” 10  or “design an anti‐inflammatory protein for COVID‐19.” 11  We suggest that this has to do with the fact that, in countries like the United States, open government practices are more established in public administrations than they are in other countries.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>33964</offset><text>Insights for Public Administrations</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>34000</offset><text>The evidence provided by some of the main crowdsourcing platforms shows that public administrations worldwide have resorted to crowdsourcing in search of solutions to problems triggered by the crisis. Such challenges have been launched by either public administrations or a mix of public administrations and private organizations and have been managed by public actors located in many different countries (from Brazil to the United States, the Netherlands, or South Korea), operating mainly at the national level.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>34514</offset><text>Our analysis identifies and discusses four main types of crowdsourcing challenges. Some of these quite closely resemble more “traditional” policy instruments in which crowdsourcing is used mainly as a platform to potentially reach a wider public, instead of embodying a more innovative approach to knowledge creation and sharing. The latter would be the case if, for example, crowdsourcing was used to develop open and collaborative solutions to complex problems; this, however, is a relatively less prevalent approach to crowdsourcing. We have found that “open co‐creation” is more likely to be used when the object of the challenges are goods and services that are far from commercialization, not requiring standard approval procedures; it is also more likely to be used when the government issuing the challenge is more experienced with “open government” practices.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>35397</offset><text>Our study presents certain limitations that open avenues for future research. While our focus was on public administrations, it would be worthwhile to examine challenges from the perspective of the participants: their type and the reasons incentivizing them to participate (especially when no monetary reward is proposed). Another promising area of investigation relates to intellectual property protection and openness. What kind of public or social issues are more prone to openness, and what kinds of participants are ready to share their intellectual property and for which kind of return (tangible or intangible)? Qualitative studies based on in‐depth interviews could be deployed to dig deeper into the mechanisms that link seekers and solvers through crowdsourcing challenges. Moreover, while our investigation is limited to COVID‐19, we believe that there is a need for a better understanding of the use of crowdsourcing by public administrations, not only in response to a pandemic, but also to other economic or societal challenges. An investigation focusing on the geographical location of seekers and/or solvers and the type of governments–administrations in place would also lead to better understanding of some of the locational specificities influencing the use of crowdsourcing by public administrations. Finally, we expect that public administrations, over time, would learn from their and others' experience of using crowdsourcing to address urgent and complex challenges, and modify their use of this instrument accordingly. Our dataset is not large enough, and the period in which data were collected is not long enough, to allow us to derive insight about how public administrations change their approach to crowdsourcing as they gain more experience with the instrument and as the nature of the problem they face evolves. It would be valuable if further research could investigate how the use of crowdsourcing on the part of public administrations changes over time, why, and in which direction.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>37421</offset><text>In conclusion, while the use of crowdsourcing by public organizations is certainly very positive and valuable, the experience gained during the pandemic period should pave the way to a much deeper and more comprehensive use of crowds to tackle issues of public interest.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title</infon><offset>37692</offset><text>Notes</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">footnote</infon><offset>37698</offset><text>This applies, for instance, to hackathon pages that have been closed after the end of the hackathon.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">footnote</infon><offset>37799</offset><text>The quote is taken from the website http://www.ic.gc.ca/eic/site/101.nsf/eng/00110.html [accessed November 24, 2021].</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">footnote</infon><offset>37917</offset><text>The quotes are taken from the website https://digital‐strategy.ec.europa.eu/en/news/coronavirus‐response‐eu56‐million‐solutions‐using‐medical‐technologies‐digital‐tools‐and‐artificial [accessed November 24, 2021].</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">footnote</infon><offset>38155</offset><text>The quote is taken from the website https://app.jogl.io/program/opencovid19 [accessed November 24, 2021].</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">footnote</infon><offset>38261</offset><text>The term “pre‐commercial procurement” was used by one of the promoters of a crowdsourcing challenge that we classified as e‐procurement, whom we interviewed in October 2021.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">footnote</infon><offset>38443</offset><text>The quote is taken from the website http://www.ic.gc.ca/eic/site/101.nsf/eng/00078.html [accessed February 11, 2022].</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">footnote</infon><offset>38561</offset><text>The quote is taken from the website https://github.com/datasketch/movid19 [accessed February 11, 2022].</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">footnote</infon><offset>38665</offset><text>The quote is taken from the website https://dih‐hero.eu/supporting‐professionals‐in‐the‐fight‐against‐covid‐19/ [accessed February 11, 2022].</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">footnote</infon><offset>38823</offset><text>The quote is taken from the website http://www.ic.gc.ca/eic/site/101.nsf/eng/00102.html [accessed February 11, 2022].</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">footnote</infon><offset>38941</offset><text>The quote is taken from the website https://fold.it/portal/node/2010049 [accessed February 11, 2022].</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">footnote</infon><offset>39043</offset><text>The quote is taken from the website https://fold.it/portal/node/2010090 [accessed February 11, 2022].</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">title</infon><offset>39145</offset><text>References</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">702</infon><infon key="issue">5</infon><infon key="lpage">3</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Public Administration Review</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">73</infon><infon key="year">2013</infon><offset>39156</offset><text>Commentary: 311 Services: A Real World Perspective</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">172</infon><infon key="lpage">90</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Handbook of Research on Global Challenges for Improving Public Services and Government Operations</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2021</infon><offset>39207</offset></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">671</infon><infon key="issue">7–8</infon><infon key="lpage">82</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">The Service Industries Journal</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">33</infon><infon key="year">2013</infon><offset>39208</offset><text>Co‐Creation and Innovation in Public Services</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">209</infon><infon key="issue">2</infon><infon key="lpage">13</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">International Reviews of Administrative Sciences</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">84</infon><infon key="year">2018</infon><offset>39256</offset><text>Innovation in the Public Sector: Towards an Open and Collaborative Approach</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1131</infon><infon key="issue">6</infon><infon key="lpage">46</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Public Administration Review</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">81</infon><infon key="year">2021</infon><offset>39332</offset><text>The Effect of Health and Economic Costs on Governments' Policy Responses to COVID‐19 Crisis under Incomplete Information</text></passage><passage><infon key="elocation-id">101479</infon><infon key="issue">3</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Government Information Quarterly</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">37</infon><infon key="year">2020</infon><offset>39455</offset><text>Cultivating Open Government Data Platform Ecosystems through Governance: Lessons from Buenos Aires, Mexico City and Montevideo</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Crowdsourcing in the Public Sector</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>39582</offset></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">23</infon><infon key="issue">1</infon><infon key="lpage">34</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Public Administration Review</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">73</infon><infon key="year">2013</infon><offset>39583</offset><text>Designing Public Participation Processes</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1197</infon><infon key="issue">8</infon><infon key="lpage">218</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Journal of European Public Policy</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">28</infon><infon key="year">2021</infon><offset>39624</offset><text>Decentralization, Policy Capacities, and Varieties of First Health Responses to the COVID‐19 Outbreak: Evidence from Three Regions in Italy</text></passage><passage><infon key="elocation-id">101409</infon><infon key="issue">4</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Government Information Quarterly</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">36</infon><infon key="year">2019</infon><offset>39766</offset><text>Government as a Platform, Orchestration, and Public Value Creation: The Italian Case</text></passage><passage><infon key="elocation-id">120799</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Technological Forecasting and Social Change</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">169</infon><infon key="year">2021</infon><offset>39851</offset><text>Crisis‐Driven Innovation and Fundamental Human Needs: A Typological Framework of Rapid‐Response COVID‐19 Innovations</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">379</infon><infon key="issue">3</infon><infon key="lpage">96</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Policy and Society</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">40</infon><infon key="year">2021</infon><offset>39974</offset><text>Positioning Public Procurement as a Procedural Tool for Innovation: An Empirical Study</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">The Platform Society: Public Values in a Connective World</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2018</infon><offset>40061</offset></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">363</infon><infon key="issue">3</infon><infon key="lpage">83</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Canadian Public Administration</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">58</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>40062</offset><text>Crowdsourcing as a New Instrument in the Government's Arsenal: Explorations and Considerations</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">The Public Innovator's Playbook: Nurturing Bold Ideas in Government</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2009</infon><offset>40157</offset></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">348</infon><infon key="issue">2</infon><infon key="lpage">88</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Journal of Service Management</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">28</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>40158</offset><text>The Influence of Platform Service Innovation on Value Co‐Creation Activities and the Network Effect</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">629</infon><infon key="issue">4</infon><infon key="lpage">33</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Public Administration Review</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">80</infon><infon key="year">2020</infon><offset>40260</offset><text>Connecting With New Partners in COVID‐19 Response</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">7</infon><infon key="issue">1</infon><infon key="lpage">11</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Public Administration Review</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">82</infon><infon key="year">2021</infon><offset>40312</offset><text>Governance: Struggle and Strife—Or Synergy and Success—In the Trans‐COVID Era</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">405</infon><infon key="issue">3</infon><infon key="lpage">13</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Public Administration Review</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">71</infon><infon key="year">2011</infon><offset>40396</offset><text>Assembling E‐Government Research Designs: A Transdisciplinary View and Interactive Approach</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">821</infon><infon key="issue">6</infon><infon key="lpage">30</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Public Administration Review</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">73</infon><infon key="year">2013</infon><offset>40490</offset><text>Collaborative Innovation: A Viable Alternative to Market Competition and Organizational Entrepreneurship</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2006</infon><offset>40595</offset><text>The Rise of Crowdsourcing. Wired Magazine, Issue 14.06, 1–5</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">665</infon><infon key="issue">4</infon><infon key="lpage">70</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Public Administration Review</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">80</infon><infon key="year">2020</infon><offset>40657</offset><text>Fighting COVID‐19 through Government Initiatives and Collaborative Governance: The Taiwan Experience</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">362</infon><infon key="lpage">68</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1111/puar.13422</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Public Administration Review</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">82</infon><infon key="year">2021</infon><offset>40760</offset><text>Platform Government in the Era of Smart Technology</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1665</infon><infon key="issue">11</infon><infon key="lpage">86</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Public Management Review</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">21</infon><infon key="year">2019</infon><offset>40811</offset><text>The Potential Impacts of Digital Technologies on co‐Production and co‐Creation</text></passage><passage><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1080/13511610.2019.1700101</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Innovation: The European Journal of Social Science Research</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2019</infon><offset>40894</offset><text>Innovation and Public Procurement: From Fragmentation to Synthesis on Concepts, Rationales and Approaches</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">446</infon><infon key="issue">4</infon><infon key="lpage">54</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Government Information Quarterly</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">29</infon><infon key="year">2012</infon><offset>41000</offset><text>From E‐Government to we‐Government: Defining a Typology for Citizen Coproduction in the Age of Social Media</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">656</infon><infon key="issue">5</infon><infon key="lpage">67</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Public Administration Review</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">77</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>41112</offset><text>Crowdsourcing Government: Lessons from Multiple Disciplines</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">315</infon><infon key="issue">2</infon><infon key="lpage">31</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Policy and Internet</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">13</infon><infon key="year">2021</infon><offset>41172</offset><text>Crowdsourcing: Citizens as Co‐Producers of Public Services</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">309</infon><infon key="issue">3</infon><infon key="lpage">25</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">35039723</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Policy and Society</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">39</infon><infon key="year">2020</infon><offset>41233</offset><text>Policy Style, Consistency and the Effectiveness of the Policy Mix in China's Fight against COVID‐19</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">882</infon><infon key="issue">6</infon><infon key="lpage">90</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Public Administration Review</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">73</infon><infon key="year">2013</infon><offset>41335</offset><text>Implementing Open Innovation in the Public Sector: The Case of</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">651</infon><infon key="issue">4</infon><infon key="lpage">6</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Public Administration Review</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">80</infon><infon key="year">2020</infon><offset>41398</offset><text>Fighting COVID‐19 with Agility, Transparency, and Participation: Wicked Policy Problems and New Governance Challenges</text></passage><passage><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1080/14719037.2020.1838787</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Public Management Review</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2020</infon><offset>41518</offset><text>A Systematic Literature Review of Open Innovation in the Public Sector: Comparing Barriers and Governance Strategies of Digital and Non‐Digital Open Innovation</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">12</infon><infon key="issue">1</infon><infon key="lpage">20</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Government Information Quarterly</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">29</infon><infon key="year">2012</infon><offset>41680</offset><text>Suggesting Frameworks of Citizen‐Sourcing Via Government 2.0</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">13</infon><infon key="issue">1</infon><infon key="lpage">40</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Innovations: Technology, Governance, Globalization</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">6</infon><infon key="year">2011</infon><offset>41743</offset><text>Government as a Platform</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">509</infon><infon key="issue">4</infon><infon key="lpage">25</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Journal of European Integration</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">42</infon><infon key="year">2020</infon><offset>41768</offset><text>EU Public Procurement Policy: The Economic Crisis as Trigger for Enhanced Harmonisation</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">93</infon><infon key="issue">1</infon><infon key="lpage">107</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Journal of Innovation Economics &amp; Management</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">7</infon><infon key="year">2011</infon><offset>41856</offset><text>Towards a Characterization of Crowdsourcing Practices</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1278</infon><infon key="issue">8</infon><infon key="lpage">98</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Journal of European Public Policy</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">28</infon><infon key="year">2021</infon><offset>41910</offset><text>The EU's Reaction in the First Wave of the Covid‐19 Pandemic between Centralisation and Decentralisation, Formality and Informality</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">874</infon><infon key="issue">5</infon><infon key="lpage">9</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Public Administration Review</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">80</infon><infon key="year">2020</infon><offset>42044</offset><text>Nonprofit Service Continuity and Responses in the Pandemic: Disruptions, Ambiguity, Innovation, and Challenges</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">851</infon><infon key="issue">5</infon><infon key="lpage">5</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Public Administration Review</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">80</infon><infon key="year">2020</infon><offset>42155</offset><text>Coproduction during and after the COVID‐19 Pandemic: Will it Last?</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">The Promise of Public Value co‐Creation in Open Government: Designing IT Services for Open Government and Public Value co‐Creation</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2014</infon><offset>42224</offset></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">497</infon><infon key="issue">6–7</infon><infon key="lpage">504</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">American Review of Public Administration</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">50</infon><infon key="year">2020</infon><offset>42225</offset><text>Responding to the Coronavirus Pandemic: A Tale of Two Cities</text></passage></document></collection>
